(Theme Song playing)
CLARKSON: Hello!
Hello, good evening,
and welcome!
Thank you so much.
Now, this is a
mobile telephone.
It's fully functional,
and what I'm going to do...
-(Splashing)
...Is throw it
in that lavatory.
I know that's the first time
you've ever seen a programme
start that way,
but bear with me,
because if we now look...
Yeah, it's only been
in the water
for a few seconds,
but it's ruined forever.
If you wanted
to communicate with somebody,
you'd be better off
using a Brussels sprout.
Yeah, but, of course, because
if you expose your phone
to any form of moisture
or heat or dust or vibration,
it will break.
It's not just phones,
it's everything.
Printers, laptops,
wi-fi routers...
My coffee machine breaks
even when you
expose it to coffee.
Anything with a circuit board
is as reliable as
a Greek accountant.
It is! Except, weirdly,
except cars.
Now, we were
talking about this
in the office the other day,
and there was
a bit of an argument.
We were saying you can
drive a car across the Sahara,
the arctic,
you can run it through
hurricanes and dust storms,
and it'll be fine.
Mmm, but the producers
are saying that
because modern cars
are so complex
and so electronical,
they're bound to suffer
from reliability problems
like everything else.
Right. So, to see
who is correct,
the producers said to us,
"go out and each choose
your favourite modern GT car,
"and then report with them
to what's billed as,
"'the most hirsute and manly
proving ground of them all,'"
Austria.
No, James, Australia.
Same thing.
CLARKSON:  This is
the hirsute and manly
proving ground in question.
The vast,
almost completely uninhabited
northern territory,
better known as the outback.
Richard had chosen
to take on this brutal and
enormous wilderness
in a car that was
designed for the car park
at Old Trafford,
a Bentley Continental GT.
James had gone for a car
engineered for the
velvet smoothness of
the world's racetracks,
a Nissan GT-R.
And I was in
the ultimate Monaco-to-Munich
mile-muncher,
the BMW M6 Gran Coupe.
CLARKSON: Tell you what...
HAMMOND: What?
I think this is the first time
in all of  Top Gear's history
where all three of us
like all three of the cars.
I mean, normally
I'd get out and go,
"yours is rubbish,
"and you've made
the wrong decision
"and I'm the only one
who's done it properly."
Yeah, that's a
good point actually
'cause I do like your car,
and I do like your car,
Hammond, and I like
my car obviously.
-That's a GT-R.
You can't not like a GT-R.
-Yeah.
If you like driving
above all else
and to the exclusion
of all other considerations,
you have to have one of these.
If you have a Ferrari
or a Lamborghini
what you're saying is,
"I'm not that interested
in driving."
-It's showing off.
Speaking of which,
the Bentley Continental.
Now what happened there?
MAY:  We used to think
it was a bit dull and now
it's, sort of, good.
-But it was overnight!
-It was.
We all must have woken up
independently...
I hate the
Bentley Continental.
God, I love the
I don't understand that.
'Cause they haven't
changed the styling much.
No, not since... I mean,
it's been around a while now.
But then we just woke up
one morning and went,
"that looks really good!"
MAY: I'd actually
have a yellow one as well.
I think it looks tremendous!
But then, while we're on
the subject of styling...
Hmm-mmm-mmm!
Oh, how we mocked
when they said that
they were gonna do this.
Right, so you're gonna
do a four-door version
of a two-door version
of a four-door saloon car.
And then it came out,
and you just thought,
"that is so good-looking."
I love that back wheel.
That dished back wheel
in there looks sick!
-It's fantastic, isn't it?
-And then...
Almost a double bubble roof.
I know it's carbon fibre
which is a little bit...
MAY: You know,
we can gloss over that, yes.
CLARKSON:
But, God, it looks good.
As we continued our three-car
love-in, a challenge arrived.
Here we go.
"You will drive to a farm
which is four days from here."
Everything's four days
from everything in Australia.
"And when you arrive
you will use your cars
to round up 4,000 cows."
-Wha...
-Can you do that?
The farm is a big one.
Three million acres!
-No, it's not three million.
-You read that wrong.
(Chuckling)
Three... It's not...
Are you sure you...
Is it 300,000?
-Three million is it?
-That's a big farm!
Never mind that. Rounding up
4,000 cows using...
-These.
-(Gasps)
Oh God, James
what have you done?
-What's he done?
-What?
As we know, there is a strong
republican movement
in this country.
People who think
it's ridiculous to have
a head of state
living in London, on the
other side of the world.
He turns up here with that
on the number plate.
What?
CLARKSON:
Can you not see that?
It's obvious.
-No.
-Charles and Camilla.
You've done it on purpose,
haven't you James?
-Look, let me explain.
-Hammond: You
blithering idiot!
CLARKSON: You idiot!
HAMMOND: Oh no!
Mine says "big royalist."
CLARKSON: It does!
Big royalist!
HAMMOND: It totally does,
and you can see it.
Luckily, mine just
says "BMW 001"
'Cause I've covered
myself on this occasion.
No, you idiot.
"Bloody Mrs Windsor."
-Oh no! Bloody Mrs Windsor!
-Oh no!
We're in a lot of trouble.
How could he possibly know?
I rang them up and said,
"can you provide a car?
"Can you make sure
the number plate doesn't say
'convict' or anything on it,"
And they've done that!
We're gonna have
to drive through...
We'll be stoned
by republicans.
CLARKSON:  As we set off,
though, we had
a more immediate problem.
Could our complicated cars
really cope with this vast,
super-heated dust bowl?
Vauxhall once thought
they'd try and sell
the senator in Australia,
a big old saloon made
in Germany in the '80s.
So they shipped one out here,
and it lasted a couple of days
and then it split in half.
Split in half!
That's how brutal
the outback is.
This car has
electronic valve control,
electronic gearbox control,
an electronic differential,
everything is electronic.
It actually has
a sensor in the engine
that adjusts all the settings
so that no matter how
hot it is or how cold it is
you always get 575 horsepower.
And I'm expecting it
to work here, in this dust,
and this heat,
and with these vibrations,
and then go farming.
MAY: My Nissan
is an absolute nerdfest.
I'm gonna give you
a few examples.
It's built in a
hermetically-sealed factory
so that no dust can get into
the engine or the gearbox.
The tyres are filled
with nitrogen,
'cause it's more stable
than atmospheric air.
The engine is canted slightly
forwards under the bonnet,
so when it tenses up
under acceleration
it all forms a nice,
straight, efficient line.
I mean, it's been built by the
cream of Japanese automotive
engineers at Nissan.
That's a pretty
good guarantee.
But even they, watching this,
would think,
"are we sure?"
HAMMOND:  This has
30 ecus in it.
That's 30 laptops
buzzing away all over.
It's got two miles
of wiring in it,
a lot of which is super-fast,
super-sophisticated,
super delicate fibre optics.
And this dust is
going to get everywhere.
And delicate, modern,
sophisticated electronics
do not like dust.
CLARKSON:  As Hammond
was rabbiting on about dust,
I decided to have
a debate with James
about which of our cars
was the fastest.
You know, the Datsun
you're driving is
unbelievably fast, yes?
MAY:  Yes.
Off the line,
this will leave it for dead.
The M6 will cream you!
No, not off the line it won't.
You know that's nonsense.
CLARKSON:  To prove him wrong,
I decided to have a drag race
on one of the many
world war ii airfields
that litter this part
of northern Australia.
It is absolutely blistering,
this thing!
0 to 60, 2.8 seconds!
2.8!
Hammond, would you like to
come in to amuse us with your
stately home in a drag race?
Yes. All right, if I must.
He's probably got a demented
relation living in a tower
in there somewhere.
HAMMOND:  It didn't take long
to find an airfield.
And we lined up on the runway,
with me resigned to my fate.
I have a 4-litre,
twin turbo v8,
making 521 brake horsepower.
But I think
I may struggle here.
They've got launch control,
more power
and they're lighter.
It's come up here,
what I have to do to engage
the launch control.
So, "deactivate
dynamic stability control.
"Select sequential mode with
drive programme three."
That sharps up
the gear changes.
"With the engine running,
depress the brake
with the left foot."
Done that.
"Push the selector lever
forwards and hold.
"A flag symbol appears
in the instrument cluster."
It doesn't.
Start again. Into f...
-(Beeping)
-Oh...
It will be
a fairly simple process,
but it will be beyond
the mind of the average ape.
Maybe the air-conditioning
has to be off.
(Button Clicking)
Let's try that. Nope.
MAY:  Things were
much simpler in the Nissan.
Right. On, on, on.
Red, red, red.
Manual mode first,
left foot on the brake.
This is a tiresome formality.
I'm sorry to waste
your time, viewers.
Nothing in the world moves
off the line more quickly
than a Nissan GT-R.
That's just
one of those facts.
It's probably
in the bible somewhere.
Right, not a lot to do in
the Bentley before we do this.
Lower the ride height. Done.
Firm up the suspension.
Let's have that on "sport."
And that's it.
I'm ready to go.
HAMMOND:  And after
about half an hour,
so was Jeremy.
Okay, we're good to go.
We're good to go.
Three... Two... One.
(Engines Roaring)
CLARKSON: Oh, it's gone.
It's gone, it's gone,
it's gone.
Bmw, scrabbling about
for traction,
all over the shop.
Should prove the point.
HAMMOND: Wow!
(Laughing)
This launch control
doesn't work.
(Chuckling)
It does about
five feet and it goes,
"oh, I can't be bothered."
As, it seems, had James.
CLARKSON: Why did you stop?
I won.
What do you mean, you won?
The flags are down there!
No, you said, "which is
the quickest off the mark?"
-Mine was.
-No, you weren't.
-It was!
-It wasn't.
It went like a scalded rabbit!
I know, but I was off
the mark quicker.
-You weren't!
-Nothing is quicker off
the mark than this car.
-Do... Do you want
to check the camera?
-Yes.
Well, then, we'll go
check the camera.
We'll go and
CLARKSON:  We went
to check the camera.
You watch this, okay?
-Right, and go!
MAY: Go!
CLARKSON: God! We haven't got
very good reactions, have we?
HAMMOND: Oh my God!
We are useless.
CLARKSON: No, that can't...
MAY: Yes!
Thank you! Thank you!
HAMMOND: Yeah, you were first.
-CLARKSON: What?
-(May laughing)
CLARKSON:
Oh God, look, the BMW is...
Why am I last?
Right. We've established...
I think the Nissan
just wins it...
-(Clearing throat)
-...Over 16 meters,
followed by the Bentley,
BMW, a rather poor third.
HAMMOND: Yes.
CLARKSON:  I therefore
decided we should
have another drag race
in which James would
go all the way,
and I'd go old-school.
CLARKSON: I'm doing
manual gear changes,
manual start,
no traction control.
Me and the machine.
This is a serious test,
actually, of these cars,
drag racing them in this heat.
107 degrees Fahrenheit.
HAMMOND: Three... Two... One.
Come on, Bentley!
Come on! Come on!
I am hard on the heels
of the Nissan.
Oh, my God!
I'm overtaking it!
Come on, Beemer!
I've got the Datsun!
That Bentley is
unbelievably fast.
But I'm gonna get him.
(Laughing) Oh, this is
the closest I've ever seen!
Come on, Beemer! You can't
lose to that monster!
No way! No way!
(Hammond Laughing)
Yes!
What a machine you are, BMW!
CLARKSON:  Having established
that the most powerful car
is the fastest,
we got back on the road.
Cooling down now
in the evening,
it's down to
98 degrees Fahrenheit.
The producers said
we'd be staying that night
at the million stars motel
which boasted the finest fish
restaurant in the outback.
And we were looking
forward to that.
However, when they
told us we'd arrived...
-Hammond: Where is it?
-(Sighing)
-I know exactly what this is.
-I've got it.
What?
-"Million star motel."
-Yup.
-Oh.
-Best fish restaurant
in the outback.
-It's a joke.
-Stars.
MAY: Yes. It's a funny joke.
-Funny.
-Funny. Yeah, good.
So, we're tenting.
MAY:  We were given
some horrible camping stuff,
and an Australian kitchen.
And once that had been set up,
we had to catch our supper.
-May...
-Thanks.
-Welcome to  top gear.
-(Sighing)
Oh, fucking hell.
(Both Chuckling)
What're you struggling with?
-Every single...
-No! Watch it!
Can you look behind you
when you do that?
CLARKSON: Yes!
Why are you in your car?
I am in the car because the
crocodiles are in that pond.
CLARKSON: Oh, there're
no crocodiles here.
HAMMOND: Well, there are!
They can sit underwater.
These are machines
for killing and eating!
They can tackle
a water buffalo whole!
Are you not scared
of crocodiles?
Well, I'm not
when they're not there.
-Hammond: then there's
the snakes.
-(Clarkson groaning)
HAMMOND: There's the
death adders!
There is no country on earth
where the public perception
of the country
is further removed from
the reality than Australia.
-But it's just tourist...
-(Water splashing)
Hold on, what was that?
What did that?
MAY: Well, it's gone
under the water.
-Where's he gone?
-I don't know,
but he's gone down.
-Oh, look at that!
-It is!
Yes, it is.
CLARKSON: That is moving
towards us, isn't it?
HAMMOND: Yes!
Did you read last week
about the one that ate
a Bentley whole?
-Complete with the man in it.
-Yeah, but it spat
the Bentley out.
It carries a spare
set of teeth.
-Does it?
-Yes.
CLARKSON: Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Now, because we're in
Australia this week,
and because Australia is
enormous and full of
a million things to do,
we have no time
to do the news,
I'm afraid.
Nor do we have time
for the Stig to go
around the track,
but we have made time
to put a star in our
reasonably-priced car,
and that's because
my guest tonight
is the best British actor
ever to come out of Canada.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome, from America,
Kiefer Sutherland!
Oh, hi, how are you?
That's something else.
-Good to see you.
-How are you?
-Hi! Great!
-Look who's here!
-Thank you.
-Jack Bauer!
Thank you very much.
How are you?
-I'm very well.
-Good.
I think a lot of people
would be surprised to find
that you were actually
born in London, weren't you?
Yeah.
I was born in Paddington.
In fact, there was a
very funny moment,
I was doing a documentary
with a friend, and he was
following me with a camera,
and I said, "Oh, St Mary's
hospital is right down here.
That's where I was born,"
And as I was showing it
to him, a wrecking ball
came out of nowhere
and just knocked it down,
and apparently they were
moving it across the street,
so I got the last vision
of the hospital
that I was born in.
The place of your birth,
they'd knocked it down?
-Yeah.
-Yeah, I know,
they did that with mine,
while I was being born.
Um...
-Of course, your father,
he's Donald.
-Yes!
I want to get on to this.
It's slightly delicate, but...
Nobody likes to think
of their parents having sex.
-Mmm-hmm.
-This is not something
we can even visualise.
-But your father, of course,
was in  Don't Look Now.
-Yes.
-With Julie Christie.
Is that a struggle
for you to watch?
It was a real struggle
at about 13, 14, because
Julie Christie was stunning,
and you're 14 years old,
and you're watching it,
and you're trying to
block your father out.
And then, "no,
this isn't gonna work,
this isn't gonna work."
But yes, that moment
was kind of tricky.
Now, obviously,
you're best known for  24,
and I know a lot
of people here will
want me to talk about  24.
-Sure.
-Now, I think I'm
right in saying,
was it the first of the,
sort of, what we now take as
the binge-viewing box set?
-Yes.
-It sort of was.
There'd before...
And there'd never been,
like, you were
a big-name actor,
-who took up a TV role,
which now is the norm.
-Mmm-hmm. Right.
I mean, you've got
kevin spacey going in
house of cards and so on,
but back then,
you were either a TV actor
or you were a movie actor.
And so it was
a groundbreaking thing.
Well, for me it was
a no-brainer.
I noticed that
the film world was changing.
We used to have five studios
that made 50-some-odd
movies a year.
Went down to three studios
that were making
15 movies a year.
And all of a sudden,
the movies that I liked,
like  ordinary people,
or  terms of endearment,
their kind of
$20 million movie
wasn't getting made any more.
It was all superheroes,
and all of the great drama
was kind of shifting over
to television.
And with regards
to the binge-watching,
I ran into a gentleman
at an airport
and he said,
"you ruined my honeymoon."
And I said, "how?"
And he said, "well,
my wife..." I said,
"I don't even know your wife."
And he said,
"no, no, no,
not that, not that.
"We watched the first 12 hours
of  24 on the plane
from Los Angeles to Paris,
"and the first day
of our honeymoon,
"we spent the next
12 hours in the hotel,
watching the next 12 hours."
I went, "well..."
And I was flattered by that.
Yeah, ruining people's...
24 actually ruined
my children's lives,
because they were young
when it first started,
9:00 was their bedtime,
but they had to go
immediately at 9:00,
and even now, when they
hear the word "previously..."
They go to bed.
"Uh-oh, we go to bed."
That's quite a great tool.
But it was very
important in my life.
Very, very important.
Wow. Thank you very much.
CLARKSON: No, I'm sure
a lot of people here
would agree with me on that.
-Didn't you do rodeo riding?
-I did, yeah. Yeah.
Actually professionally,
or just...
I roped in the USTRC circuit,
and I was fortunate enough,
I think, I won
about three or four.
So why don't you do more
movies that call for you to
ride around on horses?
They don't make a lot of them.
I'm actually one of
the few actors I know
that's actually gotten
to do a western.
Earlier in my career,
I got to do films
like  young guns I
and  young guns ii,
and I wish they made more.
Can't Charlie Sheen
ride a horse? He must be
able to ride, no?
Charlie Sheen
didn't like horses,
and horses didn't like him,
and that was firmly
established when we were
shooting  young guns I,
and most of the scenes
involving Charlie on a horse,
he was on a ladder,
with a saddle,
and some poor teamster
holding the bit,
and he would hold the reins
and he would kind of
act his way out of that,
and when we went to
go do  Three Musketeers,
I remember saying to the
AD, Lee Cleary,
"what are you
shooting right now?"
And he said,
"oh, we've got Charlie
coming around the bend
on a horse."
I said, "you do, do you?
Oh, that's pretty great.
"I'd get your people
out of the road."
And he said, "no, no, no,
he's gonna stop right by
the camera over there."
I said, "I promise you,
he's not."
And they called "action,"
And you could hear the horse,
starts off in
a kind of a trot,
and then in seconds
you could hear
it's in a full gallop,
then off in the distance
you hear, "whoa! Fuck, whoa!
Whoa! Whoa! Fuck, whoa!"
And then he came
around the corner, and
he's holding on to the mane.
He's let go of the reins.
He's now holding on
for dear life, and he's
hitting the horse,
in the back,
behind the ear.
And I remember
Lee Cleary, he went,
"well, you weren't
fucking joking there,
were you?"
And he didn't move.
Didn't move a muscle
to help him, you know?
Um, now, we're gonna
move on to your cars,
'cause I've looked at
your car history,
which is pretty good.
-Thanks!
-'Cause you began
with a '67 Mustang.
I did, yes.
When I was about 17 years old,
I was living in New York,
and I wanted to get
to Los Angeles, and I did
a print ad for Levi's,
and I took that money
and I bought a '67 Mustang,
six-cylinder,
and I learnt how to drive
somewhere between
New York and Maryland,
and then got pretty good at it
somewhere around
the Texas panhandle.
-You've got
a Panamera now, too?
-I do, yeah.
What in the name of all
that's holy possessed you to
buy a Panamera,
which is not
a good-looking car.
It was... I think it's one of
the most beautiful interiors
I've ever seen.
I like those buttons
in a herringbone.
That's brilliant.
I think it's phenomenal.
But I was actually
going to shoot  24
in cape town, in South Africa.
And the flight I had
was from Los Angeles
to frankfurt,
and then Frankfurt
to South Africa.
And Porsche, before
Panamera had come out,
they would take you off
the plane, they would take
your luggage off the plane,
they would put it
in a Panamera,
the Panamera was
being driven by
a race car driver,
and they would take you
to the next terminal, which
was about five miles away.
And he would get it
up to about 145 miles an hour,
and halfway to the terminal,
you're like, "holy shit, I've
gotta get me one of these!"
Anyway, the lap.
How was it out there?
Well, first of all, you know,
it's an amazing experience,
I have to say.
I've been watching
this show for years.
I've been making fun of people
driving this car all the time,
and the whole time
while the Stig was driving,
I'm like,
"oh, I wish I'd never
made fun of anybody
driving this car."
It scared the crap out of me.
He got it going at
such a point
where I'm like,
"you're not gonna make it!
You're not gonna make it!"
Literally, I felt like that
sticker of Garfield
at the back of the car,
trying to crawl out.
That'll be the follow-through.
We'll go through the tyres.
So, who would like
to see the lap?
AUDIENCE: Yes!
Can I say,
can I introduce this?
Yes.
The following events
take place in real time.
I've always wanted to do that!
Here we go. Let's play it.
SUTHERLAND:
I like the colour.
CLARKSON:  Yeah, the colour
stands out well.
You see, this is
unusual weather
for Britain in January.
This is that moment
where you think of
nothing to say.
Except,  "scheisse."
CLARKSON:  You should've
said, "damn it!"
SUTHERLAND:  Damn it!
CLARKSON:  We would have liked
a "damn it!"
Or maybe, "send me
the schematics of the track
on my PDA,"
That would have been
another good one.
That's very tidy,
through there.
And in... Ooh, yeah,
that's very well done,
in that weather.
Come on!
Oh, you're in fourth,
you prat!
CLARKSON:  "Prat"
gives it away.
SUTHERLAND:  Yes.
CLARKSON:  No American's
gonna say "prat,"
Or Canadian.
Tidy again.
Hit the brake
like you hate it.
CLARKSON:  Yes, look at
the tight line there,
driving on the brake.
It does handle
very well, that...
Ooh, now, wait.
You've got it
understeering there.
SUTHERLAND:  Yeah.
CLARKSON:  That is
very slippery.
SUTHERLAND:  It felt
so much faster
when we were doing it.
CLARKSON:  Yes, it's...
It's tragic.
Don't you dare
take your foot off,
you pussy.
CLARKSON:  The thing is,
the slower it looks, weirdly,
sometimes, the faster it is.
SUTHERLAND:  Yeah?
CLARKSON:  See, that's...
Look at that, staying away
from the tyres,
very smooth again.
I don't know
what the time is yet,
I haven't seen.
SUTHERLAND:  This is
the tricky part.
CLARKSON:  Oh, that's
a tricky corner,
that is.
SUTHERLAND:  Oh,
it's mean.
CLARKSON:  But that was
beautifully done.
And again, beautifully done
'round Gambon,
and across the line!
There you go.
Thanks very much.
CLARKSON: Well,
there we are.
So...
Where do you
think you've come?
Oh, gosh.
I have no idea.
CLARKSON: Bearing in mind,
okay, these are all
dry laps up here.
SUTHERLAND: This is where
I need my glasses.
CLARKSON: The wet ones
start with James Blunt.
I can't remember what
"fw" stands for.
I think, "fairly."
Anyone? But it
might not be.
Oh, "fairly wet," yeah.
I think our fastest
wet lap we've had so far,
at a 1, what is it, 49.4?
What do you think?
I really haven't a clue.
Okay, Kiefer Sutherland,
you did it in...
-Well, 1...
-Good.
CLARKSON: That's
not surprising.
What is surprising
in that weather
is the next one.
-40.
-Okay.
-See, what's terrifying me...
-(Sutherland laughing)
...Is if, and I like
James Blunt a lot,
he's a really good guy.
Mmm-hmm.
But if James Blunt's
faster than Jack Bauer,
this could end  24, so...
Yeah. Okay.
All right, here we go.
1.49...
AUDIENCE: Ooh...
-2.
-So that...
-Will go where?
CLARKSON: Two.
SUTHERLAND: There.
Are you happy with that?
I'm... You know what?
Yes.
I've never run on a track.
I mean, anything I've ever
been asked to do in a car,
which is quite a lot of stuff,
but they basically say,
you know, "okay, I want you
to go as fast as you can,
"start here, and then when you
see that bus, hit it,"
You know?
That, I do really well.
Anyway, ladies and
gentlemen, can I just say
on behalf of all of us,
-thank you so much for coming.
-My gosh, thank you so much.
-Kiefer Sutherland!
-Thank you guys very much!
Thank you.
Right.
Tonight, we are in Australia,
trying to find out if
modern complicated cars
can survive the outback.
Indeed! The producers had
told us to drive from Darwin
to a three million acre farm,
where we would have to
round up 4,000 cows
using a BMW M6,
a Bentley Continental
and a Nissan GT-R.
542 horsepower
from a twin turbo v6.
It is absolutely ballistic!
The mid-range thrust of this,
when you're midway
through a corner it just...
-(Engine revving)
-Whoa!
Launches itself.
I think, in this, you could
give pretty good sports cars
a pretty big surprise.
CLARKSON: In the early days,
BMW's M cars sounded like
500 yards of ripping
calico and they had
telepathic steering
and they were magnificent.
In recent years, though,
some of the magic
has sort of gone.
With this one, though,
it is back.
It is properly back!
God! This is just
electrifyingly good!
CLARKSON:  Soon, the producers
told us to pull over for some
kind of motor racing event.
What manner of thing
will it be, I wonder.
CLARKSON:  The mystery
deepened when we arrived
and were given idiotic
health and safety outfits.
But then, all was revealed.
CLARKSON: Holy cow!
Most of the steel used to
build modern China came out of
this vast hole in the ground.
But today, it would
be our racetrack.
It must be a hill climb.
Like Goodwood.
-MAY: yeah, it is.
-But it's not exactly
like that.
Not, exactly, no.
Every single corner has got
a drop on it that's lethal.
Oh, hello. Oh, it's you.
"You will now take it in turns
to drive up the
hill climb course...
-It is, yeah.
-"...Attempting to beat
a benchmark time."
And let me guess,
the benchmark time
is set by the Stig?
It isn't the Stig.
But it is the Stig's
Sustralian cousin!
CLARKSON: He's bigger
than the Stig.
MAY: Mmm.
And he's got a bigger...
...Sausage.
-How did you find that out?
-Well, look!
-Even from here,
one can see that he's a...
-Hammond: Big Stig.
CLARKSON:  Big Stig would be
laying down the gauntlet in
a typical Aussie sports car...
A Holden ute.
-You know that,
whatever it's called, Maloo?
-Hammond: Yeah.
It's got more horsepower
than my BMW.
-Does it?
-Two more.
Three... Two... One... Go!
Whoa! That's a spectacular
thing to look at!
Whoa! He's gone a bit
sideways there!
What?
-Hammond: Am I the only one
who really likes that ute?
-Yes, you are.
And then ready, steady, and...
Across the line!
HAMMOND: Gordon Bennett!
He was... Oof!
CLARKSON:  As Big Stig's
dust settled,
the three of us made our way
to the bottom of the mine.
I'll win this.
I seriously doubt that.
Well, I will or he will
because we've got
-four wheel drive.
-It's true.
Four wheel drive is useful
on a tractor, but on a normal
road car it's pointless.
It's like water.
-How's it like water?
-Well, 'cause it's neither
good nor bad,
it just doesn't do anything.
Water is useful
for a lot of things.
Well, it is if you put
hops in it or grapes.
But on its own...
When was the last time
a rear wheel drive car won
the world rally championship?
-Ha!
-Uh... Recently.
-Not that recently.
-Well, in my mind it was.
It was 1983
-and that was yesterday.
-Correct.
Ever since then,
it been four wheel drive and
that's a rally stage isn't it?
I shall do this first
and you will witness poetry.
Fire away.
CLARKSON:  In front of a crowd
of bemused miners,
I prepared for my run.
Traction control, off.
Three... Two... One! Go!
He's struggling
for traction already.
Dive for second,
still spinning the wheels.
Third!
Still spinning the wheels.
Maybe I should've kept
the traction control on.
Whoa!
Slithering. Big slide.
God above!
What if, all of a sudden,
whoosh!
And then we just saw
the underside of his BMW?
MAY: I'd check
the exhaust is okay.
Come on, Beemer!
Give me that 575 horsepower!
Four wheel drive
is for the weak!
180 kph.
And through the lorries
and across the line!
MAY:  Next, the Bentley.
And the magnificent
country residence of the
Duke of Marlborough
takes its place
on the starting line.
I'm gonna bias the suspension
slightly towards soft,
because I might get
more traction that way.
Three... Two... One! Go!
Grip, grip, grip! Good girl!
MAY:  After just 100 meters,
the four wheel drive
Bentley was four seconds
ahead of the BMW.
Into the hairpin.
Oh, four wheel drive
helped me around that a treat!
(Chuckling)
Hairpin.
The china and silverware
is going to fall over
and make a terrible mess for
the butler to clear up later.
Right. Braking,
ready for the... Oh, god.
Turning it.
Come on, bite! There you go!
(Chuckling)
Right, viewers,
now we're alone.
Look, that car should be
the fastest up that course,
but with the best one in the
world, I'm not going to be.
So, I've got a plan.
English Stig!
I've been carrying him
around for days.
With English Stig smuggled
into the driving seat,
the GT-R readied for the off.
There he is, look. Hello.
Three... Two... One! Go!
(Engine Revving)
-That's quite a
vigorous start, actually
-Hello.
-Erm, that was a racing
line there. Did you see?
-Yeah.
None of what I'm seeing...
-Makes sense?
-...Is possible.
HAMMOND: Oh my God!
Did you see that twitch
he did there?
CLARKSON: He's twitching!
He's actually...
Where's he going?
He forgot where
the end mark...
Well, he did something
James May-ish.
(May Groaning)
Thanks very much.
Oh, here he is.
-That was very quick.
-Yeah.
-It was vigorous.
-Four wheel drive.
HAMMOND: It's a good car.
It flatters.
-I'm not saying...
-It does. No. No.
He was right to say it.
I, you know,
I wasn't that confident,
but it does look after you
all the way.
We have the times
here, anyway.
The Australian Stig
in the HSV Maloo did a 1.17.8.
I was a little bit slower,
as it's turned out.
MAY: Really?
HAMMOND: Go on.
He was 1.17.8, I was 1.31.6.
HAMMOND: That is slower,
isn't it?
Bentley, 1.18.6.
-Oh! That's not bad!
-That's pretty good.
I'm pleased with that.
You were really...
You were only a second off.
Yeah, I was on it
in the old Bentley.
Gt-r, 1.13.3.
Four and a half seconds
faster than a Stig?
-Well, well done you.
-Thank you.
CLARKSON:  As we got
back on the road,
I could accept that
four wheel drive makes sense
in an iron ore mine.
But James' time? No.
1 minute 13 seconds,
James May.
It normally takes James May
1 minute 13 seconds
to go through a door!
How did he do that?
And more to the point,
how did our cars do that?
To be in this Bentley,
hammering up that hill,
you're asking a lot
of a modern luxury car
weighing the best part
of two and a half tonnes.
It did it.
HAMMOND:  After a
dirty, dusty day,
we were looking forward
to staying in an actual hotel.
Sadly, though, this was
the only one for miles.
-Evening.
HAMMOND: Is that a bed?
MAY: Is it? Yeah.
HAMMOND:  Jeremy therefore
suggested we should
leave immediately.
And try a new type of tenting
that he just thought of.
HAMMOND: What are you doing?
Most people build a campfire
and then sit around it, yes?
-Yes!
-What I've done,
is built the campfire
round us.
So we can sit in the middle,
cook our salmonella,
and none of all the dangerous
animals can get at us.
I have revolutionised tenting,
is what I've done.
Hang on.
HAMMOND: What are you
doing there?
CLARKSON: What's the best way
of starting a fire?
Petrol.
What must the world look like
from inside that head?
-Are you ready?
-Yes.
Behold!
I've made fire all around us!
-HAMMOND: Brilliant! Jeremy!
-What?
One of the many advantages of
a single traditional campfire
that you sit around is
that you can move
out of the way of
where the smoke's going.
Yeah, you can't with mine
but we are safe.
Get down! Get down low!
-Down low, it's better!
-I already am down low,
it's worse!
No, it's better here!
-Anyway...
-What?
Where are the tents?
In the cars!
-Well...
-You plum sack.
CLARKSON:  The next morning,
after another dreadful night,
we were back on the road.
And after about four hours,
Professor Hammond
finally realised something.
Oh!
It's big, yeah,
it is big, Australia.
CLARKSON:  We were headed
for the gigantic farm where
we'd be herding cattle.
And we decided to try
and reach it in one day.
The drive would be enormous!
I spy with my little eye
something beginning with "t."
Tree.
I spy with my little eye
something beginning with "t."
HAMMOND: Termite mound.
I spy with my little eye
something beginning with "t."
It's tree! Just stop it!
CLARKSON:  Since Hammond
wouldn't play,
I tuned in to the only station
that my radio could receive.
MAN: (Over Radio)
Light weight heifers
out of Darwin,
heading to Indonesia,
are now fetching up to
$2.25 a kilo.
Feeder steers heading into
Indonesia up to $2.45 a kilo.
Why don't you play Steely Dan?
Normally, you get some
excitement in this
part of Australia
when you have to
overtake a convoy
of gigantic road trains.
We were actually quite looking
forward to the peril.
A lot of dust coming up here.
CLARKSON:  But, in cars
as fast as ours,
it was a doddle.
I'm out of their way.
I'm free.
CLARKSON:  At 1:00, I had a
delicious Aussie lunch.
(In an Australian accent)
Bloody hot ring burner!
And then, it was back
to business as usual.
MAN: (Over Radio)
C2 heifers sold
from 160 to 176.
Lightweight C3 heifers,
lifted four.
They sell from 160 to 190.
And heavyweight heifers
returned up to 204 cents.
C2 yearling steer
at the feeders...
CLARKSON:  Darkness had fallen
when we finally reached
the bottom of the farm drive.
Joy of joys.
But it took another two hours
to reach the farmhouse
at the top of it...
WOMAN: Welcome to wave hill.
Thank you.
...Where there were no
spare bedrooms.
So, I decided to try another,
new sort of tenting.
HAMMOND: Do you know what?
CLARKSON: What?
HAMMOND: We started this,
I liked all three cars,
I still do,
but my conviction
that the Bentley is the best,
it's now absolute.
-I just...
-(Clarkson snorting)
I still find it
slightly, sort of...
HAMMOND: What?
MAY: There's still a slight
hint of faux toffery about it.
Which suits you
very well, obviously,
but the great thing
about the Nissan is,
it's just a finely-honed
driving instrument.
Well, no, okay,
on the Nurburgring,
-yours is awesome.
-MAY: Don't mention
the Nurburgring.
-HAMMOND: But, that's
what it's for, James.
-No, it's not.
HAMMOND: And, Jeremy, your BM,
it does look brilliant.
CLARKSON: There you go.
MAY: It's a very competent
motor car, the BMW.
That's damning with
faint praise, that is, May.
Yes, exactly.
Yours is a bit too
Dolce & Gabbana.
Yours is a bit too Poundland.
They're both brilliant cars,
make no mistake.
What are you doing,
by the way?
Claymores. They're mines.
I brought them from Britain.
Ring our campsite
with Claymores,
then any animal that comes...
(Imitates Explosion)
They will be...
It will become a veneer.
When my work was done,
and May and Hammond
had drunk all the beer,
we turned in for the night.
(Explosion)
HAMMOND: What was that?
CLARKSON: That was the sound
of me saving your life.
HAMMOND:  The next morning,
our campsite looked
like an abattoir.
What's this?
Crocodile's ear.
It's hairy.
Crocodiles do have hairy ears.
They don't even have ears.
They do.
That was a crocodile
that was coming to eat us.
And my claymore
saved our lives.
Look what we've got here,
Hammond.
It's a crocodile's hoof.
You've detonated one
of the man's cows.
Let's not get bogged down
with "ooh, blew-up,"
All right?
Because I've been
reading about this farm.
Yes?
It's actually
3.2 million acres.
So, another 200,000 acres
just slipped in there.
And to put that
in perspective,
this single farm is the same
size as Buckinghamshire,
and Hertfordshire, and Surrey,
and East Sussex,
and West Sussex,
and Kent combined.
It's the same size
as the south east of England.
Everything you see here,
and a lot more besides,
is one farm.
And as we set off to do
cattle herding,
we were still struggling
to get our heads 'round
the enormity of it all.
It's 250 miles from this farm
to the nearest supermarket.
That's like driving
from London to Newcastle
just to buy some washing up
liquid and some bog roll.
And it's not driving
on motorways,
it's not the a1,
it's not the m1. It's tracks.
MAY: In Britain,
the average beef herd
is between, sort of,
28 and 50 cows.
And here it is 64,000.
Our task was to round up
4,000 of them.
And we assumed this many
would be easy to spot.
Now, have you raised
your suspension up, Hammond?
Yes, I have.
CLARKSON: Can you see
any cows?
HAMMOND: No. No. Not one.
But, we could be
in equivalent of dover,
and the cows could be
in Beaconsfield.
MAY: Well, I was just
thinking that.
What if they're all
in the opposite corner?
They could be a hundred miles
away from here.
Even the high-tech
BMW was no help.
FEMALE AUTOMATED VOICE:
Voice commands, new entry.
Spell name of place.
Some cows.
FEMALE AUTOMATED VOICE:
Did you mean sheep hills?
No. Not "sheep." cows.
MAY: What's the noise
you make to attract a cow?
If it was dog,
it would be, sort of
(Whistling).
I don't know anything
about cows.
Apart from
what they taste like.
It is difficult to be a cowboy
when we can't find any cows.
41 degrees out there.
No cows.
After an hour's
meandering about, however,
we struck gold.
(Shouting) Cow.
CLARKSON: Oh, there.
Yes, cows.
I'm counting, four cows.
That is a start.
Get'em. Round'em up.
MAY: You two take the flanks.
I'll stay at the rear.
Yee-haw!
Don't get too close.
Panic'em, you'll
spoil the burgers.
We've got them. We have them.
MAY: This is perfect.
(Mooing)
CLARKSON: We're brilliant
at this.
But, then...
They're going to break
and go in the woods.
They're getting
into the trees.
I can't go in there.
It's too rough.
And even though Hammond
had four wheel drive,
it turned out, he couldn't
go in there either.
(Engine Roaring)
Erm, I'm beached.
CLARKSON:  And by the time
James had pulled him out...
Three, two, one, action!
(Engine Revving)
CLARKSON:  ...our four cows
had wandered off.
Sitrep. We found four cows
and we lost them.
So, what chance would we have
when we found 4,000?
(Mooing)
CLARKSON: Right.
Right.
This is the biggest flock
of cows I have ever seen
in my entire life.
Our job was to get
them all turned 'round
and then herd them into
a giant pen which was
ten kilometres away.
A pretty tall order
for three cars like these.
It's like  Zulu, watching them
coming towards us.
MAY: Here we go.
CLARKSON: Has anyone got
any plans? 'Cause I haven't.
Hammond suggested we break
the herd into smaller chunks,
but that didn't work at all.
They're going in completely
the wrong direction now.
Oh, now they've come...
How are they...
What... They've gone...
They're just going 'round me.
They're not very scared of me.
MAY: Yeah, I'm in the middle.
I've been herded by the cows.
It's all gone wrong.
(Laughing)
MAY: Clarkson,
where the hell are you?
CLARKSON: I am now
in cow dust.
I can see nothing.
Okay, they're charging me.
This is unexpected.
They're running towards me.
MAY: We're in the middle
of the cows.
We've been outwitted by cows.
HAMMOND: Erm, nice cows.
Morning, cows.
That bull is menacing me.
This is a remarkably
brave cow.
It won't be pushed back
into line at all.
Well, I say cow,
I mean massive bull.
Look, I may need
some help here.
This guy is properly stubborn.
I shall call you James May.
It fears the Nissan more.
CLARKSON:  As it turned out,
that wasn't entirely accurate.
(Banging)
He is head-butting me.
(Clarkson Laughing)
He head-butted your Datsun.
CLARKSON:  Meanwhile,
back in the Bentley...
(Hammond Whistling) Jeremy!
CLARKSON:  Clearly,
things weren't going well.
So, we made a decision.
I think there are
too many for us.
HAMMOND: Well, yes.
We need the cavalry.
And ten minutes later,
it arrived.
(Laughing)
One of the most dangerous
jobs in the world,
flying the
Robinson helicopters
to muster the cattle.
On average, one of about
eight are killed every year.
Sometimes,
they will use the skids
to actually push
the cows into line.
With the air-cav as backup,
we started to get
our act together.
Hammond, you are the rough
terrain response.
And I'm the quick response.
HAMMOND: (Over Radio)
That's good, that's good.
You channel them in,
I'll drive them forward.
CLARKSON: Flank in, flank in.
MAY: Go on, go left.
Power sliding my horse.
HAMMOND: Breaking right.
CLARKSON: Good work, Hammond.
Good work.
That Bentley going
across that field
is a sight to behold.
Look at its wheels.
Soon, we realised something.
Oh, there you go.
Look at that.
CLARKSON:  For once,
Top Gear  was being ambitious,
and not rubbish.
All right, cowboy.
HAMMOND: I feel pretty manly.
I feel like one
of those bulls.
HAMMOND: I loved that.
-CLARKSON: God, that was fun.
That was a lot of fun.
-It was.
And these cars?
Better than horses.
-And nobody fell off!
-Much better.
-CLARKSON: Yeah.
-But, can we just
stop for a moment?
The amazing thing,
the cars survived it.
Nothing broke, all three.
Fantastic! And if Nissan,
well actually, or Bentley,
or BMW,
-if they made a laptop.
I'd buy it.
-Hammond: yeah.
You could throw a Nissan
laptop in the lavatory,
do a log on it,
and you'd still be able
to log on on it.
You would!
Anyway, we must now decide
which of these cars
is the best.
Well, I'm not backing down.
It's the Bentley.
I'm not backing down.
It is this Nissan.
James, sorry mate,
you are just wrong.
The Nissan GT, it has
a whiff of the Nurburgring,
no, it's not just a whiff
of the Nurburgring,
it reeks of it.
Your clothes will smell of it
six weeks after
you've been in it.
It's better than it smelling
of Ryan Giggs' bathwater.
No, no, it's a Bentley.
Think what that means.
I'll tell you
what it means, Hammond.
It means it is 66,000
more expensive than this.
Yes, because that's a Nissan!
That's a Bentley.
Exactly! It's a Nissan,
and when you strip everything
off this Nissan,
you find, underneath,
a racing car.
When you strip all the stuff
off of that Bentley,
underneath it is a VW!
If we strip
all the stuff off you,
we find underneath the same
basic skeleton as you would
find in a racing driver,
but when we put it
all back on, as we must,
to make you James May,
you're James May!
That's the wrong car!
Yes, but , Hammond
if we stripped everything
off of you,
we'd find the same
skeleton that you'd have
in a racing driver,
when he was a little boy,
but when you put it
all back together,
you are still
Richard Hammond.
You, in that GT-R,
is like you in those shoes.
Ridiculous!
Says the man in the jacket
woven out of 100% pure 1935.
That was designed
very specifically
for a purpose,
to feel good on the
ragged edge of performance.
You're not going to do that.
You have a watch
that can go to the moon.
You're never gonna go
to the moon. They don't make
moon boots in your size,
but you like
having that watch,
because it means
it is a good watch, and
it's the same with the car.
You're just being
a (Bleep).
Thank you.
And you've got a
(Bleep) Like a
(Bleep) (Bleep).
A baby one!
Gentlemen, gentlemen,
gentlemen, I'm sorry,
I'm gonna have to
interrupt at this point,
because the fact of
the matter is, by any
measurable muse you choose,
-the BMW is the best car.
-(Hammond spluttering)
-But, I wouldn't buy one.
-Well, why?
Because fast, expensive BMWs
plummet in value
as soon as you buy them.
You buy one of those,
within 18 months,
you're gonna lose
40-45,000,
and as a Yorkshireman,
I just couldn't handle that,
really couldn't.
-That means you have to
choose one of these two.
-I know.
I find myself, now,
with the casting vote.
Um, the problem I have is,
okay, I'm at the precise age
when I'm growing
out of the Nissan and
into the Bentley.
That's the problem
I've got.
And that is why you
should have this.
The Nissan will help you rage
against the dying
of the light.
Rather than any of that,
you can grow old gracefully
and in comfort in the Bentley,
which is a great place to be.
It's got quilted leather
in there.
Hammond, quilted leather
is what an incontinence sheet
looks like
if you look at it
under a microscope.
I have made up my mind.
Right now,
I've made up my mind.
I'm gonna ditch my
Yorkshireness, not care
about the depreciation,
go for the Beemer.
Because, come on.
We never change our mind.
We never will.
CLARKSON: The thing is,
it's breathtaking, that car.
MAY: All right.
And on that bombshell,
it's time to end.
Thank you so much
for watching. See you
next week. Good night!