How much longer to the embassy, my good man?
I'd say about twenty minutes, sir.
Huh?
The brakes...
H-Hey!
You!
Look out!
Our diplomat in Ostania died in an accident,
but we at the bureau believe he was
assassinated by a certain Eastern far-right party.
They want a war with our
great nation of Westalis.
It is paramount that we uncover
the full extent of their plans.
We should send the best...
Our top agent,
Twilight.
As promised,
photographic proof that the foreign
minister wears a wig.
The negatives, too.
Good work.
This should be enough to make the man resign.
I'll call again.
Hey.
Now, the package you promised, if you please.
Huh?!
But I just—
They got me!
Codename, "Twilight."
The man was a spy.
In an age where nations the world over
engaged in a relentless secret information war,
the man had worn some hundred faces
to survive just as many battles.
So, Papa says some guy "stole the wig
pics," and he has to take it out on me!
I don't get it!
It's crap, you know?
Hey, are you even listening, Robert?
Hmm?
Yeah, that's rough.
Hey, Robert.
You think, one day, we might—
Karen, let's break up.
What?!
Your conversation lacks intellect.
Goodbye.
I wish you all the best.
Wait,
Robert!
Where'd that come from?!
Sorry, Karen,
but my business with you
and your father is done.
After tonight, I'm done being Robert.
Marriage?
An average life of happiness?
I left any attachment to such prospects behind,
along with my papers, the day I became a spy.
Meow.
Cipher C, huh?
The train to Berlint will shortly
be departing from platform five.
Hello or good evening, Mr. Twilight.
Good work on the last mission.
Thanks to you, the minister can keep his post,
where he may prove an asset to our nation.
Now, as for your next mission,
your target is the president of the
National Unionist Party, Donovan Desmond.
A dangerous man, and a threat
to peace between east and west.
Your job is to get close to him,
and investigate his movements.
To that end, first,
get married and have a child.
Pardon?!
Desmond is a cautious man,
who rarely shows his face in public.
He has only been known to appear at the
social events hosted by his son's prestigious school.
These gatherings are a place for the
financial and political elite to rub shoulders.
You must get your child into that school,
and infiltrate these gatherings.
Furthermore, the school
admissions deadline is soon.
You have one week.
How do I make a kid in seven days?!
Excuse me.
Operation Strix.
This mission is vital to ongoing peace
between east and west, and thus, the world.
Dear unsung heroes,
the work you do will
never see the light of day.
There will be no medals,
not one small article in the paper.
Nonetheless,
never forget that your sacrifice forms the
basis upon which the people live their lives.
Very well...
I lost my name and face
to become Twilight.
I'll play the part of a father.
If that's what it takes
to build a better world.
"Operation 'Strix' "
Here we have the family apartment.
Fully furnished, with heating and
air conditioner, as well as...
Um, sir?
No bugs.
Easy escape route.
I'll take it.
Then, Mr. Forger,
if you could sign these papers...
Loid Forger,
a psychiatrist.
My latest life.
A loving family,
a happy household...
Isn't it wonderful, finding
a home for your family?
Do you have a little boy, or a little girl?
Oh, that's...
...undecided.
Huh?
It's the last thing a spy needs.
What?
You wanna adopt a kid?
Indeed.
I heard this orphanage
offers adoptions, and...
The truth is, my wi—
Sure.
Take your pick of the litter.
Huh?
Come on in.
The state of this place...
However, there are more children of unknown
origin in these obscure institutions,
which helps when it comes
to doctoring their history.
This mission needs a kid,
and I'll figure the rest out.
Really, I'd rather handle
the whole thing myself.
Still, while I may be the
best spy in Westalis,
even I can't pass myself off as a child.
Oh, sorry, I'm looking for a child
who can read and write, if possible.
Hmm, in that case...
Hey, Anya!
She's the smartest one we've got.
Doesn't talk much, but she's not a bad kid.
Creepy brat! Can't say I like her.
I just want her out of here quickly.
Come on, say hello to the man.
Err, excuse me...
Age of admission at Eden
College was six, I think.
This girl's clearly four or five, at most.
Six!
Hmm?
Six.
Oh, huh, you're six?
But she's so small though...
The paper?
The crossword?
That's a bit beyond a child, isn't it?
Though, I'd say it's child's play.
One down, "homeostasis."
One across, "determinism."
Then, under that, "symplectomorphism."
She did it?! For real?!
What a fearsome intellect!
She'd get through the
entrance exam, no problem!
I'll take her.
Now, if there's paperwork—
Never mind that.
Just take her off my hands, already!
I have a kid. Mission accomplished.
That was almost too easy.
You okay with that?
Spy!
Mission!
So excited!
The girl was a psychic.
Subject No. 007.
The girl could read minds.
A certain organization had made her,
through science and chance.
She would later flee the facility,
and drift from place to place
in search of a guardian.
Listen up, little lady.
Anya!
Listen up, Anya.
I took you in as my daughter today,
but I want those around us to
think you were with me from birth.
You understand?
Aye.
Address me as "Dad," alright?
Father.
Right.
My, what a little darling! Hello!
We just moved in. Forger's the name.
I'm Anya, and I've been
Father's child for ages.
Oh?
Not helpful.
Alright, let's head in.
My house?
Yep.
TV!
Turn it on, if you want.
- Adventure awaits in... Spy Wars!
- I like this!
Well, I never...
You got a gun with a silencer, eh?
So excited!
You're a pro!
First off, I have to get everything I need,
and get some papers forged for the girl.
Right, I'm going out for a bit.
You watch that and wait here.
Adventure!
It's not an adventure! It's just shopping!
I want a pistol that doesn't make a sound!
Sure, if they have one on sale.
Never stand out, and always act
normal. The essence of espionage!
We must appear as a most
ordinary parent and child.
Father! Help!
Why must she stand out?
Oh dear.
You really ought to keep
a hold of your little one.
Here.
With one hand full, I'm hardly best
prepared in case of an enemy strike,
but it can't be helped.
Enemy?!
What are you doing?
Taking cover!
Did I do something to make her run for cover?
Was it too soon to hold hands?
Does she hate me?
Not good.
I need to stay on good terms with this
girl, for the sake of the mission.
I need to know more... about this organism.
Like with diplomacy, step one for
lasting peace is learning about others.
Learning about me means world peace!
I like peanuts!
I hate carrots!
I like crunchy bacon!
"Bakery" doesn't mean
"crunchy bacon," you know?
Can I have this, please?
You can't buy something that costs
one dalc, with a ten pent coin.
I'm starting to think this
girl's none too bright.
Was the crossword pure luck?
Maybe I can still swap her for another kid—
D-Don't throw me out!
Where'd that come from?!
Gosh, some parents!
I'm a good deal!
What do I do?!
Stop crying, I'll buy you some peanuts!
Peanuts!
Father,
I'm sleepy...
Can't walk.
I give up.
I don't understand...
...the utter absurdity of her behavior!
I'll need manuals to decode this one...
"Trust is the most essential
part of parenting."
"Don't scold, sympathize. Try to see
things from your child's point of view."
"Children aren't good at verbalizing
their thoughts and feelings."
"You have to be intuitive with children."
So, I guess interrogations are a no go.
I really don't know how parents do what
they do. It feels like mission impossible.
"Nurture self-esteem to prepare
your child for the future."
"Teach your child to think for
themselves, so when they grow up..."
Once the mission's over,
she's going back to the orphanage.
That's the sum total of our relationship.
No!
I hate studying!
I need to know your academic level
to prepare for the entrance exam.
I don't need to study! I can do the test!
I just listen out for pe—
People's thoughts!
What? Are you planning on cheating?
Look, if you don't get in, it's mi—
Mission failed.
Fine!
I'm going out.
You're not coming this time!
Not today!
You stay right here!
Hey!
What did I just say?!
You there! I see you!
There!
Father's on a full-on finding-spree...
Fun!
Bet you can't get out now!
So that's why you were late?
In the end, I barricaded the
damn front door to seal her in!
Here's hoping that no one
reports you for child abuse.
Still, I really don't know what
goes on inside a child's head.
The way they try to cry away
any problem ticks me off.
Crying is pretty much part of
their job description, Mr. Twilight.
Anyway, here. As per your request...
Application form, exam
ticket, and exam questions.
Not an easy thing to get, you know?
You're a lifesaver, Franky.
Even she can get in if I can
get the answers in her head.
Oh yeah! The kid!
The orphanage had no records
for her, but I found them!
Nothing on her birth.
Age and parents, both unknown.
Couldn't find anything
beyond the last year or so,
but she's been in four foster
homes, returned each time.
Bounced between a fair few orphanages, too.
Anya Williams.
Anya Levski.
Anya Roche.
Swapping names left, right, and
center! Like father, like daughter!
Huh?
I'm kidding, man.
It's the mission, I know.
Sure, she's just a kid, but it's never
a good idea to get too attached, eh?
I'll keep that in mind.
Hey! My fee!
Geez...
Well, I for one really don't know
what goes on inside a spy's head.
Bored.
Being a spy isn't what I thought.
I want to get a bomb back.
I can't have her playing with my spy
gadgets, so I'll keep them locked up.
The combination is six, one...
...one, zero.
Bomb! Bomb!
Whoa!
Secret comms!
Secret! Secret!
Boss,
we've intercepted new comms.
Western ciphers?
No, sir. Seems like plain text.
Err...
"Twilight..."
"...on the scene..."
"Twilight on the scene"?!
This is the frequency that
the western agents use, sir.
Oh, there's more!
"Tag..."
"...you're it."
Find the transmission source, now!
So, you know I'm a spy? You must be silenced!
He can't know I'm a psychic, either,
or I'll have to leave.
Anya, you must tell no one of
your power, you understand?
Now, it's time you got back
to your studies, Anya.
I want to do drawings.
You've no need for such childish frivolities.
We must use your power to
bring peace to the world.
We have no time to waste on tears.
Now, stop playing, get studying.
She'd better not have trashed the room.
Oh, right. I have to shift this thing.
Hmm?
Who the hell are they?!
Anya!
She's been taken?
By this bunch?
Why?
I'll find them.
Calm down.
Judging by this scene,
the enemy knows I'm a spy.
I need to make myself scarce, now.
As for Anya...
There are plenty of other kids out there.
I'll just have to start again from scratch.
What the hell is this brat doing here?
What? Is she Twilight's kid?
We don't know, boss.
She was in the room with the transmission
source, so we took her...
It was the comms!
She'd holed herself in, with a big
barricade built outside the room.
Outside? Why?
Don't know.
Well, fine.
If she's got any value as a
hostage, then we'll use her,
and get Twilight himself to go
grab the foreign minister's wig.
Boss,
why don't we give up on the wig—
Transparency is important in politics.
Wigs are bad.
A pistol that doesn't make a sound...
Moreover, the minister is a traitor
who works with the west in secret.
Those who defend traitors
are traitors themselves.
A real bad guy!
Boss, Nguyen's group is
back from the apartment!
We got the man.
Good work.
He moved like a pro.
He's the real deal, sir.
Go take five.
Alright.
Now then, Mr. Twilight,
if you could kindly return
those photos you stole.
Nguyen?!
What's going on?!
He just—
The girl's gone!
He got us, again!
I screwed up!
Walking into enemy territory,
taking any number of risks!
I'm a failure of a spy!
Father!
Fa—
Whoa! It's okay!
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Don't worry!
Darn brats...
Oh, I think I kind of get why it
ticks me off when I see a kid crying.
It reminds me of myself when I was little.
No one ever offered me a hand.
The despair, loneliness, and sense of
powerlessness, when all I could do was weep.
I thought I'd left my past behind, but
somewhere in my mind, I'd seen myself in her.
No, what's more...
Listen up, little lady.
Anya.
Listen up, little Anya.
You see, we're all a group
of professional tag-players.
When we see anyone that looks like
promising talent, we challenge them, out of the blue.
Huh...
Father's a liar.
Now,
if you go straight, then head down the
street on the right, you'll find a police station.
If you can get there and hand this
to a police officer, you win.
Got it?
If she shows them this, they'll
take her in at a better orphanage.
I won't involve any children in my plans.
- I'll find another way to do it.
- Father.
Alright, go! Now!
A failure of a spy?
No,
but I did screw up the moment
I dragged her into harm's way.
I remember now...
I wanted to make a world
where no kid has to cry.
That's why I became a spy.
That bastard's not getting away this time!
We'll drag him out, and get a
good look at his ugly mug—
A trap?! When did he—
What the hell is this?! Flour?!
T-Twilight?!
Don't shoot, or the whole place will blow!
Wha—
You're kidding me...
Turn around, and you're dead.
Twilight!
Hello or good evening, Mr. Edgar.
How's Karen doing?
You! How'd you know my daughter's name?!
Of course, I know.
That's what spies do.
I know her height, her weight, her foot-size,
everything from her favorite food
to how many freckles she has.
While she's not as rotten as you,
she's also got her own laundry list of crimes.
Don't be absurd! My daughter would never—
Edgar, I also know that
you love your daughter.
Listen closely.
If you want her to live out her days in peace,
then never come near me, again.
If you get it, then hurry home.
Anya?!
Father!
Why are you...
Uh, no, what're you doing out
of the house on your own?
I mean, I wanted to go shopping over there,
but the place was closed down.
Father's a big liar.
I was playing tag with some nice men.
Is that so?
Did you have fun?
It was a bit scary.
I wanna go home...
Back to our home.
Are you... sure?
If you leave me behind, I'll cry.
She's been in four foster
homes, returned each time.
Anya Williams.
Anya Levski.
Anya Roche.
I see.
Let's head home, then.
That apartment's dangerous
though, so we'll have to move.
I saw a nasty snake in there, yesterday.
I hate snakes.
Father's a big fat liar,
but he's a cool liar.
I want to live in a castle.
Sure, if we can get one.
Once we've moved, you've gotta study, though.
Wah!
Just look at the answers
and remember, this time.
It's easy.
Your exam starts now!
I'm counting on you, Anya.
Give it your best shot!
This is so hard!
I don't have a clue!
Which one should I pick...
Mama!
K-212.
There!
You passed!
Well done!
I did well?
You did so well!
So...
Father!
- The fatigue caught up with
me, the instant I relaxed...
- Don't leave me!
- The fatigue caught up with
me, the instant I relaxed...
- Father!
- I... relaxed?
- I'm gonna cry!
- Me?
- I'll be a good girl, so please come back!
- I must be losing it.
Father is dead.
Postal service!
Are you Miss Forger?
I'm Anya Forger.
Could you pass this on to
your mommy or daddy, then?
Mother doesn't exist.
Huh?!
Oh...
Sorry...
Father!
The postman came!
What the hell?!
Have you come here to kill me?!
I fell asleep, right there
in front of everyone.
Damn, I need to get my focus back...
Post!
It's a notice from Eden College.
What's up, Father?
The second round of assessments
will be a parent-teacher meeting!
The child must come with both parents in tow.
No exceptions.
Mother doesn't exist.
"Secure the Spouse Role"