This programme contains adult humour
Ooh, here we are.
Your place, your place.
La maison de la femme.
El casa del senorita.
Das haus die frau.
Good night.
Er... I'll just walk you
to the door.
There's no need. It's fine.
I can get there on my own.
So...
I guess this is arrividerci.
I quite fancy a cup of tea, though.
Glass of water, maybe?
Perhaps a little lie down.
Look, I have to tell you something.
What?
I wanted to say it in
the restaurant but...
a good time never came up
and I wasn't going to say it,
but I have to. Er...
What?
You've got shit on your head.
There's some shit on your head.
Where?
Where? Where?
It's been there for ages.
Oh, God!
It's chocolate.
It's chocolate. It's not shit.
It's not shit. It's my dessert.
I don't know how it got
there but it's on my fingers.
It's not shit.
Thank God for that!
Do you know, I've just spent
the last hour thinking you were
some sort of disgusting tramp.
Oooh, no!
That's funny.
Ha haaa!
Oh... It's not. It's chocolate!
Aah. How about that cup of tea now?
I was a perfect gentleman last
night from beginning to end,
but she can't see past a little
bit of shit on my forehead.
I thought you said it was chocolate.
Yes, chocolate, I meant chocolate.
PHONE RINGS
I forgot to turn this thing on.
Hello, IT.
'Hi, something's wrong
with my computer.'
'Have you tried
turning it off and on again?'
'No, I'll do that, thanks.'
'You're welcome, mate.'
You know, it's typical.
The one time I manage to bamboozle
a girl in the building into going
out with me and this happens.
Oh, she's going to tell everyone.
Oh, come on, she's a receptionist.
She'd hardly gossip.
Besides, it's a boring story.
Yeah, yeah, it's boring.
It's boring. She won't tell anyone.
SCREAMS OF LAUGHTER >
'Ello...
Sorry.
She might have told Jen.
No, no, that's what I'm saying.
It wasn't. It WAS chocolate.
It was chocolate. I don't know!
It got on my
fingers and then I must have...
Listen, how did you
even hear about this, Mum?
Moss, Moss, there's a spider in my
office. Could you deal with it?
I just hate spiders.
Oh, ah, yeah, I'm not overly
fond of them myself there, Jen.
Um, how...
How big is... Whoa, hey now!
I tell you what, I'd actually
recommend my good friend Roy there
as the go-to guy on anything
with more than seven eyes.
He's on a very brief
personal call right now.
Come on, Moss, don't be silly.
You're right, I'm being silly.
Wrap it up, Roy!
It's just a spider. It's fine!
It's just a spider.
Oh, look! It seems to have
left of its own volition.
Oh, be a man, Moss.
You're right, I'll be a man.
I'm a man.
Please don't shut the door.
I won't.
Goodbye, Jen.
That was my mother.
How did she hear about it?
Oh, was that the woman who phoned
earlier, I've been telling everyone.
Why would you want
to go out with Patricia anyway?
Her last boyfriend
was Simon from third.
Jen? >
Heya!
Hello there. >
Have you caught it yet?
Not quite Jen. >
The spider's managed to walk behind
me and it's between me and the door.
So I can't get out.
Simon from third is
the one with the hair.
Oh, him! Oh, he's awful.
He once ate a copy
of Loaded for a bet.
She liked him?!
Apparently.
I mean, that explains everything.
She likes the kind of big,
obnoxious guy who eats Loaded.
Hello, Daniel.
How are you?
Oh, I'm great, thanks. How are you?
I'm great.
Can either of you tell me, OK, OK,
who wrote Missa Brevis in D Minor?
Was it Mozart or Beethoven?
That was a certain Mr Mozart,
I think you'll find.
Oh, do you know a lot
about classical music?
Un petit pois.
Oh, right.
Mozart, Beethoven. 50-50, innit?
Actually, you were right.
It was, it was Mozart.
OK, so, let's try another one.
OK, here we are - in what year did
Mozart die? Was it 1780 or 1791?
91.
Yes, yes! Bang on! Wow.
God, I hope he
doesn't come in again.
Jen? >
Yes?
Is Roy off the phone yet?
The spider is now upon my person. >
You guys don't mind me
chilling out in here, do you?
No, chill out!
Did you see the match last night?
Oh, yeah!
Oh, yeah! God...
Did we?! Wow! What a match!
Yeah!
Oh, all of the players running up
the pitch.
Running and...
And running down it again.
Such athleticism!
What was Rooney thinking of though?
Who knows?
That Rooney...
He is a foolish boy.
Yeah, but that referee. I'm sorry,
the referee is just an idiot.
Yes, he was certainly
the villain of the piece.
Oh, Daniel. You're still here.
Yeah, just having a little break.
Do you want to come and join me?
Ha ha ha! Oh, stop it!
Well, I'd better... Anyway, cheers.
Oh, by the way, guys, if you need
any help with any more spiders,
just give me a call, OK?
We'll be fine, I think, thanks.
Actually, do you have a card?
That's good. See you.
You like him!
Who?
Oh, that good-looking man with
"Security" written on his shoulder.
Yes, yes, I do.
He seems really nice.
Oh, nice(!) Cos that's what you
women want. "Nice guys"!
PHONE RINGS
'Hello, IT.'
What are you talking about, Roy?
If my date last night proved
anything, it's that you ladies,
you don't want nice guys.
If your date proved anything,
it's that women like men without
poo on their foreheads.
That's our type.
That had nothing to do with it.
She clearly just didn't
want a gentleman in her life.
I hate to generalise, you know that,
but all women just want bastards.
That women liking bastards thing
is a total myth.
'I've tried turning it off and
on again and nothing happened.'
'Is it definitely plugged in?'
'Let me have a look.
'Oh, sorry, that's it.
Thanks very much.'
'You're welcome, mate.'
It's just not true.
Women don't want gentlemen.
They want bullies and thugs.
I'll prove it to you.
How will you prove it to me, Roy?
Oh, OK, I'll put
on a classified ad online.
A classified?
Yeah, but I'll make it
sound psychotic
and I bet I'll
get a bezillion replies.
Oh, dear God.
Come on, how much?
OK, yeah. I'll give you 20
quid if you get one response.
You're on.
Oh, my God, no!
It's all about body fluids
with you, isn't it?
Come on, Moss.
We need to get to work.
Work?
Yeah, we need to post a classified
lonely hearts ad online that makes
me sound like a psycho
so that I can prove to Jen
Oh, thank God.
I thought that thing was broken.
Shut up. Do as I tell you.
I'm not interested.
"These are just some
of the things you'll
"be hearing if you answer this ad.
"I'm an idiot and I don't
care about anyone but myself.
"PS, no dogs."
That's good.
Mine doesn't look any good now.
Go on.
"I'm going to murder you."
"You bloody woman."
Might want to play a bit hard to get.
If you were a murderer, what would
your nickname be? Mine would be
"The Gardener", cos I'd always leave
a rose at the scene of the crime.
What would your murder weapon be?
A hammer.
Hey, Moss.
Would you like to go
for dinner with me?
And then maybe back to my place?
I'd love to, Jen, but I'm
actually helping Roy at the moment.
No, no, no, no.
Who does this remind you of?
Do you want to go on a date with me?
Gandhi?
No, no, the other one, Bono.
No, no, no, I was doing Roy.
Oh, yes, yes, it's like
there was two of me.
Hey, hello.
It's security.
I hope I'm not in any danger.
Oh, my God. It's not shit.
On my head, it's not shit.
It's chocolate spread. Taste it.
Look. You can eat all of it.
That is... Oh, that is dis... Oh!
Ringo Starr?
I'll be wondering
about that all night.
How do you know about this site?
Oh, I'm a member.
Really?
You do the whole lonely hearts thing?
I'm a 32-year-old IT man
who works in the basement.
Yes, I do the whole
lonely hearts thing.
So, as you can clearly see,
it wasn't...
excrement, it was chocolate. I was
playing a joke, it was chocolate.
Jen, it's OK, I've got it.
Don't worry about it.
Listen, what are you doing tonight?
I got a response!
That was quick.
Yeah.
Why is it taking so long to download?
Something happened with the routers.
We're back to pre-broadband speed.
"Dear..."
But we're on the phone now.
Why can't you just ask me now?
I can't, Jen, trust me.
Why should I trust you?
Because I know what's good for you.
You have to be home between
eight and nine tonight.
Are you gonna be home?
OK. This sounds exciting.
Look, it might not happen,
but hopefully it will.
Now I don't know if
this is exciting or not.
Jen, Jen, it's exciting.
(GIGGLES)
"Would be very interested in
meeting up and talking it over,
"love Rebecca."
Oh, my God, what did we write again?
It started with, "Shut up."
Oh, there's more!
"I attach a photograph
for your approval, or not."
Exclamation mark. All right,
let's have a look, you mad thing.
Nice hair so far.
Eyebrows seem normal.
Two eyes.
That's the best amount of eyes.
Nice eyes too.
It has to go wrong.
She must have a shite nose.
Oh, do you remember
the internet at this speed?
Up all night and
you'd see eight women.
Good nose.
That is a good nose.
The mouth has to be wrong.
There's gotta be something
wrong with the mouth.
Now, that's a good-looking woman.
Shall I tell Jen we got a reply?
Roy?
Roy? >
PHONE
Hello, Daniel. I mean, hello.
'Jen? It's Chris Tarrant here
from Who Wants To Be A Millionaire.'
Oh, my God! OH, MY GOD!
Chris Tarrant, hello. (SHRIEKS)
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. Oh, my God!
'The next voice you hear
is gonna be Daniel's.'
Daniel's, OK.
'But before I put you on with him,
he's asked me to ask you a question.'
OK, ask me a question.
'He wants to know if you'll go out
for dinner with him tomorrow night.'
Oh, really?
Yes, yes, of course I will!
Of course I will, yes, yes,
I'll go out with you, Daniel!
'Yes, that's great, Jen. Right, let
me fill you in on what's happening.
'Daniel's doing very well,
although he has just used his 50-50.
'Here's Daniel. Daniel, you've
got 30 seconds starting from now.
'OK, Jen.'
Hello, Daniel.
'Hi, Jen, hi, Jen.
Who composed The Wooden Prince?
'Was it A, Bartok, B, Chopin?'
Did you see
I'm A Millionaire last night?
Who Wants To Be A Millionaire,
it's called. No, I didn't.
You are not going to
Adam and believe this.
Do these make me look like a bastard?
Why do you wanna
look like a bastard?
I've got that date tonight,
she's expecting a monster.
Do these make me look like a bastard?
They make you look like an idiot.
Anyway, did you see it? >
What?
Do You Want To Be A Millionaire.
Who Wants To Be A Millionaire!
Ah! Who wants to be
a person who is wrong?
Whoa, whoa, what's happened?
If I may?
Sure.
Guess who was on it last night.
You?
No, Daniel, king of men.
Daniel was on Millionaire?!
Indeed he was. And it was the
"do you want to phone a friend..."
BOTH: It's just Phone A Friend.
Anyway...
She was the Phone A Friend?
She was the Phone A Friend.
You were the Phone A Friend!
Oh, what was the subject?
Classical music is the extraordinary
answer to that question, so who,
of course, is Daniel, our esteemed
temp security guard, going to phone
but Jonathan Miller over here?
Daniel was on Millionaire.
Too bad it wasn't 50-50.
It was.
And?
I got it wrong.
Oh!
It isn't funny though.
Now I have to go on a date with him.
Wow, the rules on that show
have really changed!
You don't understand!
He asked me out on the show
before I got the question wrong.
It was all very romantic. But now,
I don't think he likes me now!
And I don't want to go out with
the biggest loser in England!
There you are, Daniel.
Hello.
Hiya.
We gonna go for this meal, then?
Yeah. Yeah, I can't wait.
I'm going to take you to
one of my favourite restaurants.
Great.
I'll pay.
It really is the least I can do.
Oh, my God.
Did you see that look?
I have a dinner date with that man.
If I'm not here tomorrow,
I want you to call the police.
Maybe not the best time to
mention it, but you owe me 20 quid.
What? You got a response?!
With the one that ended, "No dogs"?
Yep.
Oh, my God,
brilliant, more money gone.
The money that Daniel lost
wasn't really yours.
It would have been if
I'd married him, Moss.
OK, I need a good restaurant.
Maybe if he likes the food, he
won't beat me to death with a shoe.
You said you were taking him to one
of your favourite restaurants.
Haven't you got it yet?
That's what I do, I lie.
I lie and I lie - and I lie.
I went to a good place recently.
Nice atmosphere. Food's great.
Really?
Yes, what?
Sorry, I just didn't have you down
as a restaurant person.
I'm a restaurant person.
Why wouldn't I be?
Cheese string?
No, thanks.
What's this place called?
Mesijos.
Is that French?
French? No, it's English.
OK, thank you, Moss,
I'll give that a go.
I need a place to bring this girl
that says, "I'm a bastard!"
I went to a good place recently.
Nice atmosphere, food's great,
it's got a bit of an edge.
Yeah? What's it called?
Mesijos.
What is that, Spanish?
No! Spanish? It's English. Mesijos.
Okey-dokey, you get the
firecracker nachos!
And you get the
prawn bites with spicy salsa!
This seems an unusual place for
someone like you to want to meet.
Yeah, well, everyone needs
a place to come to be alone.
Can we get a clown over here, please?
You're a loner?
I'm a loner, all right.
I'm just...
a lonely loner...
on the lonely road.
Alone.
Do you always wear shades?
Always.
They help me hide the fact...
I'm always lying...
to women.
# Everyone is having, having
fun, fun, fun
# Because everything is nice and
everyone is friendly
# Lots of friendly faces
having fun, fun, fun
# Because everything is nice and
everyone is friendly
# Smile and the world will... #
Excuse me, it's just not...
sorry, it's just not appropriate
at the moment.
< # Everybody's having, having
fun, fun, fun... #
Ha, ha,
you're that bloke off the telly.
And you must be the woman he phoned.
Brilliant,
funniest thing I've seen in ages.
God, I'm a bastard!
Yes, so you keep saying.
Trouble is basically what I am.
Oh, thank you.
You know something,
I don't think
you're a bastard at all.
I am so. I am a complete tool.
No! Oh, my God!
No, don't...
SHOE SQUEAKS
I know her.
What's going on?
Stay out of this, Fonzie!
You're frightening the kids!
I don't care!
You're a brute.
This bloke just insulted me.
Hey! Bit more careful with
the clown shoe there, mister.
SHOE SQUEAKS
He caught me by surprise.
Oh, when I see him tomorrow though...
That was his last day.
Oh, thank God!
Oh, my God, look.
If you're coming, can
you just bloody hurry up?
I'm coming... I just need to
take my shoes off.
They look like such fools.
I'll call you a cab.
No, no, no, it's fine.
Taxi!
I'll get the night bus.
Don't be stupid, it's cold. Taxi!
Here...
Oh, God.
You can have your 20 back. I don't
really think the bet proved anything.
Taxi!
Thanks, Roy.
I just want...
Night, then!
Just a lonely loner,
walking down a lonely road.
Hi, girls, my name's Maurice Moss,
or Moss for short.
Sorry about the sound quality,
but I'm having to do this
in the toilet of my mum's house.
She's watching Diagnosis Murder
at full volume
and it drives me up the wall.
Don't worry, though, I'm sitting
on the toilet, but I'm not using it.
KNOCK AT DOOR
What?
Number twos, leave me alone.
< Don't forget to flush the toilet.
Don't clog it up like you usually do.
I know! Stop doing this,
you're always doing this!
You're making it go back in!
Now, my type...