Very soon, I will finish my life happy.
So, I'm still alive.
Huh?
Schedule notes.
On today's page, 1 entry has been input.
10 AM. August 17th.
Showa-dori Intersection.
An entry you don't recall?
Yeah.
I have absolutely no memory of it,
but it was entered into my IP device.
Fri.
Sat.
Sun.
10 AM   Showa-dori Intersection
Mon.
Tues.
Wed.
I see. How strange.
That's in about two and a half hours.
Some Grandpa from a parallel world
probably came and input it.
That might be it, actually.
That, or you've gone so senile that you forgot
you put it in there yourself, Grandpa.
Ai!
I'd say that's the far
more likely possibility.
So? Are you going?
That's a good question.
It does read like a promise, or something.
I don't think you should go, Grandpa.
Why?
'Cause you'll only realize
you really have gone senile.
Ai, that's quite enough.
And the chilled chocolate
is a treat you get at 3 PM.
I thought you were studying
in your room until lunch?
Which is why I need some
barley tea as a study buddy.
So, kids these days already know the term
"parallel world" in elementary school.
Supposedly, they learn it
in the early grades.
Eri-san mentioned it.
Is that so...
Why not go?
Aren't you curious?
If you go there, you might
remember something.
That's true. And it's in the neighborhood.
I'll be back in a bit.
Yes, dear. Be careful.
Hold on.
Your hat. I'll go get it.
Oh, that one's fine.
This one?
Please wait until the traffic signal changes.
Tell me, dear. Why are you standing there?
It's dangerous.
You came for me?
Yeah. I'm here.
The light is changing.
Please exit the crosswalk.
Take care not to stop
in the middle of crossing.
Please wait until the traffic signal changes.
Did I Parallel Shift?
Display IEPP.
An error?
Where am I?
To Every You I've Loved Before
From the moment they're born,
people make countless choices.
The worlds with the option you
didn't choose are alternate realities.
In other words, parallel worlds.
And their existence has now
been demonstrated.
Moving into a parallel world
is called Parallel Shifting.
That said, it's not your physical
body that does the moving.
Your consciousness, termed
your imaginality, trades places.
Small Parallel Shifts are
an everyday occurrence,
but you basically never notice.
When you can't find something
where you left it,
but then it's there when you double-check,
it's often because
of a small Parallel Shift.
If we say your original world is "0",
you Shifted from world 0, where you left
the item there, to world 1, where you didn't,
then Shifted back to 0.
The farther from 0 you go, the greater
the difference in the tangible world.
You might have a different occupation tha
n you did in world 0, or a different spouse.
Still, they're all worlds
that your choices can lead to.
The first time I made
a major choice was when I was 7.
Between Dad...
Or Mom...
Who do you wanna go with?
I no longer remember where
or how exactly they said it.
But that was essentially the situation.
I wonder how I felt, and what I said.
Even after my parents' divorce,
several times a month we'd
all go on outings together.
But, once fun time was over,
we'd leave my dad, and I'd go with
my mom back to her childhood home.
Her home was large but very old.
"It was already ancient when
your old Grandpa was a kid."
Old enough for my grandpa to say that.
Despite there being no second
floor, it had two entryways,
but it wasn't a two-family home.
The one in front is only ever opened
during New Year and on special days.
Normally, we just use
the smaller one in the back.
We lived there with my grandfather,
my grandmother, and a big dog.
The pond in the inner yard
didn't have fish or turtles,
and most of the rooms were empty.
The only things it had in excess
were empty space and ceilings.
Koyomi, where'd you get that?
Dad bought it for me last time I saw him.
It's my present for my eighth birthday!
Yuno.
Bang.
You're too young to have this.
It says for ages 10 and up.
Yeah...
But the other kids have them, too.
You don't need to copy bad stuff
from the other kids.
Grandpa!
Koyomi, is something wrong?
I'm never talking to Grandpa again!
Mom.
Yes, dear?
Can I take Yuno for her walk?
Go ahead. But come back early so
you can get ready for the wake.
Yuno?
Geez...
You can't just take off.
Hey! Yuno!
Stop, Yuno!
Wait! W—
Hey. Can you open this?
Open this lid.
Thanks.
Hey, wait a second!
Imaginary Science Research Institute
Imaginary Science...
This is where Dad works.
U-Um! Um, excuse me, ma'am?
Excuse me. Could I borrow your phone?
I was really surprised to get a call
from you all of a sudden.
You could have just called your dad
since you were at the Institute.
I don't have Dad's cell phone number, though.
You had mine?
I don't have it. I know it.
I call it all the time.
What are you talking about?
You're a goofball.
Koyomi, what are you doing?
Um, nothing. I'm coming.
I'm home. Koyomi's visiting.
Visiting?
Hey there, Koyomi.
Is Mom in the kitchen?
She is.
It's been a while. Tell me, how've you been?
I'm in a different world.
If I'd known I could've
made something special!
Not that you ever need to call us first.
This is your home, too, Koyomi.
This is a world where
I chose to go with my dad.
And it's a world where
Grandpa's still alive.
Right?
Right.
That's right. Come by any time.
Now then, I think
I'll go give Yuno her supper.
I'll come with you.
You will?
Let's both go, then.
Yuno, Koyomi came to see us today.
Grandpa.
Ah, Koyomi.
What is it?
Can I sleep in your room with you tonight?
Yes, of course you can.
That reminds me.
Is this the first time you've
visited since you turned eight?
So Yuno's gone.
Yeah.
There's no way we could
make it so she's alive again?
Unfortunately, that's not possible.
The dead can't come back to life.
Grandpa, I'm sorry.
I never got to say sorry after our fight.
Our fight?
Did we have a fight
the last time you came over?
Did your old Grandpa
scold you for something?
Even when that happens, it doesn't
mean Grandpa doesn't love you.
Don't worry.
Really? How come?
How do I explain it?
Would you rather be sad yourself,
or for someone else to be sad?
Well, I mean... I don't wanna be sad.
Right. And everyone's like that.
So, because of a momentary mood
or whatever other reasons,
people do things that make others sad.
Usually, they only realize
their mistake later,
and wonder why they ever did those things.
But at that point, they can't fix it,
so they suffer the pain of that
sadness over and over.
It's truly a difficult thing to go through.
So you see, your old Grandpa
is only trying to help you avoid that
based on his own experiences.
Because Grandpa loves you.
Because you love me?
Yup, it sure is.
But y'know, your old Grandpa
makes mistakes sometimes, too.
So in the end, what you do is
for you to decide, Koyomi.
You're going to experience
all sorts of things.
You might encounter situations where
nobody knows what might happen.
That's just how plentiful
the choices you have are.
Choices...
Then my grandfather explained
the significance of possibilities to me,
but at that age, I couldn't
really wrap my head around it.
It's even hard for your Grandpa
to figure out a simple explanation.
You're bright, Koyomi,
so once you get it, make sure
you can explain it clearly to others.
Okay.
Even when you mess up, your
old Grandpa will never hate you.
So even when Grandpa occasionally
makes a mistake of his own,
don't go hating him immediately, okay?
I love you, too, Grandpa.
Good morning.
Mom?
What is it?
Where's Grandpa?
The funeral people made
him look really nice,
and now he's resting in the main hall.
Is something wrong?
Mom, yesterday I...
There's no reason to feel embarrassed.
This is a tough time.
It's perfectly normal to want some company.
Okay.
Now, let's get ready.
We've gotta give Grandpa a proper sendoff.
The man in my grandfather's altar
photo wore a stern expression,
and looked nothing like the same,
mellow man from the previous night.
The thin-looking man in the coffin
didn't look like the picture, either.
I brought fresh water.
Thanks.
Put it down there.
Now, take a look in the top
section of that tall cabinet.
Okay.
Be careful, honey.
Yes, Grandma.
Mom, look.
Oh my. I'm amazed he saved this.
What do we do with it?
Well, it's not like we need to
completely empty this room out,
so let's put it back and...
Happy 10th birthday, Koyomi.
Don't point this at people or animals.