What do you want to know? Um...
See that? A clock, calculator in one. So...
That's free. Thank you.
Oh, here we go.
-(ANSWER MACHINE BEEPS) -Three.
Hello, David, it's Paul Shepherd here. Can you give us a call, mate? Cheers.
No!
Dave, it's Julian. Can you give us a ring, please?
-Go away! -(ANSWER MACHINE BEEPS)
Good bloke. Good laugh.
-David, it's Paul again, I think... -Leave me alone!
(MESSAGE CONTINUES, INDISTINCT)
It's fine. It is fine, that one.
That's okay. It doesn't matter.
Take that there...
That's the old office. So...
Let's get you started. Ohh.
No one is going to lose their jobs.
Yes, Head Office are talking of downsizing,
but they've said clearly
that the most efficient branch will incorporate the other one.
We are the most efficient branch.
Cogito, ergo sum, we'll be fine.
DAVID: Why should they be worried, yeah?
They trust me implicitly.
I've said there's not going to be any redundancies, so that becomes gospel.
Unconditional trust. It's nice.
Mutual. Likewise. Reciprocated.
My only worry is that the powers that be don't come down here
and pop their head round the door with their rule book
and go, "Oh, hold on, what's going on here?
"These people are mucking around." Right?
"Whilst getting the job done, they're having a laugh at work
"with the Sword of Damocles hanging over them." Right?
"This isn't in the rule book. Who's in charge here?"
Guilty! Get a new rule book!
All right?
It works with the turtle.
(ALL LAUGH)
Okay. Good. Um...
Finally, this young lady is Donna.
DONNA: Hello. ALL: Hello.
Daughter of my best friends Ron and Elaine.
She's lodging with me, so she's my responsibility,
and her dad's not only a copper but he's a bloody big bugger, isn't he?
So, hands off.
I've got something she could take down in evidence!
Oh, don't worry about this lot.
Do you want to receive some swollen goods?
(ALL LAUGH)
Wouldn't mind escaping up her tunnel!
Get out.
Get out. I mean it.
(SIGHS)
It's a shame.
I will not have her tunnel
bandied around this office willy-nilly.
Right.
Okay. Help her to settle in.
If you do have any trouble from the men...
-What does she do, Dawn? -Kick them in the balls.
-Oh! Feminist. -Get your bra off.
Do you want to go out as well?
Sorry. Burn your bra but... Feminists.
-Good point. -Yeah. Right.
Obviously keep a T-shirt on, like Charlie Dimmock.
-Okay. -Women's libbers.
That's it.
(TAPPING)
What are you doing? What are you doing? That's ridiculous.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello. Wernham Hogg.
Yeah, hang on a minute. I'll just put you through.
That is... You won't need to use that.
You've met this lot. Um, this is Gareth,
who you saw in the meeting.
Formal introductions.
Hi. Gareth. Welcome.
Just a handshake is fine.
-And Ricky. -Hi. Nice to meet you.
Even longer.
And Tim.
-Hello. -Good.
Okay. Settle her in. Get her started. Show her the phones and everything.
But first, methink the lady dost need a chair.
To sit down on.
Maybe she should sit down here
then I could teach her the ropes,
seeing that's my responsibility as team leader.
David? I'm just saying, maybe...
When people say,
"Oh, would you rather be thought of as a funny man or a great boss?"
My answer's always the same. To me, they're not mutually exclusive.
There's a weight of intellect behind my comedy. Yeah?
If you were to ask me to name three geniuses,
I probably wouldn't say, um, Einstein, Newton...
You know. I'd go Milligan, Cleese, Everett.
Sessions.
(TIM LAUGHS)
Gareth, have you got a licence to carry that?
(CHUCKLES SARCASTICALLY)
Portable phone. All right?
Can you swap places with Donna, please?
No... I'm not moving.
Do as you're told.
Why, what are you going to do, phone me?
-I am team leader. -I don't give a monkey's.
You're so immature.
Gareth, if there's one thing that I am not, it is immature.
You're an immature little tosser.
(MOBILE RINGS)
-Gareth Keenan. -Cock.
-So... -David, I was just saying to Tim...
Looks like a... Doesn't it?
-Gun holster. -It's just my portable telephone.
I was just saying to Tim maybe...
Sorry, I just thought of something.
(IMITATING CLINT EASTWOOD) I know what you're thinking,
did I make five or six calls?
The question is, do you feel lucky, punk? Well, do ya?
-Clint Eastwood. -Spot on.
Let's let them get on with it. Okay.
We're all online here. Hooked up
to the world wide web. Internet.
No shopping. All right?
Um, everyone's got email. Have you used email before?
-Yeah. -Yeah. It's easy, isn't it?
-I'll just show her on here. -Yeah.
Oh, you got a new one. See where it says "New mail"?
Just go to that. Just click on that.
(GASPS) No.
No, it's not... Yeah. It's not funny because
Donna should not have to see me
as a woman with two men doing that all over me.
You've got nice boobs.
No. It's just not, it's just my head. They've put it on there to...
Who else has seen this filth?
You know what I'm talking about. Who else has seen this filth?
You haven't even got email, Joan.
Someone printed it out for me.
Who printed this out for Joan?
Wow. I'm angry.
And not because I'm in it,
but because it degrades women,
which I hate.
And the culprit, whoever he is, is in this room.
Or she. It could be a woman.
Women are as filthy as men.
Naming no names. I don't know any.
But women are dirty.
Good friend of mine and a bloody good rep, Chris Finch,
IQ of 142, one of the cleverest blokes I know.
Certainly the cleverest bloke you know, isn't he?
Chris Finch, yeah.
He was in an argument once and he went,
"How can I hate women? My mum's one."
Yeah? There's a lot of truth in that.
And that's why when I see rubbish, all right?
I'm not annoyed 'cause I'm in it or I'm a prude.
-It offends women. -And our mums.
In a way. It's sexist, and I hate that.
-So do I. -Yeah, but I've said it, haven't I?
We've both said it. We've had meetings where we've both said it.
-Yeah, but I really hate it. -I've always...
The point is this, yeah?
We've got access to the internet, yeah? But it is not censored.
Is that a good or a bad thing?
-Bad. -Well, it's not for us to say.
All I know is I can type in
"sex...fetish". Yeah?
It takes a little while.
2,230 matches. Yeah?
Just click on one at random.
Oh...
"Dutch girls must be punished for having big boobs."
Now, you do not punish someone,
Dutch or otherwise, for having big boobs.
If anything, they should be rewarded.
-They should be equal. -Women are equal.
I've always said that, so...
-Do you want to play with my hair? -Huh?
-Do you want to play with my hair. -Play with your hair?
All right, then.
I've got kind of hot hands. Sorry.
That's all right. Just don't touch my head.
All it is...
Well...
Donna.
Yeah? My responsibility.
Away from home. I know boys will be boys.
Word from the top is...
-Hands off. -Yeah.
-Out of bounds. -Yeah.
-Look, but don't touch. -What do you mean by look?
Talk to her, be friendly,
-don't get any ideas. -Yeah. Good.
Fine.
What if she's up for it?
You want to get some of this sorted out, mate.
-What can we play now? -I don't know.
Ask around. Find out who did the picture, yes,
-discreetly. -Undercover.
Well, don't go steaming in, accusing people.
-Mmm-hmm. -Okay?
No, I'm trained in this. When I was in the army.
-Territorial. -Territorial Army.
Yeah, whatever. Okay?
Okay. I will need some stuff.
Like what?
An office.
Well, use the meeting room for now.
Right. I can say it's my office, can I?
What?
I can say to people, "Come into my office"?
-Well, while you're doing this, yeah. -Right.
-I'll make a sign. -You don't need to make a sign.
And if I need the meeting room for a meeting,
it's the meeting room again, so...
-Right. I'll take the sign down. -Don't need to make a sign.
-(MOBILE RINGS) -Don't make a sign.
Gareth Keenan.
-So... Who was that? -No one.
No, I'm sorry, you've got the wrong number. Bye.
That's that, okay?
You go left, you go right, kick.
It's ding ding da!
Yeah, but I never said that was...
No, that was straight from Thriller, though.
He goes... # Eeeh hee! Ah! Chamone! #
-It's that. -Afternoon, Mr Jackson.
I know you're an international superstar but have you sent that fax yet?
Have you heard, um... Have you heard, uh...
Michael Jackson's new song he's doing?
He's teamed up with West Ham football team, apparently.
Doing I'm Forever Blowing Bubbles!
The chimp.
She doesn't know about football. Tell her later.
Have you heard George Michael's latest release?
No. George Michael's latest song. It's his release...
-Is it about blow jobs? -Yeah, the thing in the toilet,
-it was a hand job. -Right
DONNA: Is it Wank Me Off Before You Go Go?
(ALL LAUGHING)
Um...
What's white and slides down toilet walls?
-I don't know. -Michael Jackson's latest release.
George Michael's.
Good, innit? Oh.
-Can you moonwalk? -Probably not any more.
-Give it a go? -Yeah. I used to...
You got to drop your heels back.
Not on this. You can't do it on this.
-Let me show you. -I used to do it, yeah.
Oh, yeah, I know how to do it. We used to do all that stuff as well.
All that sort of stuff, yeah. Just like take control of the body.
-And it's all that now, isn't it? -Yeah, and it's all...
-Busy? -Yeah, just, uh...
keeping up the morale.
-Can we have a chat? -Yeah.
Ooh!
Keith, Keith, Keith, Keith, Keith...
Thanks for coming in. Um...
Now, you know what this is about. Obviously you've seen the picture,
-you know, of David on the computer... -I saw it, I saw it.
Yeah. And we've all had a bit of a laugh about it, haven't we?
-It was funny. -Yeah.
There's a time when the joking has to stop, though. Um...
Not only is it derogatory...
GARETH: David has trusted me with this because
not only have I got people skills,
but I am trained in covert operations.
You know the phrase "softly softly catchee monkey"?
I could catch a monkey. If I was starving, I could.
I'd make poison darts out of the poison off of deadly frogs.
One milligram of that poison can kill a monkey, or a man.
Prick yourself, you'll be dead within a day.
Or longer.
Different frogs, different times.
Do you know who done the picture?
Yeah.
No. I mean, no.
Right. Your first answer was "yeah".
-Wasn't it? -I meant no.
-Well, why did you get... -Uh... Don't know.
Am I making you nervous?
No. I mean, yeah.
Hmm, that's interesting.
I've just spent two days in Swindon with Neil
and he's made some big changes.
Now, when we spoke on Friday,
you said you were going to instigate some changes of your own.
I just wondered how that was going.
-Great. -Good. What have you done?
Changed many things, really.
In a global sense,
streamlining the whole ongoing enterprise of it.
I'm sorry, David, that sounds like management-speak to me,
-and I know you hate that. -Yeah, I do. So...
Well, can you give me, let's say,
five practical changes that you've actually made?
-Five changes? -Mmm.
I'll give you three, and then another two if you need them.
Okay.
Efficiency. Turnover. Profitability.
I'm sorry, David, that still sounds like management-speak.
-No, because... -You hate that.
-Shall I tell you what Neil's done? -Can do.
He's frozen any wage increases,
he's put a stop on all overtime.
And any purchases of £100 or more now go through him.
Hundred? I was going to make it 90, but 100's all right.
And he has started making redundancies, David.
-That's only four. -Yeah. Whatever, David.
Have you made any redundancies?
I gave a speech only this morning to my staff,
assuring them there would not be cutbacks in this branch
and that there certainly wouldn't be redundancies, so...
-Why on earth would you do that? -Why? Oh, don't know.
A little word that I think is important in management called "morale".
Well, surely it's going to be worse for morale in the long run
when there are redundancies and you've told people there won't be?
They won't remember.
-With your arms... -This way?
-Ah! -And then...
-Ooh! Yeah, I know. Like a... -More of a...
DONNA: Yeah. RICKY: That is nice.
I'll be honest with you, David, there have got to be cutbacks.
Now, if you can't manage that yourself,
that's why I'm your boss, I can do that for you.
You're not the boss here. And you don't have to do anything for me
'cause I've already made cutbacks.
-What, you've made cutbacks already? -Yeah.
I didn't want to tell the staff, but to you...
Cutbacks where?
Staff.
-So there have been redundancies? -Yeah.
-Well, have you let anyone go? -Yeah.
Who?
Julie.
Where does Julie work?
Warehouse.
What does she do?
Just general warehouse in the warehouse. She was, uh...
I'm sorry, David, I thought I knew everyone in the warehouse.
What's her surname?
Second name?
Anderton.
Um... It's signs that Gareth's made for the door of his office.
He started off with "interrogation room".
He went to "interrogation office",
"investigation room",
"investigation office", just for the...
He really lost it here.
"Quiet, please! Investigation in process!"
"Silence. Interrogation." That's frightening.
That's the one he's gone for. "Investigation and meeting room."
Makes sense. My personal favourite, though, has to be...
"Gareth Keenan investigates!" Why?
So...
There's a lot of um...
-I'm trying to work in here. -Sorry, mate, yeah.
-How is the investigation going? -Good.
-Very good. -Do you need a deputy at all?
No. I've already got one.
-All right, Sheila? -All right?
Keep it down.
This is scary, David.
Don't tie any more cash up in stock unless you have to.
I'm sure you could lose more people from down here. Who's the foreman?
Taffy!
Taffy! (GIGGLES)
-Glynn! -What?
We all call him Taffy.
The thing is, though, no one's dispensable in my book. Yeah?
'Cause we're like one big organism, one big animal.
Yeah? The guys upstairs on the phone, they're the mouth.
And the guys down here, the hands.
-Mmm. And what part are you? -Good question.
Probably the humour.
With responsibility comes harsh things.
Um... People look at me, they say, "Oh, he's tough. He was in the army.
"He's going to be hard. By the book."
But...
I am caring and sensitive.
Isn't Schindler's List a brilliant film?
Um, yeah.
See? People think a strong man can't be sensitive
but I'm thoughtful and caring...
Sorry, what's this about?
About the picture of David with the two blokes jizzing on him.
Were they both jizzing on him?
I thought he was sucking one of them off.
I don't think...
No, look, it's just jizzing.
Well, I didn't do it.
Good. Fine.
Well, I'm glad we had this little chat.
I don't want you to think of me as your boss.
Well, you're not.
Well, I'm higher up than you, so I am.
What I'm saying is don't think of me as a boss,
-but know that I am. -I don't think you are.
Well, I'm team leader, so I am. I'm higher up than you.
(MOBILE RINGS)
Gareth Keenan.
Right, seriously. Now, just stop it.
Yes, I've had office romances.
Loads.
Not here, another place I worked at.
Good-looking ones as well.
But they're not a good idea, office romances.
It's like shitting on your own doorstep.
I've had loads of offers here, but I go, "No way."
Distracting. And that's actually one of the major arguments
against letting gay men into the army.
And I haven't got a problem with that.
You know, a gay man's not going to put me off. I can handle myself.
But if we were in battle,
is he going to be looking at the enemy or looking at me
going, "Oooh"?
You know? "He looks tasty in his uniform."
And I'm not homophobic, all right?
Come round, look at my CD collection.
You'll find Queen, George Michael, Pet Shop Boys.
They're all bummers.
(DOG BARKS ON TV)
All right, lads? What are you watching?
-It's my dog shagging his dog. -Oh, yeah.
Glynn, I'm sure David's made it clear to you that you'll be losing personnel.
That's a funny bit. Look at Gazza's face!
I'm sorry to interrupt,
do you think you can lose any more staff from down here?
-I know you lost Julie Anderton. -Who?
-Opening a can of worms there. -Julie Anderton. David fired her?
-Never heard of her. -Oh, loyalty.
When someone goes from this organisation, they no longer exist.
She never existed, did she?
-Well... -You made her up.
Well, you backed me into a corner and I...
-You lied. -It's a form of acting.
Can you take this upstairs? We're a bit busy.
-You don't look busy. -Do you want me to get busy, love?
I'm sorry?
You can be next. Gazza likes some posh.
-A word with you. Now. -Yep.
That was out of order in a way.
-Ooh! -No, I'm not in trouble.
What she needs is a good shagging!
I might bloody have to now. See you later.
Now, then. You two.
Dawn and Tim.
What do you want, Gareth?
I've been assigned to find out who did the picture.
Right. Who was it?
-Well, I don't know. -Will you get fired?
-Will I get fired? -If you don't know who did it.
Well, I'm finding out now. I'm doing investigations now.
-Was it one of you two? -Yes. Christ, you're good.
-Was it? -No!
I knew it wasn't.
Listen. I'm not going to fire you if you know anything
-because... -You couldn't.
-I could. -How would that work?
I would say, "You're fired. Clear your desk and..."
I would say, "You don't have the authority." But go on.
Not true, not true.
Because in this room, I have special...
-Needs? -No. I am a special...
-Needs child? -No, and that's not funny. All right?
-I won't have you fired because... -You couldn't.
-Right, that's all. -Thank you.
I just can't believe their total lack of respect.
Yeah, yeah. Not only did they undermine you in an authoritive sense...
-(KNOCKING) -Come in, Gareth.
...but they left an image in my mind
of you naked on all fours
being quite literally done doggie-style.
David!
-Carry on. -What is it?
I've found the guilty man.
-Have you indeed, Mr Keenan? -Can this wait, David?
Uh, yeah,
but if I tell you there's pornography, sexist pornography, which I hate,
going round the office, then do you want it to wait?
Pornography?
-Who was it? -Surprise, surprise. It was Tim.
Shame. Good man. How can you be sure?
I found these pictures on his hard drive downloaded from the internet.
After investigation,
licensed by, carried out by...
Oh, no.
Urgh. I don't want you to see this. I don't want to see this. Urgh.
That's worse than the one before.
Oh, I hope there aren't any more. There are more.
Well, he will have to be disciplined
because when the disciplining has to be done,
then the laughter stops for that amount of time, then continues,
rehabilitation notwithstanding.
It's everywhere. Oh.
How did you find out?
Well, I suspected the pictures probably came off the internet,
so I checked everyone's computer.
'Cause there is a log of every web page you've visited.
You just go to Internet Page and then Net History.
-Well, it's not worth it... -It only takes a second.
I don't want to even know how it's done, in a way.
Can you delete the history thing on the computer? We should, really.
-David, this is a meeting. -Yeah, yeah.
Okay. That's all. Anything else?
Um, oh, Taffy phoned from the warehouse.
-He's got another funny video for you. -Thanks.
-This is just one big boys' club! -Not really.
Seedy little men with seedy little jokes.
This morning, perfect example!
I do not want to be put in that position again.
Don't go down the warehouse.
David, don't tell me where I can and can't go in my own company.
-Advice... -You're on very thin ice as it is.
You've already lied to me today. What's that?
You lied to me because you don't have the guts to do your own job.
I don't have the guts?
If you're not man enough to do your job, I will do it for you.
Not man enough?
Okay.
Come here.
Busy at work?
-Is there a problem? -Yeah. That.
-I'm sorry. What's that? -(CHUCKLES) "What's that?"
I don't know. A dirty picture with my head on it, as a sex object.
And don't... You know I like a laugh, Tim. I'm just...
Porno laughs are not funny, okay?
-I'm disappointed. -You think I did this?
Case closed.
Hey, shouldn't I say that? As it was my investigation.
What annoys me is you obviously didn't do it in your own time...
Whoa, whoa. Colombo here figured it out, did he?
Well, yeah, of... I must be guilty if you've got your best man on the case!
Stop trying to be funny for one second, Tim, okay?
And listen, okay? And stop taking advantage of my good nature
'cause I could be like every other boss in this situation.
Okay? Right?
You're taking the piss and I'm getting sick of it.
David, it wasn't me, okay? It was your good friend Chris Finch.
He used my computer.
He said he was your best mate and you'd find it hilarious.
Oh...
No, it is. That was never in question.
I think it's bloody hilarious. You're missing the...
Are you going to apologise to Tim?
I'll tell you about families. You don't have to, in a way.
So...
Are you going to apologise to Tim?
I have, in a way...
-Are you going to apologise now? -Yes!
S... sorry about that.
You weren't involved... You covered for it so well, as well.
You were involved, but you covered, that's what I like.
Well, I really wouldn't want to be here when you bawl out Finchy.
You won't be. It's not fair. Nor will you.
So it's not offensive now it's Chris Finch?
Let's not dwell on whether it is or isn't this or...
Let's stop degrading women, shall we? Please.
Let's have a laugh with them, not at them.
Let's have a laugh at work,
with women, at us.
So I trust you'll be telling Chris Finch he won't be working with us any more?
Yeah, that's a good idea. I'll get rid of a good rep
'cause he played a joke. Brilliant.
-David, don't even start. -No, no, fine.
That's come from the top.
Yeah. Hi, Chris. It's David here. Yeah. Bad news, mate.
We're going to have to let you go. We can't use you any more. No. Yep.
'Cause of the joke.
No, I've got a sense of humour, but that was offensive towards women,
and I can't tolerate that. I'll have to pass on...
...the time sponsored by Accurist will be 4:21
and 40 seconds.
-Pathetic. -Is it?
At the third stroke, the time sponsored by Accurist
will be 4:21 and 50 seconds.
Sorry, has anyone got the right time?
# So what becomes of you, my love
# When they have finally stripped you of
# The handbags and the gladrags
# That your granddad had to sweat
# So you could buy #
Mmm-hmm. Mmm-hmm.