The following programme
contains adult humour
Thank you.
There we go.
Do it properly.
Cheers.
Bill.
(Mick Hucknall.)
(GIGGLES)
This is fun.
It's been a good night so far.
Yeah, it's been really good, yeah.
I'll be honest, when Julie suggested
we get together, I was like, "No!"
I get set up a lot by friends
and it never works out.
Oh, tell me about it. Me too.
You know, I hate dates usually.
They should call dates, "spend
some time with a big, fat loser."
But this has been brilliant.
Hey, um, I was thinking afterwards,
maybe you'd like to come
back to my place. We could listen
to the new Jamie Cullum album.
Maybe, yeah. Yeah, yeah... That
would be really nice actually.
Great.
Let me guess, um,
you're a red wine person.
Yes, yes, I am.
Oh, I would be too if we could
get some service round here!
Yeah, you, Hucknall,
when you're simply red-y.
Unbelievable!
Oh, I should say,
I don't really like sharing, so you
get what you want, I'll get what
I want, we'll leave it at that.
I just think it's less confusing.
Sure, sure. Did you say Jamie Cullum?
Yeah. Yeah, I hate Jamie Cullum.
"Oh, and just to say,
"I don't really like sharing," with
the rising inflection and everything.
In a tapas restaurant,
he doesn't like sharing!
What the heck is tapas?
You know tapas, tiny food from Spain.
Oh, yes, tape-as?
That's not how you say it.
Yes, it is.
You're a tape-as.
What else? What else?
What else? Oh, God, you should have
seen him with the waiters.
Rude?
Unbelievable.
I used to work as a waiter.
If anyone was ever rude to me,
I used to carry
their food around in my trousers.
Oh, my God, before you
brought it to their table?
No, after.
Of course before!
Why would I do it after?
Well, do you think
they did that to him?
OK, well, while he was eating,
did you hear anyone laughing,
like in the kitchen area?
Yes! Yes, I did actually. Yes, I did.
That will be trouser food!
Oh, God!
Probably a good thing
you weren't sharing.
Oh, my God!
I could have saved you the trouble.
That guy is famous, he's a mouth.
They call him The News because
he's talks about who he slept with.
I would honestly rather
sleep with a rat, literally.
The thing I can't understand yeah,
this, this is a man Julie on fifth
thinks is perfect for me.
I mean, what was she thinking?
Wait, who do you know on fifth?
Why?
Judy or Julie?
Why do you need to know?
No reason.
Lots of nice looking girls on fifth.
Looking for an in, are we?
An in? No, thank you. No.
Don't use my name to start leching
around on fifth.
For your information,
I do not lech.
I have a little more class
than that, thank you very much.
Post!
Thank you. Oh, no, this is a wrong -
a lingerie catalogue for
a Cathy Morganforman.
I'll make sure that Cathy gets it.
Who is Cathy Morganforman?
Who's Cathy Morganforman?
Cathy works in, Cathy, Cathy works
in the department of...Shaloopest.
Department of what?
Oh, that's my phone ringing.
I didn't hear anything.
It's on vibrate. Hello?
Hello, Cathy,
yes, your parcel did arrive.
I'm keeping it here safe for you. No
problem at all, Cathy Morganforman.
If he comes by...
If who comes by?
The News.
Yes, right.
If he calls, just tell him something.
Leave it with me. Great.
I should say I'm not good at lying.
I'm very good at lying.
I thought you were on the phone.
Yeah, I am. Yes...
MOBILE RINGS
Hello?
Listen, Moss, you're
not going to court, yeah?
Just tell him something.
It's just I've never been very good
at judging the scale of the lie...
Yes, stop over-thinking. You're
getting yourself into a tizz.
I was never able to do it as a
child and I told a whopper...
Just tell him I'm busy!
You're busy.
That's brilliant.
Just don't let him in here under any
circumstances. No. You're busy.
What was the name of that girl that
Jen knows? Was it Julie or Judy?
Yes, one of those.
OK, I'm just going to go
for a lech on fifth.
Yes.
Look, I told you, she's busy.
Hey, back off, buster,
this lady's busy.
Too busy for you.
Busy!
Brilliant!
Hello.
I'm just looking for Jen.
I'm afraid Jen can't see you
at the moment, she's very busy.
Is she? She's a busy
Miss Lizzie. Goodbye.
What's she doing?
She's doing fine.
Not how's she doing?
What's she doing? Er, er...
Is she in here? No.
I'm just going to give her these.
I just want to give her these.
She won't like them. She won't mind.
She will mind.
It's not a problem, I won't take
any time. Look, why can't I go in?
Because she's dead!
What?
Yeah she's dead. She, she died.
She died last night.
She died?
Yeah.
Completely.
Oh, God!
I just can't believe it.
Well, I'd hardly make up
something like that!
No, of course, of course not.
Oh, God!
Well, she was a bit off
at the restaurant.
I mean, was it the food?
The tapas, do they know?
Tape-as. I don't know.
Yes, it was. Why not? Yeah.
Oh, Jesus.
Oh, I know it's terrible,
but thank God we weren't sharing.
I just can't get over it.
Yeah, well,
we all have to go sometime.
It's terrible, it's just terrible.
It's bloody awful.
She was so beautiful.
She was some piece of ass.
Anyhoo, can't mourn
all the ruddy day so...
You know...
..I was the last person
to sleep with her.
Really? She said that...
What?
She said she was looking forward
to sleeping with you.
(WHISTLES CHEERILY)
I can't believe he lied like that.
Doesn't he realise that lying can
lead to very serious ramifications?
THREE DRAMATIC CHORDS
Hello?
Hello.
I'm Roy.
IT.
My boss has assigned me
to take on any work that
you might want done personally.
Personally...
Basically, if you want to,
just take my card.
And...
If you need anything done
to your computer,
just give me a buzz on
the phone, my mobile phone.
You won't have to go through
all that call-waiting palaver.
OK, thank you, Roy.
You're welcome, Judy.
Oh, I'm not Judy, I'm Julie. Judy?
Someone to see you.
This man says you're
to take his card!
The girl from IT, that's terrible.
I know, terrible, terrible thing.
I was actually the
last person to sleep with her.
Very sudden, yes.
I hear it was some bad tapas.
Tape-as. Yes. You must be stunned.
I'm flabbergasted.
You know where we are if you need us.
Sure. I... I'll be fine, thanks.
Just sort of stay away
from this whole area,
while we come to terms
with the loss.
Leave me now. I would be alone.
Oh, God!
Oh!
Good lech?
No!
The girl. Oh, my God.
The girl, Judy, she's, um,
have you seen this girl?
What's she like?
Well, she has hair on her eyes.
Who has hair on her eyes? Not you.
No.
I'm going for a coffee.
Anyone want anything? No?
OK, bye.
MOBILE RINGS
Hello.
'Hello!'
Oh, hello, Judy.
What can I do for you?
Computer's broken.
Is it a PC or a Mac?
'Yes.'
Well, what's wrong with it?
Broken down.
Yeah, broken down how, Judy?
Bing bong noise. Bing bong noise!
What's the precise nature
of the problem?
E-mail.
Judy, the battery on my phone is...
PHONE BEEPS
(SHUDDERS)
Look at this.
What? How nice is this?
I just got a big load of flowers
and a big card
and everyone has signed it.
"You will always be in our hearts."
My God, and you said
they weren't nice here.
Yeah.
I don't understand
why they've done this.
Why? I'll tell you for why.
It's because everyone
thinks you're brilliant.
Really?
In fact, everyone thinks
you're so brilliant
they've just made you
employee of the month.
No! Yes.
No! Yes. No!
Ya-ha. I don't believe it.
Please believe it.
Oh, my God,
I didn't even know they had
employee of the month here.
No, they brought it in
just for you.
Wow. I'm going to go up
and thank everybody right now.
No, don't do that.
What? Why not?
They'll be embarrassed.
It's embarrassing being thanked.
Don't be silly.
Events seem to be taking
a downward turn.
THREE DRAMATIC CHORDS
I told you,
stop calling me at work!
Oh, it's the beautiful Jen.
Hello, Small Paul.
Didn't I hear... I thought
you were sick or something.
Sick? Me? No. I couldn't be better.
I've just won Employee of the Month.
So you going my way?
Don't you dare go too fast. No! No!
(YELLS)
Just hard to get your head round,
you know?
One minute she's there and
the next minute she's gone.
You know I was the last person
that slept with her actually.
She held on so tightly, you know?
It was like, it was scary, but sexy,
scary, you know? It was like...
Ahhhhhh!
Aah!
Jen?
What are you still doing here,
Bill? For God's sake go home.
He was the last person
to sleep with her.
I know. Apparently
she was pretty hot stuff.
Bye, Small Paul.
Bye, Jen, see you.
(PANTS)
Oh, oh, dear oh, Lord.
Oh.
THUD!
At this dreadful hour,
we're all reminded how brief
our time is here on Earth.
Sorry, who was it who died?
I don't know.
I believe Mr Reynholm
has a few words.
There's one more angel in heaven.
God, I miss Jen.
She reminded me of me at her age.
I mean, when I was her age,
she reminded me of her age.
She reminded me of my age at her age.
When I was her age,
she was reminded of me?
I grew to like Jen
and that enlikening of
her became a friendship.
A friendship which ended
so suddenly, just 12 hours ago,
after what I gather was a
sensational evening with Bill Crouse.
Bill! You dog!
Where is he?
Still cleaning himself off.
She was special,
so special in fact that when
I called my close personal friend
Elton John and told him about her,
he dropped everything and offered
to come here and perform for us.
You heard me, he's in the building.
Elton John is going to sing
a beautiful song about death.
APPLAUSE
Oh, my God, this is so, so lovely.
Thank you so, so much.
Thank you, thank you.
Oh, God.
Can I say a few words?
Oh, my God.
Thank you so, so much.
I would, I would not be standing
up here today if it wasn't
for so many people, not least Dad,
without him...
Hey, she isn't dead.
Yeah.
ALL BOO
You lying cow!
We want Elton.
(CHANTING) We want Elton.
We want Elton. We want Elton.
If that Judy woman comes
down, I don't work here,
you've never seen me - just make
up something, just get rid of her.
She's easy to spot,
she has three rows of teeth.
Listen, if I needed to get out
of the country very, very cheaply,
how would I go about doing that?
Hiya.
What did you say about me?
Hello there, Jen.
I would love to stay and chat but
I've just received a telephone call
saying my father has just killed
someone which I need to attend to.
Did you tell everyone I was dead?
Maybe.
Because they all thought I was dead.
Argh!
Don't hurt me, I know something!
What? What do you know?
Bill Crouse, he's saying you
slept with him last night.
He's saying what?
He thinks you're dead, he's
telling everybody you slept with him.
He's the one you should
be angry at, not me.
Bastard.
(PANTS)
Voicemail.
(COUGHS)
(STRANGLED VOICE) Hey, it's Jen.
Stop telling everyone
I slept with you. You bastard!
Must have gone home.
Oh, God, my throat hurts.
Well, it's probably all
that shouting.
I'm talking, aren't I?
Can you get me his address?
It might be a bit difficult, I have
to hack into his private company
account. It might take some time.
There we go.
Oh, oh, I really
don't feel very well.
Well, you look terrible.
I'm still talking, aren't I?
You have one new message.
(STRANGLED VOICE) 'Hey, it's Jen.
'Stop telling people I
slept with you.
'You bastard!'
Argh!
Where Roy?
Roy's dead.
Aaaaah!
(WHISTLES CHEERILY)
No, don't break down.
Don't break down.
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Bloody hell.
I don't know what any of this does.
Oh, my God, it's bloody hopeless.
I don't know what any of it means.
Oh, come on, come on.
Ritchley Street.
Ah!
Oh, my God. OK, right.
It's probably guys, leaving a
message, funny message, probably Bob.
It's Bob leaving funny messages
and a floating head.
You're stressed, a bit stressed.
It's all just fun and games.
(SHRIEKS)
Oh, God!
Let me in. Let me in, Bill!
No!
It's raining! Please let me in.
Oh, God you're never coming in.
Stop telling people
I slept with you.
I will, I will, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
You bastard!
I'm sorry!
(WAILS)
# Small Paul, you're gone now
# You pushed that trolley
a little too hard
# You felt a twinge,
it was your heart
# And you're dead now
# And though you were only 4ft 11
# There's no height
restrictions... #
Did you know him?
No.
# You're no longer around... #
I don't think that's Elton John.
# We're all the same height
When we're lying down. #
Subtitles by Red Bee Media Ltd