This programme contains strong
language and adult humour
MAGICAL SPARKLY MUSIC
(TV)
'Has this ever happened to you?
Oh!
'From today, dialling 999 won't
get you the emergency services.
'And that's not the only
thing that's changing.
'Nicer ambulances, faster
response times and better looking
'drivers mean they're not just
'the emergency services,
they're your emergency services.
'So, remember the new number.
'That's...'
'Hello.
'I've had a bit of a tumble.'
Well, that's easy to remember.
# 0118 999 881...
# ..999 119 725...
# ..three. #
I don't know why they changed it.
How hard is it to remember 911?
You mean 999.
I mean 999.
That's the American one.
Yeah.
You berk!
Come on. Are you ready?
It's fine,
there are so many shoes.
They are beautiful. I love them.
They're the most beautiful
shoes I've ever seen.
I can't have everything that
I love, otherwise I'd own lots.
They're red, which is quite tarty,
and they don't necessarily go with
any of my outfits. Although...
Sssh...
Come on, you crazy bitch. Come on.
Come on. Denholm's called a general.
Oh, God, another one?
Yeah.
I bet he declares war on something.
He loves declaring war.
I am declaring war!
I can see that got your attention.
What am I declaring war on?
My bollocks?
ALL GUFFAW
Stress!
Stress is a disease, people,
and I am the cure.
I'm a doctor with a cure.
No, I'm not.
I'm a general and it's still
a war - a war on disease. Stress!
There's too much stress around here.
(THINKING) 'They're expensive
and the woman in the shop
'said they're too small for me
so, you know, be practical.'
While I've been speaking, over 80
million people have died of stress.
SMASHING GLASS >
That's another one.
More.
Mayhem!
We've gotta deal with it.
Are you ready to deal with it?
Yeah!
Say, "I hate stress".
I hate stress.
No, you didn't let me finish.
Say, I hate stress, and I want to
limit it's influence in my life.
What can I do about it? Anyone?
Have a bath?
Have a bath? Get a bike!
I cycle to work every day.
70 miles.
Both here...and here
are as red as a fire engine.
Any other ideas?
Jen, what about you?
Shoes.
What?
Shoes. What? Shoes...
OK, look.
I have invited Dr Julian Holmes to
come and give a class at lunchtime.
He is Europe's
leading stress expert.
They call them "stressperts".
Anyone interested in
picking up a few tips
on how to manage...STRESS!
There's a free buffet.
Good.
Good people.
Oh, by the way,
anyone still experiencing
stress at the end of the day
WILL BE FIRED!
It's not going on.
Just angle it a bit more.
Are you sure you're a five?
Well, I'm not a liar.
Yeah, but I mean, I can't...
(WHIMPERS)
I can feel the heel going in.
Just angle it a bit more.
There is no angle that I could...
Don't let me push you away.
Lean in with the shoe!
BOTH GRUNT
BOTH PANT
We have been here for half an hour.
The shoes aren't going on.
They are two sizes too small
and, even if they did go on,
they would cripple ya.
You don't want that, do ya?
(BREATHES RAGGEDLY)
Now, I, myself, have been subject
to some terrible rages.
KNOCKING
Yes?
I'm sorry. Is this stress class?
Oh, yeah. Come on in.
Moss!
Stress is in here!
Just come on in.
(Sorry.)
Um, sorry.
Thank you.
Thank you. Just...
That's OK.
(SHRIEKS)
Are you all right?
Um, as I was saying,
I have been subject to some
terrible rages where I've snapped
at my wife, or spoken harshly to
a work colleague because of stress.
In fact, just thinking about it now,
I realise I'm raising my voice.
So, I'm sorry.
Stress is the main cause
of heart attacks.
And, even a little bit - well...
..let me show you
what stress can do.
I'm gonna need a volunteer.
Yes, come on up.
APPLAUSE
Can I have your left hand
there? Sit back.
Now, just relax.
I'm going to ask you
a very personal question.
There we are, you see.
It's all right.
I'm not going to at all.
That's just to show how little
is needed to send
our stress levels shooting up.
Just a simple statement like
that has registered strongly
on the display.
Yes, another volunteer?
Yeah.
OK, I'll just take this off.
I'm going to kill you!
Very good. Yes! Right up.
Look at that. Brilliant.
Excellent. It's a super machine.
Wow! Great shoes.
(GASPING) Thank you very much.
I envy women with dainty feet.
What are you - a five?
Yes. Five.
Just a little misunderstanding
there, I imagine, so let's move on.
Whoa. I haven't had a proper go yet.
I don't think that that should
count, what happened there.
I don't think that's fair.
I would like a go
and Roy should be punished
for nearly killing that lady.
We'll move on.
I think I should go first.
OK, let's move on.
When did you grow your beard?
We're going to move on.
Is it very accurate?
Just one little go.
Are you very old?
(SHOUTS) Let's move on!
(SOBS)
Oh, shut up!
What are you eating?
Muffin.
A muffin! How can you be hungry?
You ate a whole chicken
at the stress buffet.
What's that?
I've made a stress machine
to try out on myself
like the one in that class.
Watch this.
I'm going to ask myself
a very personal question.
Don't worry. I'm not really
going to ask myself any questions.
Good. It's not as good as
the one in the stress class.
The shoes-a!
DOOR SLAMS >
What was all that about?
Like all women, she's shoe mad.
That's a bit sexist, isn't it?
Do you know one woman who
isn't obsessed with shoes?
No. But I only know one woman.
And she just left the room
shouting, "The shoes-a!"
(SHRIEKS)
(GASPS)
(SCREAMS)
The needle's freaking out!
Try not to hurt yourself.
Moss?
Yeah.
Did you use a soldering iron
to make that stress machine?
Yes.
You turned it off?
Oh, I'm fairly sure I did.
Because, you remember what
happened last time, right?
Yes, that was very funny.
Well, no.
It was very dangerous
and someone nearly died.
Right, no, yeah. I'm thinking
of a different incident -
the one on the golf course.
What?
I'm talking about the fire!
Oh, yeah, fire - sorry. I always
get mixed up between golf and fire.
Just make sure it's off.
It is off, I think.
Well, just make sure it is.
I will make sure it is.
And if it's already off...
I'll just walk away.
Get off my back. What is he -
the soldering iron police!
It's off.
That means I turn it on...
..and just walk away.
FIRE CRACKLES
Oh, four!
I mean, five! I mean, fire!
Now, let's see what we have here.
"Stand upright."
Now I can't read it.
Oh, not me.
I am a giddy goat!
OK. "Remove safety clip."
Don't look at my feet!
Fire. Fire? No?
"Aim nozzle at base of fire."
Oh, that is typical!
Why has it done that?
I'll just put this over here
with the rest of the fire.
01153...no.
011...no.
0118 999...3.
Hello,
is this the emergency services?
Then which country
am I speaking to?
Hello? Hello?
I know.
OK.
Subject: "Fire".
"Dear Sir/Madam, I'm writing
"to inform you of a fire which has
broken out at the premises of..."
No, that's too formal.
"Dear Sir/Madam.
"Fire! Fire! Help me!
"123, Carenden Road.
"Looking forward to
hearing from you,
"All the best, Maurice Moss."
What are you wearing size five shoes
for, woman? You're at least an eight.
Eight?! How dare you?!
That foot is completely mangled.
And the other one's even worse.
You're not wearing these again.
But I threw away my other shoes.
What am I supposed to wear?
Hello? Hello! Do you remember me?
Can I have a go on
your machine now?
Hello again!
Oh, hi.
Please thank Haiamusa San for
this fine ceremonial sword.
It is a magnificent symbol
of our new merger.
(SPEAKS JAPANESE)
I am sorry that my gift,
a huge pair of Doc Martens
with thick and heavy soles,
is so paltry in comparison.
(SPEAKS JAPANESE)
Rest assured that my
cultural advisor will be fired
as soon as this meeting is over.
(SPEAKS JAPANESE)
These are very heavy shoes.
It feels like Godzilla.
Does he? Godzilla!
Go on, stamp your feet!
Clap him, man! Good!
The Jap loves it!
Go on, break something!
Put your weight into it!
(SCREAMS)
You (BLEEP) idiot!
What are you doing?
You stupid little (BLEEP)!
You (BLEEP) (BLEEP)! You think
you're a big man (BLEEP) shoes!
Well, you're not! You're
nothing but a (BLEEP) (BLEEP)!
(SPEAKS JAPANESE)
I am so sorry, Denholm.
That was quite a tirade, Jen.
It would have been even
worse if Paul hadn't been so
quick on the profanity buzzer.
Well done, Paul,
you're back on the payroll.
As for you, you fucked up.
BLEEP!
Shouting at Japs, mad feet -
both classic signs of stress.
And you know how I feel about stress.
Go to your office and wait for me.
The weirdest thing just happened...
Fire! Fire!
I've sent an e-mail, it's fine.
An e-mail?! It's a fire!
Where's the big-stinguisher?
Made in Britain.
This is just like the golf incident!
You mean the fire incident?
Of course I mean the fire incident!
What have you got there?
Oh, I'm in trouble.
Help me get my shoes on!
Help me get my shoes
on before Denholm comes.
Denholm's coming?!
Yeah, and he's going to fire...
Fire, fire!
I've taken care of it.
I have to say I feel
a little bit insulted
by the lack of faith
you're both displaying.
What happened to your feet?!
What is this?
I think a fire in the
office demands a little more
attention than my feet, don't you?!
How did you get the
stress machine, Roy?
Don't really know.
Met Dr Holmes by the lifts.
Wasn't he nice?
I thought he was a lovely man.
Yeah, I thought he was a delight.
But I met him there by the
lifts and he just went mental!
Ah-ha...
And one thing led to
another and I just stole it.
You stole it?
Yeah!
But that's stealing!
Yeah. Didn't know what a
stress machine was this morning
and now we have two.
I hate to remind everyone
but I just destroyed a merger
that probably took
hundreds of years to set up,
the office is on fire, Denholm is
furious, so could we please
concentrate on what's important
and help me on with my shoes?!
We're going to get into trouble!
Empty!
Got a little bit there.
No, these are a size five.
What are you, eight and a half?!
Shut up.
Come on.
I'm pushing!
Push it on, don't pull away.
Is it in?!
Come on, push it on. Go on! Woah!
Aaagh! The heel went right through.
Oh my god, it hurts so much!
Oh, God! Oh, now I'm bleeding!
It's Denholm!
What?!
Hide the stress machine!
The stress machine?
What about the fire?!
OK, put the stress machine in Jen's
room. He'll never go in there.
But what if he does?
It doesn't matter,
he won't know what it is!
I can't go to prison, Roy.
They'll rape the flip out of me.
You stall him by the door.
How?
I don't know, use your womanly ways!
Moss, pass me that
monitor, the broken one.
There you are.
Hello, there.
It's no use being
womanly with me, Jen.
You're in big trouble.
Nice screensaver.
Thank you.
A-ha! A stress machine!
Just what we need.
Roll up your sleeves, Jen.
Let's get this over with.
It's a one way ticket to
Slammer Town for us, Roy,
with no return ticket.
I really am losing
quite a lot of blood.
This is your last chance.
If the needle goes beyond here
you will be fired.
Does that make you feel stressed?
Jen! Does it? No? Are you sure?
Are you sure? Are you sure?
Are you sure?
I'll level with you, Roy.
I don't think I'd flourish
in a prison environment.
Can I try on your glasses?!
See this balloon, Jen?
I'm going to burst it.
But I'm not going to tell you when.
Do you feel stressed, Jen? Jen?
Jen? Look at that.
That's your peace of mind
and it's going to go bang.
Do you feel stressed now?
Jen? Jen? Jen?
Jen? Jen? Jen? Do you?
Evidently not.
Well done, Jen.
You're not being fired by me
at this precise moment.
I love the way the smoke seems
to be coming off the top of it.
Just a second...
I'm late for golf!
I wonder why it didn't work.
Ah!
I don't know if
it's the loss of blood
or the melting plastic from
the monitor, but I feel great!
It's ironic, but this entire
situation has been quite stressful.
I'll get help.
Did someone e-mail us about a fire?
Subtitles by
Red Bee Media Ltd