And every other day, I take
a short helicopter ride
to Heston Blumenthal's restaurant.
Last night,
I ate a chocolate radio
that still worked in my stomach,
and a flat chicken
that was actually a glass of water.
Even the menu was edible.
They said it wasn't, but I ate it.
Sounds like
you're living the life of Riley.
Well, I actually knew Riley,
and yes, there are similarities.
And yet, there is some sadness in
your life. Tell me about Victoria.
You'll have to forgive me,
there's been quite a few Victorias.
Your wife?
Oh!
My God, my wife, oh yes, Victoria!
What a fantastic woman. The two weeks
we were married were unforgettable.
She disappeared in mysterious
circumstances, did she not?
She vanished while washing the car.
Despite a search that lasted nearly
five hours, we found nothing.
So naturally, we assumed the worst.
You must miss her.
(TREMULOUS VOICE)
More than words could say.
I'd give anything to see her
walk through that door right now.
Hey, why don't you
take your clothes off?
What?
Come on, we both knew it was on
the cards as soon as I realised you
were a woman!
What if someone were to walk in?
I left strict instructions not to
be disturbed in case we had sex.
There's no way anyone is
walking through that door...
Hello, Douglas.
Victoria!
But I thought you were dead!
I must say, Douglas, you still
don't seem very pleased to see me.
No, no, I must have eaten
some bad stereo system.
How's the wine?
Exquisite.
From the chef's own cellar.
What are you doing, Victoria? Last
time I saw you, you were...
Washing the car? Yes, I imagine
you have many questions.
I was under a lot of stress that
day, Douglas. I think we both were.
We both knew it wasn't working.
I picked up my sponge and bucket
with a heavy heart that day.
The rest is a blank. The next thing
I can remember with any clarity
is being on a kayaking holiday
two years later.
That looks good, what's that?
I sort of wish I'd ordered that.
Our invisible desserts have arrived!
I know we weren't happy that second
week of our marriage, Douglas,
but give us another chance,
as a couple.
I don't know.
I don't think we can just pick up
from where we left off.
No, Victoria, I'm sorry, it's over.
UNZIPPING
Oh God!
I forgot you could do that.
Maybe we should give it another go!
Nnngh...
Well that is new!
How are you doing that?
That might be the dog.
Heston!
I'd like to introduce you to my...
wi-i-i-ife.
I want to divorce my wife.
Why are you telling me?
Aren't you with legal?
No.
Remind me?
IT. Relationship manager.
Ah. Well then I probably
shouldn't have told you any of that.
Anyway...
I want to divorce her right now.
Now's too late. Before now.
In fact, I want to have already
divorced her, is that possible?
Well, as I said,
I'm not a lawyer, so...
Yes, but you're a relationship
manager, and this is a relationship!
Well, erm...
have you told her yet?
Kind of. I changed my Friendface
profile from "married"
to "it's complicated".
That's not the same as
telling her, Mr Reynholm.
Yeah, but someone will pass it on.
Why not you?
No!
Oh come on! Please break up with
my vanishing, car cleaning wife!
I don't want to do it!
I'll give you...I don't know...
Who are you again?
I'm Jen Barber.
I'm with the IT department
at Reynholm Industries.
Sorry, I thought
I was meeting my husband.
Er...Mr Reynholm asked me to
convey a, um, a message to you.
Mrs Reynholm.
How long have you and Mr Reynholm
known each other?
About ten years.
Ten years, ten wonderful years.
Who are you?
Mrs Reynholm...
Can I call you Victoria?
No.
Mrs Reynholm.
Sometimes there is a day and
then there is a night.
Sometimes there is a morn,
and then there is an eve.
Flowers grow, trees are cut down,
babies are born, but, erm...
lawyers exist.
What are you trying to say?
Oh, I can't do it, I just can't.
Let me guess. My husband wants
to leave me
and he paid you a large amount of
money to spare him the embarrassment
of facing me.
Yes, but I'm not going to
take the money... I feel sick.
Of course you do,
you're a normal person.
You're not upset?
No, because I'm not a normal person.
You see, what you're
trying to do here but can't -
if the tables were turned,
I wouldn't find it difficult at all.
In fact, it's how I
met his first wife.
I didn't know these were edible too.
They're not.
What's all that?
I have to spend the afternoon
with Douglas.
Somehow I've been drafted
into his legal eagle fantasy.
Have you ever spent
any serious time with that man?
He's unbelievable! You should
hear the way he talks about women.
Oh yeah, he's some piece of work.
He's like a sexy Hitler.
I mean, I don't expect to
put on a pedal stool,
but please, show a little respect!
I'm sorry,
you don't expect to be put on a what?
On a pedal stool.
A pedal stool?
What's a pedal stool?
Oh, you know, you put women on it
when you admire them,
you know, the phrase.
Oh yeah, the famous phrase,
"to be put on a pedal stool".
"Pedestal"!
What?
"Pedestal" is the word!
What's a "pedal stool"?!
Did you really think there was
such a thing as a pedal stool?
Shut up, everyone has blind spots.
Can you help me sort through
all this legal crap, please, Moss?
I'd rather not. I've not had good
experiences with the legal system.
How come?
Well, when I was 11, I broke the
patio window, and my mother sued me.
She sued you?
Yeah, to teach me a lesson.
She's always been a very
aggressive litigator.
Can you even do that,
can you sue your children?
It was kind of a show trial
in the kitchen.
She made a little gallery
for the cat.
Aw-w... What happened?
She won.
I'm still paying costs.
(CHUCKLES) "Pedal stool"!
212 million quid!
You can't be serious!
Oh, we're quite
serious, Mr Reynholm.
But that's enough to bring
Reynholm Industries to its knees!
Bloody blast, this is up my arse!
That is the amount,
it is not up for negotiation.
Balls from hell, you shit-twins!
Calm down, Mr Reynholm.
Bollocks to be telling me
to calm down, my old chap.
She wants 220 titty million quid and
you tell me to calm down!
You're fired.
I'm not your lawyer.
Piss off!
I'm going to represent myself.
I'm not your lawyer.
You sit there, all confident.
Yeah? But when this goes to Court,
that's when the talking stops.
Mr Reynholm,
there might actually be more talking
in Court,
this would actually be a
comparatively small amount of
talking, what we're doing here.
Oh, I see.
Sorry.
No, that's all right,
it's what I pay you for.
Look at her. Cold as ice.
But I tell you this -
behind those shades, she's terrified.
(SNORES)
One thing you should know about me,
Jen -
when I put my mind to something,
it gets done.
Representing myself is the kind
of challenge I relish.
Well, you'll have to do
a lot of preparation.
Bring it on!
GLASS SMASHES
Er... What's this?
It's my suit.
I made it myself. Took me a few days!
How did you find time
to prepare for the trial?
How did I what?
Mrs Reynholm, you say that in the
short time you were married,
you became
indispensable to Mr Reynholm -
in what way were you indispensable?
I had to brush his teeth.
Really?
Yes.
That's not an expression?
No.
You got the brush,
you applied toothpaste to it,
you moved it into his mouth...
and moved your hand up and down.
Well, if I didn't do it,
he wouldn't do it.
Make a note - "brush teeth".
Now, you're asking
for quite a large amount.
I think it is an appropriate amount.
Bollocks.
Mr Reynholm.
Yes, your honour?
I would ask you
to refrain from using that kind of
language in my courtroom.
And which word in particular
do you object to, your honour?
You only said one.
Could you read it back?
"Bollocks".
Don't read it back!
Why do you say
it is an appropriate amount?
Mr Reynholm caused
me great distress.
I'm entitled to some restitution.
Besides, it's not as if he
ever put the money to good use.
As the film proves.
Your honour, may I present the
central exhibit to our case -
it is, I'm afraid, a sex tape.
A sex tape?
Which one?
The alien craft appears
to have dropped its shields.
Thank you, Female Chekhov! Female
Sulu, beam their Captain aboard.
But... Captain...are you sure?
But she's hurt,
she may need our help.
Jim, even if she's injured as you
say, I can't do an examination
on a new species
without proper research.
Dammit, Jim, I'm a sexy doctor,
not a sexy scientist!
Female Sulu. You have your orders.
Perhaps the good doctor thinks
certain alien species do not
fall under the Hippocratic oath.
I have never refused treatment
to a patient, Female Spock,
and you know that!
I think we've seen enough.
Your Honour, I object!
There's a brilliant bit coming up.
Mr Reynholm,
are you ready to start your
cross-examination of Mrs Reynholm?
I am, your Honour, but rest assured,
it will be a normal examination.
I am not in any way cross.
You are Victoria Reynholm,
are you not?
Mr Reynholm,
we have already established that.
Might I suggest
that you try less to do
an impression of a lawyer
you once saw on the television
and make your case
as simply as you possibly can.
Wise words, my learned lud.
Victoria, you've spoken
about the real me,
and I think it's time we heard
a little about the real you.
Isn't it true, that you...
Used to be a man?
No.
It isn't true, you say?
It is untrue.
Who am I thinking of?
I think you mean April,
the woman you had a fight with.
No further questions, my lud.
What?
Your entire case rested on that?
Yes, your Honour.
No, wait, Mr Reynholm,
you can't leave it at that.
Your Honour, may I confer with
my relationship manager?
What's up, Jen?
You've got to request more time
to prepare a proper defence.
Your Grace,
may I approach the bench?
Have you brushed your teeth?
No.
Then you may not.
Your Grace,
I need to prepare a proper defence.
The one I just did there
was rubbish.
Yes, he's some piece of work.
We're all very happy
at Reynholm Industries.
Are you telling the truth?
Yes.
Then why are you so ill-at-ease?
Well...
If you must know... I was in
a court myself very recently...
This very courtroom in fact,
where I gave testimony
against a former soldier who...
I was having a massage and he kissed
me on my bottom, Your Honour.
I see.
I'm sure you can
understand my discomfort.
Are you all right? Can you continue?
I can continue. Thank you.
The way you tell it, your employer
sounds like a paragon of virtue.
That's right.
And furthermore, I would like
to say at this point that I think
this whole case to be a damp squid.
Thank you, no further questions.
Oooh! I have one more question,
your Honour.
Yes?
What did you say?
What?
What did you say the case was?
May I have it read back please?
"I believe this entire case
to be a bit of a damp squid."
"A damp squid?"
What does that mean?
Oh, Jen, it's an expression.
It means that I believe
that everything that's been said
in this case, everyone already knew.
Mmmm, yes,
but did you say "damp squid"?
That's right.
Did you not mean, "damp squib"?
No, it's "squid".
What's a squib?
It's not "squid".
Squids are already damp!
Hence the phrase!
Your Honour! Please!
It is "squib".
I must say, I find it extraordinary
that you, a man in your early 30s,
could have reached this point
in your life without knowing
that it is "squib".
I think it's "squid".
I have no further questions.
No, no, no, wait, wait, wait!
That will be all.
Everyone has a blind spot!
I said that will be all!
Your name is Maurice Moss,
is it not?
Ehm...
Your name is Maurice Moss,
is it not?
Sorry, bit nervous... So... Yeah...
Fizzy! It's very fizzy.
It's fizzy. Gone fizzy.
FZZZT!
Ow, come on!
That's electric.
That's electric in there.
Just got a shock.
Your name is Maurice Moss,
is it not?
It is not.
Sorry, yeah, sorry, sorry.
My mother sued me.
Relax. Take your time.
Try to answer the questions
as clearly as you can.
Thank you, my love.
Your name is Maurice Moss,
is it not?
Chair. It was the chair's fault.
No further questions, my lud.
Don't you have anything?
She's going to take you
to the cleaners, Mr Reynholm.
Yup, I suppose she will.
What's that?
Oh, God.
I think I may have
found our miracle.
Can you state your full name,
please?
Richmond Felicity Avenal.
And you worked at
Reynholm Industries for a time?
I did, for over four years.
And what did you do?
I don't know.
Why did you leave?
Well, my life wasn't really going
anywhere. I was part of the whole
goth/ death metal subculture
but it wasn't making me happy.
It was all a bit gloomy.
It was round about that point
that I developed scurvy.
Now that sounds unpleasant.
On the contrary.
Catching scurvy was the best thing
that ever happened to me.
It made me take a long hard look
in the mirror.
And I didn't like what I saw,
I can tell you that.
Not just because my teeth
had fallen out.
Which is why I founded
From Goth2Boss.
Is it OK if I play a DVD?
Does it have anything whatsoever
to do with this case?
Not really, Your Honour.
Then you may proceed.
Where are you going?
Is it to the top?
If not, why not?
Go to the bloody top!
Is it because you're a goth?
Did you know that goths have some of
the lowest life satisfaction levels
of any subculture with the exception
of traffic wardens?
That's why you don't see
any goth traffic wardens.
That would be a deadly combination!
We at Goth2Boss work with goths at
various locations around the UK
to bring out
their hidden potential...
by encouraging them to engage in
everyday, healthy pursuits
such as sports.
Mixing with other humans.
Extended laughter sessions.
Introducing colour to your wardrobe.
Just look at these results.
This is Debbie. She used to
hang around railway stations
with her hands in her sleeves.
Now she's a lifeguard in Mumbai!
From Goth2Boss, you know it makes
sense. Unless you're not a goth,
in which case, from Goth2Boss.
Remember the name.
But what does that have to do with
my divorce proceedings,
m'kind fellow?
Well, Mr Reynholm,
I'm here to tell you that that woman
is not Victoria Reynholm!
Her name is Melanie Crawford,
a former From Goth2Boss pupil
of mine!
Sing, you canary!
Well, during our sessions,
she seemed more interested
in you than getting better.
I don't think she ever
truly exorcised the goth within.
Scratch away that fake tan
and beneath you'll find
the purest white foundation!
Yeah, that was more of a phrase
than anything.
Oh, actually, um...
No sorry, that's not her!
Oh, sorry about that. That's not her.
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury.
You've heard a few things over the
past few days, none of which cast me
in a particularly favourable light.
Stories of expensive sex tapes,
rumours of me killing my first wife.
No. No-one's mentioned that.
You know, there's one thing
I do want to say.
Just one thing, that I...
Mr Reynholm?
Mr Reynholm, please.
Mr Reynholm, this really is the most
pathetic display I have ever seen.
May I say something, your Honour?
Why not?
Lying here,
pretending to have a heart attack,
you see a desperate man.
Not pretending.
A man who has exhausted all of
his time, all of his resources,
on an expensive trial
that has resulted in humiliation.
But think not of him. Think of the
employees of Reynholm Industries.
Think of the man
who was sued by his mother.
The simpleton who thought the phrase
"damp squid" was correct.
These are the people I want you to
consider when making your judgement.
For Reynholm is not just
the name of this ridiculous man
who keeps opening his eyes
whenever he thinks no-one's looking.
Reynholm
is the name of the family his
employees have found in each other.
We are all Reynholms.
Hurt him, and you hurt...
Oh, all right then,
we'll take 70 million.
Hooray!
I'm getting oak.
Subtitles by
Red Bee Media Ltd