APPLAUSE AND CHEERING
Hello, welcome to Top Gear
where tonight it's time to slip on
the old Lederhosen,
grab a Bratwurst
and wrap it in a pain au chocolat.
Because tonight we're off to France
and Germany.
You are like a Pound Shop,
Michael Palin.
I'm a man of culture.
Fred, what are we starting with?
Supercars,
because here's the thing.
Every time we talk about supercars,
it's always those big numbers -
power, speed, price.
Yes, but we got to thinking, surely
the real point in supercars
is how they make you feel,
giving the lucky so-and-so behind
the wheel the time of the life.
And for that does bigger,
really mean better?
So to find out, we pick three cars
from different points
on the Supercar scale
and set out to do some proper
testing in Germany.
To find out if bigger really does
mean better
in the world of supercars,
the only way to kick off
is with a treat from the very top
of the supercar tree.
The Pagani Huayra Roadster BC.
I've gone grande,
I've gone very grande.
Whoa!
What we've got here is a
790-horsepower
convertible hypercar
that costs £3.2 million.
But what does £3.2 million get you?
Well, the body made of carbotanium,
which is a mixture
of carbon fibre and titanium.
And with fighter jet spec aero,
with a bespoke six-litre-twin-turbo
AMGV 12...
..it'll hit 60 in 3.2 seconds
and top out at about 230mph.
Sure, the Huayra badge might be ten
years old now,
but this latest roadster is still
utterly captivating.
This thing is an absolute joy.
HE LAUGHS
Unadulterated bliss.
The question is, though,
do you really need all that
when you could save
yourself nearly three million quid
and still have one of these?
The 296 GTB,
the latest, greatest
mid-engine supercar
from the guys who've been making
supercars
longer and better than anyone else.
A new Ferrari supercar is always
a big deal...
..but the big news with the 296 is
it's pointing the old prancing horse
towards new, greener pastures.
Instead of the traditional V8,
this one's packing a smaller,
cleaner
plug-in hybrid V6.
Now, if all that feels a bit
responsible and downsizey
do not worry.
This little, sensible Ferrari
produces 818 horsepower,
all to the rear wheels.
Nought to 60 under three seconds.
Top speed, 205 mile an hour.
And this is Ferrari's
entry-level supercar.
The world has gone officially mad.
Oh, jeez, jeez.
Ah!
How are you, my friend?
I'm good, I'm just taking an eyeful
through my rear-view mirror,
Pagani Huayra.
How much power has it got?
Just under 800 brakehorse.
So your car cost ten times
more than mine.
And I've got over 800.
It's not always about numbers
and facts and figures, is it?
It's about the excitement, the joy.
I hope you've got comprehensive
insurance, Paddy.
Exactly.
Because the excitement and joy
I brought
doesn't cost £3 million
or £300,000.
No.
For a truly extraordinary drive
half that buys this.
The Porsche Cayman GT4 RS,
The car, they said, would
never happen.
Geeks like me have always
wondered
what a beautiful little mid-engine
Cayman would be like
with proper power.
The answer is predictably
sensational.
After decades of saying it wouldn't,
Porsche has finally taken its
smallest mid-engine sports car...
..and stuffed it with the
500-horsepower flat six
from the 911 GT3.
Well, they were at it,
they added new springs, dampers,
anti-roll bars
and aero,
plus lightweight carbon body panels
and air intakes
just behind your head.
But even though Porsche
has upgraded pretty much every bit
over the standard GT4,
it insists this car isn't about
numbers and lap times.
That's not to ignore the fact
that it's 196mph
and not the 60 in a three and a bit
seconds.
So it's still very, very fast.
But the steering's perfection,
the size is just right.
The Cayman GT4 is the type
of car that makes you forget
about your supercars and hypercars
and asks the question
why do you need anything more?
Woohoo!
Oh, dear, dear, dear.
Christopher, did you not get the
brief?
Supercars?
"Supercar", "hypercar",
they're just labels.
What matters is how much
fun you're having.
And this car is a riot.
I can't even see, Chris.
It's being blocked out by a Pagani.
This might be the baby of the bunch,
but it'll still do 196mph,
which I think is ample
for a clown like you.
I've got to say, I feel
a bit left out.
I didn't get the "turn up in
a banana yellow car" memo today.
I'm just in this grey and black
fighter jet.
Come on, Pad, be honest.
Since you got in that thing,
have you managed to unclench?
How much is that thing worth?
£3.2 million, Chris.
Deary me!
With that in mind
because one of the biggest thrills
a great supercar has to give you
is real world speed,
to start finding out what this
remarkable trio really had to offer,
we made our first port of call,
the great driving Mecca, that is...
..the Autobahn.
Chris, show us how it's done.
Me first time.
Here we go, boys.
Right, have a look at this.
So when you see the magic sign,
it looks a bit like
the national speed limit sign of the
UK,
that is when you can go.
There are no limits at that point.
Yes, when the conditions are right,
on the autobahn,
you're legally allowed to go
as fast as you want.
I feel like a caged tiger,
just pacing up and down,
wanting to go.
The only trouble is, in this busy,
modern world of ours,
a lot of the time, the conditions...
..are wrong.
I've got to be honest,
it's not all it's cracked up to be.
I've heard stories about it since
I was a kid, and I'm on it now.
I go faster on the A50.
We're stuck behind a Ford Galaxy.
Sadly, it's all about time of day,
boys
And we just arrived at
the wrong time of day.
It's Friday, everyone's heading
off for the weekend.
Yeah, we won't be going more than
70mph on here.
Wow.
This is like flying all the way
to the Seychelles
and it's 12 degrees and cloudy.
This is like what I do.
Go to McDonald's and get
a vegan burger.
Or like meeting Paddy McGuinness
and realising
he's just not that funny.
Funny.
# I drive my kia
I can see it...#
With the traffic showing no signs
of improving,
we had to chalk up the Autobahn
as unfinished business.
So next we headed for a nearby town
to see what our cars would make
of a bit of urban living.
The only thing I would say
with a Pagani,
driving through these beautiful,
quaint, little roads
with these little cottagey houses,
I feel a little bit...
ooh, a bit, I shouldn't be here.
I think that's progress for you,
Pad.
Usually you just don't care.
What is German for I bet the bloke
that drives that
has got a tiny willy?
It's Herr Chris Harris.
Anyhow, Pad, the active aero
should prove crucial around the
urban streets of Rosenheim.
I'm starting to feel a bit smug now,
boys.
Because on the open road
I reckon I was having as much,
if not more, fun.
And right now my, um...
..a certain
part of my body isn't biting a hole
in the seat like it is for you two.
I'm more good at it, Chris.
I'm just going to pop it into
electric mode.
Here we go.
Oh, that is smug, actually.
That's definitely smug.
It's a proper hybrid, the  296.
I get 15 odd miles or so just
pottering about in electric.
It's responsible, it's green.
Can't be said about that Pagani,
though, can it?
Nothing green about that.
No, there isn't.
And, as it turns out, there's also
plenty of other reasons
not to take your three million quid
Pagani
into town for a bratwurst.
Oh.
Narrow here, breathe in, Pad,
breathe in.
Oh, that's tight.
Rather you than me with that thing.
Well, at least no-one's looking.
I've never been as
self-conscious
and embarrassed in my life.
Do you know what I've just done,
which is really pathetic?
I've turned it off electric then the
engine makes a noise.
How sad is that?
I'm not driving
around in electric gear.
I want to make a noise.
I'm in a Ferrari, bright yellow.
Sad or not, Flintoff had landed
on a crucial point
about the Supercar experience,
one that needed more discussion over
a sit down
with a sausage.
Do you know what I don't understand?
What?
Being in Germany you go with...
Now in the UK,
I'll have that on a brioche roll.
Soft...
..as a crusty cob.
I don't think it goes with
a...  It's a great sausage.
I'm not disputing that.
Sitting here, mine does look a bit
undernourished, I have to say.
As I was saying,
that car that's in the middle of
those two
has gone invisible, it's crazy.
I've got to say, though,
the more I look at the Ferrari,
the more I'm enjoying it.
Loved it from the start and it's
getting better, Lovely thing.
It's not fair being next to that,
though.
It looks better than that.
It doesn't draw as much attention,
though, does it, that's the thing.
Well, why do you want the attention?
It's a supercar.
Supercar, hypercar, whatever you
want to call it,
needs to be like that in my eye.
I'm going to be really honest
here, right.
If you get a car like that...  Yeah.
..I don't care what you say,
you want to be seen a little bit.
Of course you do.  Even Chris Harris.
It's a £3.2 million car.
You want to show it off a bit.
One thing I've been wondering
about, Paddy....
..where's the roof on your car?
Where'd you put it?
Great question.
See down at the back there?  Yeah.
Under there?  Down there.
Now just kind of cast your eye a
bit further across the square
and then right over there, see that
grey van?
That's where it is.
There's no-where for it?  You have a
man following you with the roof?
Yeah, he follows you around,
life's good, and also as well,
let me show you this,
little extra this.
It comes with a set of exclusive
luggage.
Comes with an absolute pillock
driving it as well.
He thinks this is his car.
Normally I'm doing this, but
normally me man in the van does
this for me.
Pop that open.  Yeah.
Beautiful.
That couldn't...  Look at your car.
That couldn't look less like your
car. It's so obvious you've never
done that before.
What have you got in there? Make-up?
That's my luggage.
What would you fit in there?
If you want the luggage option,
you're looking at around about an
extra 30 grand.
I know you think that's a lot of
money, but...
I don't think
it is, that's a lot of money.
That's the price of a new car.
We're not finished.
Same set of luggage on this side.
And...
..the key.
Well, go on, then.
Let's have a look.
What's... What's that?
The exact shape and replica
of the car. Look at it.
Right.  You imagine you're out at -
what's a posh restaurant? - Nando's.
Everyone's got their BMW keys.
You go, bosh. "There's my key."
Shape of a car, 20 quid.
No.  Yeah.
You're not comparing them two.
Yeah.  So when you go to...
Even feel the weight of that.
It's nothing. That's weighty.
It's basically a Corgi toy
in your pocket wherever you go.
The problem with that is,
I've got a two-and-a-half year old.
PADDY MAKES CAR SOUNDS
Invisible.
Love it!
THEY LAUGH
Now just let's sit down and enjoy
our steins of lemonade.
GLASSES CLINK Cheers.  Solid clunk.
Aah! Come on, lads.
What on earth is he made of?
Did you see that?
PADDY BELCHES
How's he done that.
ENGINE REVS
So, it had been an informative
first day in supercar land.
After all, it's reassuring to think
that while the owner of a £3 million
Pagani's life is full of drama,
it's not always
drama of the good kind.
ENGINES ROAR AND EXHAUSTS BURBLE
What I pulled away then, and
that shocked me how quick this was.
And I honestly think I'd have paid
a bit extra for some clean underwear
in the boot cos it does
get a bit twitchy.
Ah-ha!
And speaking of drama, it's
gratifying to know that the best
soundtrack of our three doesn't come
from the ultra exclusive Huayra,
or even the Maranello thoroughbred.
Listen to this.
EXHAUST NOTE ROARS
Wow!
What a noise!
But with the sun setting
over the foothills of the Alps,
the best part was that our
great super car experiment
was just getting started.
Lads, do you fancy a trip
on the autobahn on the way back?
Don't see why not.
I think we need a dab of speed.
Oh, yes.
It was time to settle
that unfinished business.
Let's get on with it, boys.
Come on.
I've got that nervous excitement.
Now, when it comes to running on the
derestricted autobahn,
there's one thing, above all else,
you need to know.
It is a drive that requires
more concentration than any drive
you've ever done in your life.
Derestrict now, boys.
ENGINE ROARS
ENGINE NOTE RECEDES
EXHAUST OVERRUNS
Whoa.
Man alive!
This is incredible.
This car is incredible.
Oh, I'm pleased as punch that
we got to have a proper go.
I'm pleased as punch.
Imagine coming here and just sitting
in a town square eating sausage.
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
I felt like a proud dad taking two
young pups for their first run
on the Autobahn. Well done.
Right.
Now, the idea of this film is how
these super cars make you feel.
Yeah.  Now, I can tell you on that
autobahn in that Pagani,
I felt bloody terrified.
I mean, in the dark
roof off, so visceral, felt so fast.
Now, it wasn't a competition, but do
you want to know how fast you went?
Oh, yeah.
It's got to be easy 250.
I heard a sonic boom at one point.
LAUGHTER Unbelievable.
OK, well, you actually did 167mph.
That'll do.  That's all right,
innit..  It felt faster.
..with the roof down?
It felt faster.  Now, in the little
Porsche I did 172mph.
Oh, wow.  Wow.  Again, all legally.
Yeah.  Fred, 174mph in the Ferrari.
Still wanted to keep going.
Yeah.  It's barely in its stride,
is it?
Because the Ferrari was the
quickest.
But the thing is, it was so serene,
it didn't even feel
like it was breaking a sweat.
I did enough sweating
for all of us in that Pagani.
Shall we move on?
Yes, please do.
We'll get back to our supercars
later in the show.
But now we need to talk
about these - micro cars.
Tiny little pods
designed for busy cities.
Back in the '50s and '60s,
there was a whole rash
of these things, but they never
really caught on.
But now micro cars are back
in a big way.
Well, a small way.
And we decided it was time to run
the magnifying glass over some
of the latest tiniest offerings.
HORN TOOTS
Where better to explore the brave
new world of electric mini city cars
than that most popular of
mini break cities - Paris?
And because France loves
these microcars more than most,
say a big bienvenue to
the Citroen Ami.
First things first,
this isn't even a car, technically -
it's a quadricycle.
Which means it's about
pure minimalism -
stripping everything out
you don't need,
so there's no rear-view mirror,
no central locking,
there's a very basic fan
and heated front screen.
The seats are just two cushions
plunked on some solid plastic.
BIKE BELL RINGS
It'll do 30mph, flat out.
It's not even allowed on a motorway.
Yeah, it couldn't be more basic.
MOPED REVS
In fact, the Ami's tiny
proportions, limited performance
and simplistic design mean
that here in France you can drive
one from the age of 14.
Quite what that means for the rest
of France's drivers, of course,
remains to be seen.
But around town right now in Paris,
it might just be the perfect fit.
Very nice.
But if you want to get to those
spots your average city car
won't reach,
you'll be wanting one of these.
A Carver.
Now, this three-wheeled wonder
starts at around £12,000.
It comes from the Netherlands,
and it's a very generous tipper.
Whoa-ho-ho!
Carvers have been around
for a long time now.
But this is the new
electric version.
Wah-hey-hey-hey!
Yep, all of the tilt,
none of the guilt.
The only thing with the Carver,
this particular one, is you do need
a bike licence to drive it.
But no crash helmet.
So you're never going to mess
your hair up.
Them were the days.
And besides, if you ever do get
over the sheer joy of how it works
in this eight horsepower S+ model,
you've also got a 50mph top speed
and a 62-mile range.
That might just make this
the ultimate urban micro machine.
Nipping in and out of traffic,
looking at the sights,
tilting about,
wonderful.
Maybe.
But if you want a city car
with a proper secret superpower,
there is another way.
The City Transformer CT-1
is made by an Israeli start-up,
and it's packing a mighty
20 horsepower.
And if you think it's not
that ground-breaking,
just have a look at this.
Literally, honey, I shrunk the car.
What you need is narrowness.
But the problem we've really
narrow cars is when you get them
out on the open road and fast
corners, well, they tend
to fall over.
I'll never get bored of that.
It is a proper Transformer.
Well, almost.
The CT-1 is so brand-new that this
Transformer's still a prototype,
but it will eventually cost
about 13-grand.
Ooh.
And while that might be more than
the other two,
here you get over 100 miles of
range,
a 56mph top speed,
and plenty of attention.
Hey-hey-hey!
They love it, the Parisians.
Oh, mais oui!
I'm just showing off now.
Here we go.
Tell you what, I am that
focused on my wheels,
I've just noticed the Eiffel Tower
in my mirror behind.
Didn't even see it.
Now, to see how our remarkable micro
cars really took to city living,
we'd agreed to meet up with them
at the Arc de Triomphe,
which, of course,
is also one of Europe's
finest, busiest roundabouts.
HORNS HONK
Oh, that was a good move.
A good move from the Citroen DS.
As long as you keep your eyes
peeled, it's great fun.
It's like real life dodgems really.
Oh! It's out the way.
My God.
Oh, my word.
You've got to have your wits
about you on here, haven't you?
There's Paddy. All right, Pad?
HORN TOOTS
Get over, you bloody nutter!
Treat it like a game of Mario Kart
and you'll be just about there,
chaps.
Look at this!
There's pedestrians running over!
I tell you what, Fred, that thing
looks like it's about fall over
from where I'm sitting.
HORNS TOOT
Here comes the bus.
Stay there!
HORN BLARES
That was close, Fred.
That was close, that was close.
Deciding that six complete orbits
of the Arc de Triomphe
was probably enough...
I'm getting dizzy.
How do we actually
get off this roundabout?
..we eventually manoeuvred
ourselves out of the chaos...
He's brave bringing that here.
Madness!
..and headed on to
the Champs-Elysees.
MUSIC: Bongo Cha Cha Cha
by Caterina Valente
Watch this, boys. The Transformer.
Are you ready?
THEY CHEER
Oh, yes, my son.
That's fantastic.
Get in!
That's a belter!
HE LAUGHS
Yours tilts, mine transforms.
Lovely stuff!
HE CHUCKLES
# Bongo la, bongo cha cha cha... #
Here we go, lads.
Off the beaten track.
That's the beauty
of these little rascals.
You feel like you're beating
the system, or doing
something you shouldn't -
I really like it.
Fancy a le cafe?
Trois expressos s'il vous plait.
Last car pays, eh, Pad?
It was good?  Merci.
French kiss.
And once you've had your fill of
cafe culture,
no Parisian mini break
would be complete without a quick
spin around the shops.
It's not cheap, Paris, is it, Pad?
Jeez, look at the prices!
Oh, we've got gridlock in Givenchy.
I might have a prang in Prada.
I don't why I'm going like this.
I'm going to have a Fendi bender.
Get it? Fendi bender.
PADDY LAUGHS DISGUSTEDLY
While a bit of windscreen
shopping might be all well
and good, though...  Merci.
..to see which of these
miniature miracles
was really best at slicing
through city streets...
..we've been told to head
up to the stunning
Sacre-Coeur Basilica.
Oh, look at this.
Beautiful.
Scissor doors!
Lovely stuff!
It's like a Lamborghini, Fred.
Look at that view.
Look at this. This is lovely.
Oh, yes.
A magnificent view of the city
about to be made that little
bit more...French.
Bonjour.  He's giving it all...
He's gabbing on a bit.
No city mini break would be complete
without a bit of celebrity spotting.
You will now race to get as many
selfies as possible with the famous
faces we have placed
around the city.
Be at the Eiffel Tower before time's
up, or you will be disqualified.
Got it.
Spotting celebrities.
Hey, found one. F-...
Oh, no, sorry.
HE LAUGHS
So, in what might politely
be described as an imaginative way
of testing three new
urban microcars,
we would now have two hours
to squeeze through
the bustling Parisian traffic
in a bid to find as many
of the waxworks celebrities
that have been dotted
around the city as possible.
Now, only a few of those
celebrities were living.
Many were French.
Some were none of the above.
So to help us on our way, we'd each
been armed with a map to the stars
to locate them...
Oh, my God.
It's all in bloody French.
..and a sat nav to get us there.
Here we go.
Life is a box of chocolates.
And for a final dusting
of Gallic flavour, the winner
would be the driver that got
to the Eiffel Tower
having bereted and selfied the most
celebs before the two hours were up.
Ooh, very exciting.
Three, two, one,
go!
Right, we're away.
Oh, he's gone in the little Citroen.
Here we go.
Edith Piaf is actually only 700
yards away, so I'm in for a chance
of striking first blood here.
Oh.
What a day for spotting
famous folk.
I'm going to get into Paris,
I'm going to get in the mixer,
pick them off one by one - Tom
Hanks, Van Gogh, Charles De Gaulle.
An Ami on the cobbled streets
of northern Paris.
Just built this. It's like
a Formula 1 car Spa this is.
Every corner you go around,
you feel like Rossi.
Where is Edith?
I'm going to have to get out
and look for her.
Where's bloody Edith Piaf?
So Harris has got red berets,
Fred's got blue,
and I've got the white ones.
So if I see any blue or red
I know they've got there before me.
Wheels in.
Coming into its own,
this little thing, the Transformer.
Wheels in, I get through
all the gaps.
Oh, my God.
She's very small.
Oh, he's found one.
He's found one. Damn him!
SHUTTER CLICKS
Right, Steve Jobs,
let's be having you.
Right, we're off.
First blood to the Ami.
And while next I set my sights
on influential
novelist Marcel Proust,
so far Flintoff had only found
a street that even his Transformer
couldn't squeeze down.
Come on.
It's gridlock.
I'm in gridlock. Ah!
I'm going down here.
I'm making my own route.
Let's go!
Better still, after 20 minutes
on the move,
McGuinness's hunt for Steve
Jobs was heating up
for all the wrong reasons.
Literally the hottest car on Earth,
and I'm in it.
No aircon, no fans.
Just a massive piece of glass
magnifying the sun's rays
onto the top of my thinning hair!
HORN TOOTS
Plus, over in the prototype
City Transformer,
Flintoff's day was about to
get worse.
It's starting to smell a bit
burny in here.
I'm going to pull in here.
Jeez.
What a disaster.
Absolute disaster.
And as the people who built it
rushed in to diagnose the problem...
It's starting to smell a bit
in here.
..McGuinness might have finally
got the Jobs in hand.
Oh, my God. There's Steve Jobs.
I can see him!
But over at the Place de la
Concorde, the little Ami
and I were already scampering up...
Marcel Proust. There he is.
..to our second celeb.
One of the greats.
SHUTTER CLICKS
Hey, I tell you, that's a good one,
that, n'all.
SHUTTER CLICKS
So that's Ami, two, Carver, one,
Transformer, nil points.
Can you smell it?
Yeah. It's too hot.
Optimus was still getting back
to his prime, and this was starting
to look like a two-horse race.
Tom Hanks, allez.
But while Harris might have had
an early advantage, on the sticky
streets of Paris, the little Carver
was just starting to shine.
Oh. Oh-ho. I can see young Mozart.
Look at this lad.
That's literally like
little Chris Harris.
School uniform.
SHUTTER CLICKS
Back with the Transformer,
we were up and running again.
But with time running away,
I needed a new target.
Come on, then, Ryan Gosling.
Hello!  What are you...? Go away!
Oh, Flintoff, look at the way
he can get through there.
Oh, that's appalling!
Hey-hey-hey!
Yes, please.
Coming through.
Look at him, he's just wending
his way, he's making an extra lane
for himself.
The Ami is the width of a car.
It may be short,
but I've got this width issue.
And that means
that while your little Citroen
might be stuck in a slow crawl
towards Tom Hanks.
in a Carver you could be bagging
a French Olympian...
Teddy. SHUTTER CLICKS
..and a former president.
Charles de Gaulle.
I'm going to put it there on his
shoulder on this one. Respect.
SHUTTER CLICKS
Here he is! Ryan Gosling!
La La Land, I'm in it.
Oh, that's a handsome man.
With just half an hour of our city
sprint left to go,
me and my micro car
were finally on the board.
Cheers, Ryan!
But the breakdown had left
us way off the pace.
Run, Forrest, run!
SHUTTER CLICKS
So while the other two
were still fighting for the win...
Van Gogh! Ho-ho!
I've got to give it a go with
Van Gogh, I think.
..me and the Transformer were now
only in reach of Harris's
celebrity leftovers.
Oh, no, he's got a red beret on. No!
There we go.
Desperate measures.
I'm going to go to the Eiffel Tower.
Where are you, Vincent?
Where'd Van Gogh be, then?
My only chance of winning
is getting there first on time
and the lads get stuck.
Oh, you're kidding me.
It's got a hat on it already.
Too late now, son. I've done you!
I think with three, statistically,
I'm all right.
On my way to the finishing line,
but am I going to get
there on time?
Cos if I don't I'll be gutted.
Jeez, this thing shifts!
Oh, I should have gone down there.
Oh, sugar.
I should have gone down there.
Right, I've gone wrong.
There is the Eiffel Tower.
Come on.
Oh, I can see the chequered flag.
I can see the chequered flag.
Here we go.
There's the finish line.
HORN BLARES
Hey!
I'm not seeing any other
vehicles yet.
I'll get us a table
at the restaurant.
Oh, they're both here.
Damn it.
There he is.
Here he is. Well done, Christles.
Lads.
Bit tight on time. Bit tight
on time.  Cutting it fine.
Now, I think I did OK.
I don't think I've won.
Right.  So I'll show you.
I'm out, Chris.  you're out?
I got Ryan Gosling...
Yeah.  ..one...  Yeah.
..and I nicked your Marcel.
I took your beret off and put mine
on. So you can have that one.
This worries me cos that means that
- I would have thought,
statistically, I got three...
Oh, and he looks smug. OK.
I do look a little bit smug.
That's Paddy McGuinness.
how many did you get?  Cinq.
Five! There we go.
Creme brulee.
Thank you.  Beaten into second place.
Thank you.
Well done, Chris.
I do like a treasure hunt, lads.
Can we do more of that?
I enjoyed that.
What we've got to do is get
them waxworks back in
cos in this heat,
they'll be like a 99.
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
To sum up, if you want to dash
around Paris sticking berets
on waxworks, the car for the job
is the Carver.  Correct.
They'll be putting that in the
brochure.
It's not surprising the Carver won
because what this test has proved,
when it comes to squeezing
through a city, and there's
never a good way to say
this word, everyone,
it's all about girth.
LAUGHTER
What you need is something
a little bit slender.
No, the Ami, that's great,
but it's the same width
as a regular vehicle.
You're stuck in the same
traffic as everyone else,
but with no air con.  Yeah.
And, Fred,
the City Transformer - again,
great little car if only it'd
transform into something that works.
Yeah, well, the one I had in Paris
was a prototype, and they reckon now
they've fixed the glitches.  Right.
So it seems I was a very important
part of the development process.
OK.  You're welcome.
But for now, the Carver
is the clear winner.
Not only is it the best around town,
but it turns every corner
into an event. You're tilting
that way... It's fantastic.
But they could make a couple of
slight improvements, couldn't they?
Take the roof off it,
remove a wheel,
they could call it a motorcycle.
I think he's on to something.
But now it's time to move on from
electric to very petrol
as we get back
to our big supercar adventure.
Our vital humanity-advancing quest
to discover what makes a truly great
supercar had led us into Austria...
..where, having now spent
a good spell behind the wheel,
it has to be said,
over in the more expensive seats
that new-car shine was just starting
to wear off in a couple of places.
Do you know, there's so many things
with this car,
it's so dramatic.
It has a really annoying thing
where if you, say, pull up to
a traffic light and you're sat there
for 30 seconds or so,
it engages neutral automatically.
And then when you put it in first
to set off, there's a little lag
of about a second or so.
But in that second,
the lights are on green,
you've got some tool behind you.
beeping their horn,
"Come on, mate. They're on green."
I'm like, "I know, I'm just putting
it in first gear."
I'm a Ferrari man.
I love them.
I love the brand.
I love the heritage.
But the thing which is getting
on my nerves a bit is all
this touch stuff -
heating, fan, seat.
Ugh. Display.
It's all one touch pads.
And half the time, I'm looking
down here trying to find stuff.
I've got 800 horsepower.
I need my eyes on the road.
I don't want to be looking
down around everywhere.
It's fixing problems for me
that don't exist.
Lads, let's talk rarity.
Firstly, how many of them Ferraris?
Not sure. Probably about 10,000
they're going to make of them.
It's going to be popular, isn't it?
What about yours, Chris?
Fewer, I reckon.
5,000, 6,000 in all.
Big numbers, lads.
The Pagani, 40.
To put that into some
kind of context for you -
there's been 45 US presidents.
Who's told him this information?
45 presidents.
I reckon the people at Pagani would
be happy if there's still 40
of them cars when you finish
today, Paddy.
Well, it was time to
give them a scare.
Because to help us out on our quest,
the producers had told us to stop
off at a local test track.
Wowsers.
If I had to design a circuit that
was least suitable for a Huayra BC
this would be it.
Best of luck, McGuinness.
Here we go.
I'm going to stop here, lads.
There's a fella.
The idea was we'd each stick
on a heart rate monitor,
do a couple of laps
in all three cars...
Danke.
..and whichever caused our heart
rates to spike the highest
would be the most exciting.
Not a bad way to help
decide which supercar gives
you the more thrills.
The only question for the Pagani was
what kind of excitement it'd be.
What do you reckon, boys? Shall we?
Here we go.
ENGINES REV
And we're off.
Come on, McGuinness!
These hypercars are all well and
good until you've got
a narrow circuit.
Whoa!  Now watch him go.
Oh-ho-ho! It's gone!
Oh, my God.
BLEEP, BLEEP.
Look at the speed of it!
I put it in track mode and then
I pressed the qualifying button,
which gives me all of the
818 horsepower.
Not recharging the batteries,
nothing.
Just going.
Wow, this thing is bonkers.
TYRES SCREECH
Oh, ho, ho, ho, ho!
There she goes.
CHRIS LAUGHS
Holy Scheisse.
Paddy McGuinness's sphincter
is working overtime in that thing.
Look at the little fella here.
Let's let him have a bit of fun.
Go on, Chris.
Go on.
Ha-ha!
I must catch Flintoff.
TYRES SCREECH
Go on, Chrissy!
He is definitely having fun.
The balance of this car is
just sensational.
Chris is catching me
in the little Porsche.
Here we go, Chris.
Don't even think about it.
Look at it go!
Pull away. Get away! Get away!
Oh, I'm in love!
That Ferrari has got some legs.
First run results were in,
and predictably enough showed
that Flintoff is basically a basking
shark, and the Pagani really does
get the blood pumping.
Time to swap cars...
..and run again.
Wow.
OK. That's just silly.
That's so much faster
than the Porsche.
Oh, my word. Wow!
This is raw. It's visceral.
Come on.
Man alive!
Really interesting getting straight
out of the Porsche into this.
That thing just feels alive.
The steering's wriggling around
in your hand.
In this thing it's a numb device
compared to the Porsche.
I've never driven anything
like this in my life.
I like it. I don't like it.
I'm enjoying it.
I'm scared of it.
I don't really know what's
going on with his car.
Here we go, I put the windscreen
wipers on then and I don't even know
how I did it.
I tell you what, though,
it's something else to drive.
Oh, man!
I think I might be having fun.
ENGINE REVS, TYRES SCREECH
Jeepers creepers!
I tell you what, with all the
traction off this is lively.
This is a really impressive car.
Really impressive.
Impressive enough, it turned out,
to spike Harris's heart rate
by more than 40 beats
over the Porsche.
Wow, wow, wow.
Mr Flintoff, you chose wisely.
Deary me.
And whilst the Cayman had calmed
me down and the Pagani had almost
woken Fred up, there was now
just the small matter
of one more swamp.
Oh, my God.
That is ridiculous.
I've just got out of two cars with
800 horsepower into one with 500.
It's a completely different drive.
That does not mean, though,
it's not a hell of a lot of fun.
Wow.
Oh-ho-ho.
Yeah, I've missed the point
a bit it here, haven't I?
This isn't about how fast it goes
but about the event.
Ho-ho-ho!
There he goes.
Look at Harris go in the Pagani.
Hello, Pagani, my old friend.
Bit sideways there.
I love this Porsche.
I understand it now,
Chrissy Harris.
I understand the Porsche.
Amazing. I'm in a full hypercar,
and it really isn't much quicker
in a straight line
than the baby Ferrari.
Half the price of the Ferrari.
5% of the price of the Pagani.
I've got to say,
it's so much fun.
Maybe just a bit too much fun.
Here we go.
Let's give it some now.
That was pretty special.
We're missing a cricket player.
Oh, dear.
Oh, this is the...
This is the drive of shame.
Here he is.  What's happened?
Nothing. He was just
enjoying himself.
Everything OK?
Yeah.
Just a bit of off-roading,
you know what I mean?
I can see all that grass there.
What did you do?
Well, I came round,
it started going sideways,
I didn't catch it,
so I slid down the bank.
You've actually come down the bank?
Yeah. And I just carried on again.
Oh, that's nice.  I had another
go at it.  Right, so...
Oh, 99. Gone down.
130.
130?
Is that less than that?
It was less than that, yes.
I wasn't confident enough to slide
that around.
But still, it's an event. And I've
also got McGuinness in front of me,
which is always going to make me
nervous.  What was yours?  77.
Oh, that's not even alive!  What,
even after all that?  As I came down
the bank.  Yeah.  Yeah.
..I got to 115.  Nice.
..and then I got back to the bank
and I was back to 75.
So do you always get nervous
when you off road?
When it's off-road unintentionally.
So clearly, Pagani's the winner
because everyone's heart rate
went up.
No, I was highest in that, 147.
Yeah, and you were lowest in that.  I
was lowest in that having more fun.
Hang on, I'm just trying to
compute this.
I'm enjoying myself at my most
when I'm calm...  Yeah.
..and I'm in it
and I'm just relaxed.
I was that in the Porsche.
What I rate more fun for me.
Hang on, so your heart rate goes
up when you're not having fun
and when you're really happy
and having fun,
your heart rate goes down.
I'm calm. I'm calm. Yeah.
Oh.
Danke.
Bit harsh.
You will now head to the
Grossglockner Pass,
one of the greatest driving
roads in the world.
Please decide between you
who is taking which car.
Can I first of all say, I don't want
to go in that?  I'm with you.
I don't want either of you to go in
that because that's what
I'm going in. Love it.
Erm...
Never thought I'd say it,
but do you fancy swapping?
Yes, please.
Now, look, when you're given the
chance to drive
a £3.2 million Pagani,
however intense, maybe even
sometimes stressful
that experience might be,
the thing is, you always know
that soon enough, you're going to
have to give it back.
And having been lucky enough
to spend some time with one,
I was going to make the most
of every last minute.
I knew those two would swap.
Car buddies.
But, I'm glad.
I really love this car.
I love the theatre.
I love the drama.
I love everything about it.
Quite clear that Fred really enjoyed
the GT4 RS, as did I.
The fact that Fred enjoyed it,
I just thought,
share the wealth, Chris.
Share the wealth.
I've chosen to drive this
sensational 800-horsepower Ferrari
through altruism alone.
I'm just being generous.
The Ferrari's rapid,
it's comfortable, it's beautiful.
But this was the one.
Giving up the new Ferrari
for a Porsche half the price.
And do you know what?
That suits me just fine.
Here we go, lads, the Grossglockner.
Genuinely excited by this.
My heart rate might touch 80!
MUSIC: Outro
by M83
36 hairpin bends draped across
48km of pristine tarmac.
Winding through the heart of one
of the most stunning landscapes
in central Europe.
The Grossglockner Pass isn't just
the highest road in Austria.
It's one of the most awe-inspiring
drives anywhere on the planet.
And in an open top Pagani, it can
also be one of the most refreshing.
Oh, dear.
Should have give the man with
a van a call. Whack my roof on.
I'm not sure this is Huayra BC
Roadster conditions now.
You'd be absolutely correct.
This car is outrageous.
So much torque.
I'm in third gear on a hairpin,
and the traction control's
coming in.
Wow.
This is incredible.
What a road this is.
ENGINE REVS
This is the car.
This is the car for this road.
As we climbed higher,
the clouds began to part.
The supercar gods were smiling,
and Paddy and his Pagani came back
to the party.
Oh, this is good.
# Now and forever... #
What a road.
# I'm your king. #
Whoo-ho-ho!
Wow. What a piece of tarmac, boys.
Wow. Look at that view.
What a treat this has been.
The cars, the roads, the scenery.
Amazing.
I think we're near the top, boys.
I think we're near the top.
That's the summit.
Oh!
First things first.
Is your handbrake on?
Yes.
The handbrakes are on.
Everything's on.
Wow.  Unbelievable.
Never driven anything like it.
Look at that.
That is sensational.
Autobahn, racetrack, Grossglockner.
Magic.
What a trip.
Same cars on the way down, boys?
Yes, please.
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
You still think it's yours!
No.
Now, we have to reach some
conclusions here, lads.
Now remember, we set out to find out
how these cars made us feel.
Paddy, did you enjoy driving
your Pagani?
Well, don't get me wrong,
I love this car, love it,
and it had the power to make
Ferraris invisible.  I agree, yeah.
And every time I got out of it,
I was in a good mood.
So did you enjoy it?
Well, I was in a good mood
cos I'd survived.
I was just happy all my body parts
were where they should be, really.
It was not so much happy,
more relief.
It was a happy ending.
LAUGHTER
Don't go there. Don't go there.
Fred.  Yeah?
It's important we talk
about our feelings.  Mm.
How did that Ferrari make you feel?
That's the question, isn't it?
It's so fast, but also
a bit sterile.  Mm.  All right?
And it's about, not the speed,
like you say, how it made us feel.
And I can't believe I'm saying
this about a Ferrari.
I didn't feel much.
I felt a little bit numb.
But that Porsche -
punching way above its weight.
Just a fantastic car, isn't it?
I just loved every minute of it.
And each time you both drove it,
you got out smiling.
I loved it.
So obviously you two
are going for the Porsche.
We know that.  Yep.
But if I had to pick one
as a daily...
Yeah.
..it'd be the Porsche as well.
It really would.
But I tell you what, I'd save
the Pagani for little weekends
out round Morecambe.
Love that.  Morecambe?
Love that, yes.
So all in all,
a very successful research trip.
Absolutely.
And that's it for tonight.
But we've not done with the exotic
metal because in next week's show,
Chris Harris has a go in Mercedes'
F1 car for the road, and trust me...
AUDIENCE CHEERS
..you do not want to miss that.
Thanks for watching.
See you, then. Goodnight!