This programme contains adult humour.
Hey!
I just won 450 quid playing poker!
Well done.
Saw that one coming. Mikey 73.
That's my rent sorted this month.
Ooh, and I can buy that new...
Oh no, I've lost it all again.
Jen.
Oh! Philip, hello.
Hi.
This is Philip from six.
This is Moss...Roy.
Hi.
Hiya.
So, what brings you to my lair?
Not that I'm some sort of animal!
Or...or maybe I am.
Oh, dear, oh, dear, oh, dear.
Oh, um, I was just,
er, wondering if...
er, you, em...had the latest Heat?
Yes, yes. There it is.
Thanks and...
Sorry about this.
I don't suppose maybe you'd like
to come to theatre tomorrow night?
I'd be delighted.
He means me, Moss.
He was looking at me.
No, he wasn't.
I think he was.
You're not even in his eyeline.
Philip, who were you talking to,
me or Jen?
Do you like the theatre?
Never been. But I've always liked
the idea of the theatre.
The smell of the grease,
the roar of the paint.
I've often thought if I hadn't
ended up in computers
I would've gone into the theatre.
But you've never been to see a play?
No.
Why not?
Never had the interest.
Any famous people in it?
No.
It's a pass from me then.
You haven't been invited anywhere!
Oh, wait, er...
Laura Knightly's in it.
Laura Knightly from The Bill?
She's gorgeous.
You know what, I will come, Philip.
Thank you.
There's no invitation.
Show me the invitation.
I guess you guys could come too,
if you want.
Tickets aren't a problem.
Great. That's settled then.
Right. I'll give you
a call later then,
give you the details,
how's that?
That is perfection itself.
Thanks for coming down, man!
Catch you later!
That could have been a date there.
Now it's a...work outing!
I nearly forgot the Heat!
Oh, yes.
It's...it's...
(SIGHS)
Ahh.
What?
He actually did want to borrow
the copy of Heat.
So?
Well, it's just...you know.
No, I don't. What?
I'm just surprised.
Why?
It's just I don't know many
heterosexual men who read Heat.
Huh, what, he's gay,
just because he reads Heat magazine?
Um, well he's either gay
or a woman in her early twenties.
No, no, no, why else
would he ask me out on a date?
Are you sure he meant
it as a date-date?
Are you sure you're not
going along as his gal pal?
If you're talking about who
I think you're talking about,
then the answer is, yes, he is gay.
How do you know?
Oh, everyone knows. And what's more,
he's been gay since Wham.
We're talking about Philip!
He borrowed Heat.
He borrowed Heat? Oh, la la!
And he knows people in the theatre.
That's not a euphemism. He actually
does know people in the theatre.
Anyway, it's a date, I'm sure it is.
Why else would he ask me out?
Well, don't take this the wrong way
but could he have
thought you were a man?
Let's get a taxi.
It's a ten-minute walk.
Oh, no, I don't like walking.
You could just not come,
then you won't have to walk.
I'm not gonna spoil your evening
with the gay man.
He's not a gay man.
He reads Heat!
Hey, where are you lot off to?
Oh, look, Richman's still alive!
We're going to the theatre.
Do you wanna come?
No, thank you.
And you shouldn't go either.
Why not?
An ill wind is blowing.
Last night, I was stirred
from my slumber
by a crow calling three times.
Caw, caw...
Well, you know what
a crow sounds like.
Passing to my window,
I trod on a piece of Lego.
Oh, it went right in the heel.
Turning on my television set, I
noticed the reception wasn't great,
not terrible, just not great.
Hear me well, no good can come
of your trip to the theatre tonight.
No good at all! And if you ask me...
That's just bloody rude.
Where's my Heat?
A gay musical called Gay.
That's quite gay.
Gay musical?
Aren't all musicals gay?
This must be like the gayest
musical ever made.
It's got some good reviews.
"The story of a young man
trying to find his sexuality
"in the uncaring Thatcher years.
"Warning: includes scenes
"of graphic homoeroticism."
Yuck, no!
It's set in the '80s!
"Graphic homoeroticism"?
Will they get them out?
Not comfortable with your sexuality?
I'm very comfortable,
I just don't want to be
slapped with their sexuality.
Oh, look, there's Philip.
Oh, look, he's letching at that lady.
Thank God for that.
He's just an ordinary, ignorant man.
Hey, you're already here!
Yeah.
What are we doing?
This isn't us.
It takes place in the past.
Forget the play.
Philip knows the cast.
It's about the party afterwards.
You just have to go up to everybody,
tell them they were brilliant
and you get free wine.
And besides, I really
wanna meet Laura Knightly.
Hey, the guys!
Wow, looks great, doesn't it?
We should really pick up
our tickets.
I know someone who gets the tickles!
Oh, ho ho!
I love doing that to him.
Hey!
This is Jerome, he does publicity.
He got us tickets.
Oh, great. Thanks.
This is Jen, and Moss, and Roy.
Hello, hello.
Hello, how's it going?
Oh, my God, you're Irish.
I love Irish people!
They're just mad, aren't they?
They're just mad!
We're all insane, yeah.
Well, you'll love dis!
It's great craic!
I'm mad for crack!
Well, quick, everyone,
show's about to start!
I hope Laura Knightly isn't
gonna be dressed up like Toyah.
Who's she in The Bill?
She plays that heroin addict
that gets stabbed in the face.
Oh, she is lovely.
Isn't she lovely?
Oh, god, here we go.
It might be all right.
Yeah. How bad can it be?
Welcome...
to the United...
QUEENDOM!
TECHNO MUSIC BLARES
Brilliant!
United Queendom?
He can't say that, can he?
# Today's the day the homophobes
get their arses kicked...#
Yeah! Yeah!
Yeah, kick their arses!
# Today is the day...
# I'm a friend of Dorothy,
I'm a friend of Dorothy.
# She is my friend... #
This is insanely brilliant.
# Hold my hand
# No, that's not my hand... #
# I love willies... #
OK, I'm completely satisfied.
Don't leave. It's rude.
It's too gay for me. Thought I could
handle it, but I can't.
It'll be the interval soon.
Well, I'm captivated.
Calm down. At least it can't
get any worse.
All right, get them house lights up,
let's have a look at you!
You wearing that shirt for a bet?
Audience participation.
Go, go, go.
Oh, what have we here?
Hello!
So, tell me, who wears the trousers
in this relationship?
What? Oh.
Right, no, we're not homosexuals,
we're just very good friends.
So you never had a look?
At what?
His bum!
I've seen it, when he squatted
in front of my desk
or should he bend over
to pick something up.
I'd love to work in that office!
Oh, there's nothing sexual going on.
I do like Roy but I'm not "curious".
What were you engaging him for?
He was asking me questions.
I couldn't just ignore him.
It'd be rude, Roy.
So what d'you think of it?
I think it's fabulous.
Every value I've ever held
has been questioned
and I'm loving it.
You don't like it, do you?
The songs are good.
No, they're not.
Hum one of the songs.
# Willies, willies,
I like willies. #
It's "I love willies".
Oh.
I love willies!
Could you keep it down?
I'm not going back in there.
Oh, yes, you are.
I'll wait out here for you
but there is no way
I'm going anywhere near that thing.
You can't leave me alone. I don't
know what the hell's going on.
He's laughing like an idiot
at every single gay reference!
Why didn't he come out for a drink?
He doesn't wanna miss anything!
I need to wee-wee.
Yeah, me too.
Oh, what's wrong?
They've got a toilet guy.
Oh, I hate toilet guys.
Let's just get it over with.
Thank you.
Cheers, dude.
Did you go?
No. Did you?
No. How could I?
That bloke stood looking at us.
It's not my fault
he works in a toilet!
How much did you give him?
A pound. I just paid a pound
not to go to the toilet!
He's a terrible toilet guy.
He should work somewhere
people don't want to go
to the toilet.
I'm gonna use the disabled.
You can't use it!
Why not?
You're not disabled.
You'll get in trouble.
It's not like a parking space, Moss.
I think.
I think it's OK. Isn't it?
I'm always using the disabled.
It's illegal!
I don't think so.
NO FLUSHING
Oh. Aah...
THUMPING ON DOOR
Hello. Hello. Are you all right
in there?
Um...
Do you need help? >
I'm disabled.
He sounds disoriented.
Move back from the door!
What? No.
Oh!
HEAVY BANGING
What are you doing?
Don't panic! >
What - what - what -
what - what's happening?
Someone's had an accident.
What?
Well, you'd better keep going, then.
Oh, my God. What happened?
I fell off the toilet.
Well, well, come on, let's...
let's get... Let's get you upright.
Thank you.
So, er...
what happened?
I'm disabled.
How?
How what?
How are you disabled?
Er, leg disabled.
So, what... I mean...
Do you have a wheelchair?
Yes.
Where?
Stolen.
Well, how did they get in?
I don't know!
Ah, all right, all right, all right.
Let's get you out of here.
Come on. Come on.
There you go.
There you go. There you go, mate.
All right.
Are you all right? There you go.
< On its way.
< That's all right. Eh, easy now.
Back that way. Nice and steady.
Nice and steady. All right.
Bring him. Easy! Gently!
Careful...careful...
That's it.
< Excuse me, you know
this is a staff toilet.
Yes. I'm staff.
I really am feeling much better.
You can all go now.
We're not going anywhere
until we've got you sorted out.
Ah, there's Paul with the wheelchair.
Oh, right.
What?
I keep one in the office,
for emergencies. Let's get you up.
Nice and gently. That's it.
That's it, there we go.
OK, easy, easy, easy.
There we are, there.
Ooh, the police!
At last.
Everything all right here?
I'm disabled!
So someone stole your...
My wheelchair.
I... I'm disabled.
Some lazy bastard
just waltzed in there.
Can you describe him?
It was all over so quickly.
Well, just tell us what you can.
Caucasian male.
Um, bearded. >
Red hair.
Glasses.
Possibly a disguise, I...
All right. Thank you.
Do you need any help getting home?
No, I'm...
I'm fine, I'm with people.
Here they are now.
Hey, fellas.
Oh, no, I'll take it from here.
Nonsense, it's the least I can do.
OK.
You slacking off in there?
Go and get changed.
'Scuse me, sir,
can I have a word with you?
Amazing! So powerful!
Thanks!
The, mmm... The grit of it!
(IMITATES GUNFIRE)
Five stars!
So what did you think?
Of the musical?
Did you not just love it?
Well...no.
Sorry. >
Why not?
I don't know. It's just...
maybe you have to be...gay.
But I loved it.
Yeah.
I guess it's more of a gay thing.
You know, you have to be gay,
a gay man, a homosexual.
Well, all I know is, I loved every
last second of it, and I'm not...
usually a fan of musicals.
Hey, do you wanna meet the cast?
Come on.
Er, the thing is,
I have to meet Moss and Roy.
Hey, listen, I told the cast about
what happened,
and they told me to get you
all to come back and meet them.
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
Come on everybody, off the van!
Hey, James!
Oh, wow, Edgar. Hi!
Oh, brilliant!
Jeremy!
How do you know all these
young, good-looking men?
Oh, you know, just from around.
< Hey, Jerome!
Come here, you! Great show!
Hello, darling.
Listen, can't talk at the mo,
got a disabled group
coming in for a chat. Here they are.
He's had quite an evening.
Someone stole his wheelchair.
Really?
Did you see who it was?
Red-bearded man.
Uh-huh.
How long have you been disabled?
Ten years.
Ten years. And how did it happen,
if that's not a rude question?
Acid.
What are the chances
of that happening?
100 to one.
You look like you
could do with a drink.
Whisky, please, double.
Excuse me.
Yes, miss.
OK.
Can I have a double whisky, please?
Double whisky.
And a glass of white wine.
Glass of white wine.
Thank you.
You're very welcome, madam.
Hello!
Hello, Laura Knightley.
< How are you?
I'm disabled.
It must be so difficult,
being gay and disabled.
Very difficult.
Oh, come here, my little soldier.
Aw, what's the matter?
I don't know!
You're from telly.
I am.
And do you know, a little birdie
told me that you couldn't make
the show tonight,
so I've got you two tickets
for tomorrow.
Brilliant!
You're doing so well.
Yeah.
High five!
< Laura!
Couple of photos?
Is he from the newspaper?
Yes, he's from The Standard.
Oh, good!
What...? Oh, I... I get it.
Very funny. You Irish!
Oh, I'm a bit tired,
can I have a wheelchair, too?
Ha-ha, hilarious!
"Ooooh, me legs don't work!"
"Help, help, I need a wheelchair!"
Come on, get up!
Come on, stop mucking around.
I want a go!
You take that.
Well, I...
I guess this is goodnight.
Yeah.
Oh, for God's sake, are you gay?
Are you a gay man?
No!
Are you?
No.
No. Brilliant, good, cos that's
all I wanted to know.
I don't mind one way or another,
you know, it's just I like
being clear,
and I don't want any ambiguity.
What on Earth
made you think I was gay?
Well... oh, you know,
I didn't just pull it out of the air.
You know, you've just brought me
to a gay musical called Gay,
been laughing like mad at every
gay reference, your friends...
all of who are gay,
say hello by tickling you.
Jen, what century are you living in?
Do you think that a man has to
be gay to like a gay musical?
Can a straight man not
have homosexual friends?
And since when was tickling gay?
I missed that meeting.
Jen? Jen, come here.
I guess it just threw me when
you borrowed that copy of Heat.
Oh, God, it's true, it's true!
I'm gay.
I'm a gay man. I tried
to run from it, to deny it,
but I can't! I can't! I cannot.
Jen, what am I gonna do?
I thought I could
make it work between us,
because you looked a bit like a man!
Oh, God!
(SOBS BROKENLY)
Taxi!
Hello, there!
I didn't see YOU on the way out!
All right, lads,
let's get a sing-song going.
It's a long way back to Manchester!
# Willies, willies!
I love willies, willies, willies...#
Night, Steve.
Night, Moss.
Night, Milly, you be good.
Not if I can help it!
The theatre!
Subtitles by
Red Bee Media Ltd