[orchestral fanfare]
♪ ♪
[Star Wars theme playing]
[narrator] Homeward bound.
On a peaceful relief mission
to the planet Aleen,
R2-D2 and C-3PO
were caught up in an adventure
beyond their comprehension.
After finally resolving the crisis
and being taken to Jedi Master
Adi Gallia's cruiser,
they now head home
toward the safety of the Republic,
hoping to avoid a Separatist attack.
And, Mistress Padmé,
you would not believe
the adventures R2 and I had
on that troubled planet of Aleen.
We have been
in the most absurd situations
I could never compute.
Well, I told you, 3PO,
it's a big universe out there
beyond the few million
planets you know.
And, obviously, for the most part,
quite uncivilized.
I hope never to end up
on a mission of that nature again.
Good.
I need you here to supervise
the senatorial banquet.
It was pushed up
and is only two days away.
-[rumbling]
-Oh, my!
[beeps]
They've hit the main reactor.
Prepare to evacuate.
[man over P.A.] Nonessential personnel
evacuate immediately.
Nonessential personnel
Did you hear that?
Oh, we've got to get out of here.
It's General Grievous!
R2, where are you going?
We need to find an escape pod.
[man over P.A.]
All pilots to your stations.
All flight crews, man your stations.
[chirps]
R2-D2, get down from there at once.
This is not an escape pod.
Well, if there's nothing better,
I suppose it will just have to do.
-[amused chirp]
-I'm sure I will live to regret it.
Ohhhh!
R2, you should know
I have total confidence
in your skills as a pilot,
uh, provided you can avoid
these star cruisers.
Oh, my!
[whistles]
Avoid them the other way!
R2, do something!
Get us out of here!
They're right behind us!
[chirps]
We've been hit! Oh!
[whirring]
[firing sounds]
Right on target! Oh, well done, R2!
-[alarm blaring]
-Oh, no!
The reactor was hit.
It's shutting down.
We'll disintegrate, for sure!
[whistles]
[crash]
Fixable? This scrap pile?
Without the proper tools,
this ship is utterly useless.
I suppose we could get out
and have a look around.
Ohhh!
Oh, really.
You see, not even a ladder.
Utterly useless! Utterly.
[Patitites 1] Look, look! Over there!
Intruders! Ohhhh!
-It's shiny.
-It's shiny!
-Did you hear that?
-[whistles]
[radar whirring]
Whoever you are, please note
that my counterpart here
is programmed in 47 schools
of self-defense.
[whirs and beeps]
[both whispering in native language]
[beeps]
Hmm. There.
I've frightened them off.
[all ululating]
Fear not, R2.
Just little creatures.
Can't possibly damage us.
[shouting in pain]
Aah!
[beeping, whirring]
Get the big Hay-Zu.
He'll know what to do.
Oh, oh, oh, really! Oh, oh, oh.
May I say that... Oh, oh!
This is no way
to treat friendly visitors
to your planet!
The big Hay-Zu
says there are no friendly visitors.
This Hay-Zu doesn't sound
very reasonable.
Oh, we do what he says,
whatever he says,
for our own good.
Your own good?
He sends our children
to fight his wars...
the lucky ones.
What does he do to the unlucky ones?
[trumpet fanfare]
So you are the intruders.
Intruders?
Oh, hardly, Your, uh, Worshipfulness.
-We are--
-On this planet,
things are what Hay-Zu says they are.
[R2-D2 beeps]
Quiet, R2.
What's this?
Your friend challenges
big Hay-Zu's authority?
Sir, my disagreeable friend here
means no disrespect.
We are just trying to get back
to our home planet.
But our ship is damaged,
and I fear, repaired or not,
that further travel in it
might not result
in our arrival there unscathed.
That's the chance you'll have to take.
Now get off my planet
while I'm in a good mood,
or I'll have you dismembered
and sold for scrap!
Free them!
[beeps angrily]
Ah, big talk for a small droid.
R2, have your senses frozen?
I am not going to let you at him. Hmm.
In fact, I'm going to switch you off
before you cause
an intergalactic incident.
Aah!
Oh, my!
[Patitites gasping]
[Patitites whispering indistinctly]
Dead! He's dead!
The big Hay-Zu is dead!
You... you must understand,
this was an accident,
a terrible accident.
[all chanting] He's dead! He's dead!
The big Hay-Zu is dead!
He's dead! He's dead!
[electricity crackling]
Gold one, we have a proposition.
We wish you not to leave,
but for you to stay...
as our new leader.
[beeps laughingly]
A lot you know,
you overstuffed barrel of bolts.
I could be a leader.
I am honored by your consideration.
But you should choose a leader
from among your own.
None of us has killed Hay-Zu.
None of us have earned the title.
Terminating the big one
does not anoint me leader.
You must choose.
Now, who are the three smartest,
most intelligent,
most understanding,
most compassionate?
You should choose a leader
from among these three.
Who thinks he should be leader?
[all cheering]
And this young lady?
Or, lastly, him?
[loud cheering]
Congratulations.
You are now a democracy.
-I got more votes than he did!
-No, you did not!
-Sit down! It was me! It was me!
-I got the most votes.
No, that's not true!
It was me!
[beeps urgently]
I heartily agree. Is the ship ready?
-[chirps hesitantly]
-Then we'll just have to risk it
and leave them to build
their happy democracy on their own.
I get a vote!
[male Patitite] Down with democracy!
[Patitites screaming]
[beeping]
Yes, I'm reading the gauges.
I have nothing to do but read gauges.
-[chirps]
-Why? What do the gauges say?
-[beeps and whistles]
-Running out of power?
The ship and us, too?
Oh! I knew we should never have left
the Jedi cruiser.
[chirps excitedly]
Another planet?
According to the positional
system coordinates,
this is Balnab,
a stellar remnant
in its emerging stages
of organic development.
Oh! I've heard terrible stories
about these primitive planets.
I dare not imagine
what is beginning to swim
in their primordial soups.
[beeps]
I know we have to find power,
but do we have to find it out there?
-[whistles and chirps]
-Afraid?
Of course I'm not afraid.
[squawking]
I am now.
Quickly, see if your scanners
can find a viable power source.
[radar whirring and beeping]
[chitters]
[3PO] Yes, me too.
-[chirps]
-Life forms?
What kind?
They appear to be humanoid
and completely devoid of intelligence.
[lasers blasting]
R2, make a dash for it!
[hooves thundering]
Aah!
What are they?
Bring them. The leader will know.
Another leader?
Oh! I do hope this one
is more understanding.
[R2-D2 beeps and whirs]
My fault? Oh! I should have known.
[booming voice]
Who dares come to my land?
Just two wandering droids
searching to find their home.
Droids?
What are droids?
Well, kind sir,
droids are mechanical beings
possessing artificial intelligence,
-designed to make it--
-Silence!
At once, uh, Your Sirness.
Being silent is one of my specialties.
[beeps crazily]
Who dares to bring
these nonliving things
before me?
It was I who brought them.
I thought that--
Aah!
[gasps] How unfortunate.
No one thinks here but me!
[beeping urgently]
R2, be quiet.
This situation calls
for my most
delicate diplomatic skills.
Please excuse my insolent friend,
Your Eminence-ness-ness-ness.
But I know a holographic image--
I know not of your blasphemy!
[3PO] Perhaps "holographic"
is the incorrect word
in your native tongue,
but it is obvious
that you are not real.
[meek voice] Not real?
[booming voice]
I'll show you not real!
[electricity crackling]
[beeps]
[meek voice]
Hey, what are you doing back here?
[booming voice] I said,
"What are you doing back here?"
Back where?
[chirping]
[meek voice] Help you?
We're not... Ahh! Ahh!
[clang]
We're not gonna help you.
We worked hard to keep these
mindless organics enslaved.
And if you want to order
someone around, get your own organics.
[whistles and beeps]
Oh, yeah?
And just how is an "astromech unit"
going to make
our loyal subjects rebel?
[whistles angrily]
[garbled, distorted voice]
[R2-D2 beeps urgently]
Uh-oh.
Oh, my!
Hey, get him!
Uh-oh again.
R2, it's time to leave,
but we still need to recharge.
Here they come. They're coming for us!
We're done for!
There goes my empire!
Run for it!
[pit droids shouting]
[groans]
It's all your fault, R2,
all your fault.
Whatever will we do now?
R2, I'm talking to you.
[beeping slowly]
Please don't mumble.
R2, you're almost out of power.
Here, rest.
[chirps weakly]
Me?
I have 1.723% left in my power core.
I thought for sure
you would have figured
something out by now.
You're usually so good
at that sort of thing.
[beeps softly]
[power down whine]
Oh, R2, don't leave me,
please.
Rest, my friend.
[voice distorting]
I will be joining you soon.
[pirate 1] That Republic Y-wing
is a great prize.
[pirate 2] Do you think there are
any Jedi around?
[pirate 1] Don't worry.
We'll be taking off
before anyone realizes we've landed.
What have we here?
Looks like two droids
that ran out of power.
Ah, looky, looky here.
[cackling]
Come to papa.
Here ya go!
[cackles]
Ahhh.
[chortling]
This should be a fun one.
...would rescue us.
Master Anakin?
R2! You're... you're recharged!
I'm recharged.
We survived.
Where are we?
[chirps]
Pirates?
[chuckles, humming]
Oh, my.
[all shouting]
What are they cheering for?
[robotic voice] Ahh.
Ahh!
[3PO] Oh, goodness gracious me!
Soon it will be us.
[grumbling triumphantly]
Oh, my stars!
Oh, no. Whoa!
General, we've come across
what appears to be a pirate ship.
Use that ship for target practice.
Open fire!
All forward cannons, open fire!
Battle stations!
[all cheering]
[3PO] Oh, my! Oh, oh!
Go get him, R2!
[C-3PO screams]
[all screaming]
Oh, no!
We'll never get back to the ship!
We surrender.
We surrender!
Uh, where did you come from?
They must be pirate droids.
Pirate droids?
You're under arrest.
We're not pirate droids.
-We are part of the Republic--
-[beeps]
Oh, yes, uh, we are pirate droids.
That is what we thought.
Send them off to the incinerator room
with the rest of the pirate scum.
The incinerator room?
Yes.
You will be melted down
for General Grievous' war machine.
This is terrible.
No. No.
Aah!
Oh! This trip has been nothing
but calamity all the way.
Thanks for the rescue, Master Plo.
General Grievous has fled.
Very good.
Finish off the remaining droids.
[3PO] We are Republic. Oh!
We belong to Senator Amidala.
Don't shoot. Don't shoot!
I can't believe it.
You know these droids,
Commander Wolffe?
Yes, sir.
We transported them
to Master Gallia's ship
after we left the planet Aleen.
Yes, Commander Wolffe.
How have you been, sir?
We have been on quite an adventure.
Well, I'm certain Wolffe
would love to hear about it.
Uh, a-actually, sir...
Excellent. It's a long story.
-And you won't believe it.
-Uh, sir, excuse me...
I can hardly believe it myself.
It all started...
[orchestral fanfare]
♪ ♪
[Star Wars theme playing]
[R2-D2 beeping]