[orchestral fanfare]
[Star Wars theme playing]
[male narrator]
The Clone Starfleet is under siege.
Dozens of Republic warships
have been destroyed
in merciless surprise attacks
that leave no survivors.
Rumors spread
of a terrible new Separatist weapon.
In the face of growing fear,
the Jedi Council sends Master Plo Koon
to hunt down the Menace
before it strikes again.
[dramatic choral music]
The enemy ship has reduced
its speed, general.
They must have realized
we are tracking them.
We're tracking three Republic cruisers.
-What should we do?
-[roars]
Jam their transmissions.
The fleet is holding its position, sir.
I think it wise to report
our position before we attack.
Skywalker's fleet is nearby,
in the Bith system.
Good. Perhaps he can reinforce us.
From what I hear,
Skywalker's always ready for a fight.
So I've heard.
Koh-to-ya, Master Plo.
Koh-to-ya, little 'soka.
How's the hunt
for the mystery weapon going?
We've tracked it to the Abregado system.
We need reinforcements.
I'll have to ask the council, Master Plo.
I was given strict orders
to protect our staging area.
[static buzzing]
Master Plo, what's happen--?
What is wrong with the transmission?
There's too much interference, sir.
We've lost 'em.
You heard Master Plo.
He needs our support.
We have to go help him.
We have to see
what the Council decides first.
This is an important meeting, Ahsoka.
Remember, be mindful
and speak only when spoken to.
Don't I always.
This mystery weapon
has struck in a dozen systems
and disappeared without a trace.
We cannot afford to lose
any more ships, my friends.
Ah, Master Skywalker.
Have you had any success
in finding General Grievous'
secret weapon?
Master Plo was here in the Abregado system
when we lost contact.
The enemy ship is closing.
Prepare for battle.
[dramatic music]
General Grievous, this will be
a suitable test for our new weapon.
You may fire when ready.
Yes, my lord.
We're picking up a large energy reading
from the target, sir.
Open fire.
We're not in range yet, sir.
Fire!
Brace for impact!
We're losing all our power.
That energy field has left us defenseless!
-Their shields are down.
-All cannons, fire.
They're tearing us apart one by one.
[laughs]
Agh!
Quickly, into the pods!
We don't have much time.
Get inside. Hurry!
Another successful test,
wouldn't you say, count?
We must keep our position secret.
Send out the hunters.
I want all of those lifepods destroyed.
[chuckling]
And we have had no further contact
with General Plo Koon.
The absence of distress beacons
indicates that his fleet was...
That his fleet was destroyed,
like the others.
We are about to prepare a rescue mission.
Hasn't Clone Intelligence reported
this weapon
never leaves any survivors?
The Separatists are being unusually tidy.
They don't want any witnesses.
Tragic are these losses,
but prevent more we must.
The power grid is burned out.
We've no engine, communications,
or... or life support recharge.
So we'll just sit here
and hold our breath.
Someone will come looking for us, right?
Let's get the power restored
so we are here to be found.
All our battle groups will be reassigned
to guard our supply convoys,
including yours, Skywalker.
I'm afraid we can't risk any more ships
with a rescue mission.
Wait!
Just because there haven't
been any survivors before
doesn't mean there won't be any this time.
Boldly spoken for one so young.
She is learning from Anakin.
Excuse my Padawan.
We will deploy
as you have instructed, master.
Ahsoka!
If anyone could survive, Master Plo could.
I don't understand why--
What you don't understand is Jedi protocol
or your place, my young Padawan.
Admiral. [clears throat]
We'll split up our ships
to maximize our defense area.
I'll scout ahead for enemy activity.
Isn't that risky,
with the mystery weapon out there?
It might be, but I know
you won't argue my orders.
Come on, Snips.
The air in here is getting a bit stale.
Don't look at me.
It's Boost, sir.
-He only takes a bath when he's on leave.
-Save it.
Just keep working on the pod,
not your jokes.
Do you think we've got a chance, general?
I don't believe in chance, commander.
I know if we work together,
we will stay alive,
and someone will find us.
With all due respect, general,
strategically, it doesn't make any sense
for someone to come look for us.
If I was in command,
I'd be hunting that weapon down.
I value your life more
than finding that weapon.
Sir, there's another pod out there.
If we only had power,
we could contact them.
Well, how about we just wave "hello"
when the viewport comes around?
They're dead.
Someone busted that pod wide open.
We are not alone out here.
Set those new coordinates, R2?
[beeps]
Master, I should tell you
why I spoke up before.
You don't have to explain anything.
Our ship's in defensive formation, sir.
All right, commander.
I'll check on Anakin's progress.
Admiral, how goes escort?
Oh. Convoys are proceeding
on schedule, general.
No sign of enemy activity.
And where's Skywalker?
Uh, the general felt
a redeployment of this fleet
would increase our defensive perimeter.
I see. Thank you, admiral.
That'll be all.
Problem, sir?
Anakin has just redeployed himself...
again.
[beeps]
R2, set up the scanner.
Modulate for incoming... mystery weapons.
[beeps]
No, R2, tune the scanners
for life-forms,
highest sensitivity.
Why would we scan for life-forms to spot
an enemy weapon probably
just filled with...
battle... droids.
The Abregado system.
Huh.
So it's okay when you don't follow
what the Council says.
Doing what the Jedi Council
says, that's one thing.
How we go about doing it, that's another.
That's what I'm trying
to teach you, my young Padawan.
So you always meant
to come out here for survivors?
Lives are in danger, Ahsoka.
We can't just turn our backs on them.
That's what I said
back in the briefing room.
I know, but the way you said it was wrong.
Hurry up. Switch on the illuminator.
We haven't got much time
before the fleet misses us.
No, that's not it.
This one goes there. That one goes there.
Are you sure?
We don't want to make things worse.
How are we going to make things worse?
When you ask for trouble,
you should not be surprised
when it finds you.
I think trouble already found us, sir.
What if we connect
these two wires right here?
[whirring noise]
I'm getting something.
[man's voice fades in over radio]
We are under attack. Is anyone out there?
It's one of our other pods.
[man over radio]
I repeat, we are under attack.
Is anyone out there?!
That signal is weak.
They must be close by.
[man over radio] They've locked on to
our ship. They've locked on to our ship!
Go get 'em, boys.
[man over radio] Our position
is mark 12 at 0.26.
Let's cut this can open.
I have visual contact.
Pod 1-9-7-7, do you copy?
[man over radio] The droids
are hunting for survivors.
They're cutting through!
[men screaming]
There they go.
Things just got a lot worse.
The scanners are practically useless.
Got anything on the emergency channel, R2?
[beeps]
Now, Ahsoka, we might find something
you don't want to find.
I know, master. But I have to believe.
How do you know Master Plo, anyway?
He's one of my oldest friends.
It was Master Plo Koon
who found me and brought me
to the temple where I belonged.
Now he's lost, so I thought
maybe I could find him.
[beeps]
Incoming transmission, master.
I think someone noticed we're gone.
Anakin, where are you?
Oh, hello, master.
Uh, we made a quick stop
in the Abregado system.
A rescue mission, I suppose.
You had other orders.
It was my idea, Master Obi-Wan.
Oh, I'm sure.
Well, have you found any survivors?
No, you were right.
The Separatists don't want any witnesses.
All the more reason for you
to rejoin the defensive escorts.
We need you, Anakin.
You're going to miss the rendezvous
with the fleet if you don't hurry.
I know, master. We're on our way.
I'm sorry, Ahsoka.
[beeps]
-What is it, R2?
-[beeping]
R2 thinks he's got something
on the emergency channel.
-Can he trace it?
-[beeps excitedly]
Let's get going.
I think they see us.
Corporal, there's another pod over there.
[humming "The Imperial March"]
It is time to go.
Go? Where are you going, sir?
Outside, to destroy the enemy.
I can withstand the pressure
for a brief time.
Put your helmets on.
If you say so, sir.
This is a difficult situation,
but there remains a possibility
we will survive.
That's good enough for me.
Come on, let's go.
[machinery whirring]
[reverberating thud]
Wolffe, keep
the communications signal alive.
It is our only chance
someone will find us.
Let's just hope someone's looking for us.
[beeps]
Are we still picking up that signal?
-Yes, but why aren't we finding anybody?
-I don't know, Ahsoka.
I don't know.
Well, this looks like the last one.
Let's finish the job.
Hey, what's a Jedi doing out here?
[lightsaber whooshes]
Take cover!
Is there anyone out there?
This is Ahsoka Tano.
Can anyone hear me?
I can't get a clear shot!
Time to put the squeeze on them.
[metal creaking]
[Ahsoka over radio]
Is there anyone out there?
Come in. This is Ahsoka Tano.
Is there anyone out there? Come in.
It's Ahsoka.
-She must be close.
-Keep the signal alive, commander.
-R2, see if you can boost the reception.
-[beeping]
Ugh!
Patience. We're trying to boost
the power. Hang on.
We're losing the signal.
The pod can't take much more damage.
Sinker, your turn.
I'm on it, boss.
Whoa!
What the...?
Eat laser, clankers.
[droid] Uh-oh.
Sir, we have lost contact
with the pod hunter.
Perhaps some survivors
are putting up a fight.
That is something we cannot allow.
We must find a way
to destroy this mystery weapon.
In this war, a step ahead of us
Dooku always seems.
Tell me,
has there been any word
from Master Plo Koon or his fleet?
No, we must fear the worst.
Actually, I just received word
that Anakin has found
the remains of Master Plo's fleet
and is searching the debris for survivors.
On whose authority has he done this?
His own, I'm afraid.
With his fleet out of position,
we are left vulnerable.
Oh, his fleet is right where it should be.
He's taken only a small ship
and his Padawan.
Twice the trouble they have become.
A reckless decision Skywalker has made.
Let us hope it is not a costly one.
Well, general, this is
another fine mess we've gotten into.
Your sense of humor is improving.
I don't mean to say I told you so,
but I never believed anyone
would come looking for us.
Anakin, the Council is furious.
Why have you left your post?
I decided we couldn't just
give up on Master Plo Koon.
A noble gesture, Anakin.
But the Council feels your daring
may put others in danger.
Please listen to me, Anakin.
Return at once.
[Anakin] Yes, Excellency.
Time to go, Ahsoka.
We have to stay.
Ahsoka, I want to believe
Master Plo's alive,
-but I just--
-I know he's alive!
-I can sense it.
-Ahsoka!
[screeching]
Sergeant, why are you
so certain no one is coming?
We're just clones, sir.
We're meant to be expendable.
Not to me.
-There they are!
-Ready tow cable.
Cable loaded, master.
[grunting]
Come on, hurry.
Are you okay, Master Plo?
There's someone in the pod.
[coughing]
Will they be all right?
The pressure suits offer some protection,
but they require a medical frigate
for recovery.
I will stabilize them, sir.
Your men are safe now.
Tell me, were there any survivors?
We couldn't find anybody else.
The hunters must have destroyed the rest.
I'm sorry, Master Plo.
We tracked the mystery weapon
to this system.
That is when we found out
it was an ion cannon.
An ion cannon?
A weapon that neutralizes
all power to our ships,
leaving the targets defenseless.
There's a massive vessel approaching.
Shut down the power systems
before they detect us.
[beeps]
The droid!
[beeps questioningly]
Sorry, little guy.
[dramatic music]
That is one big cruiser-crusher.
There's still no signal
from the pod hunter.
Reduce speed and activate your scanners.
We will find who is responsible.
Hey, what's with the lights?
Power has gone out.
Maybe that ship has returned.
We should get up to the bridge.
[groans]
You are too weak.
Let me go see what is wrong.
We are picking up
a faint signal from a droid,
not one of ours.
They're right behind us.
[roars]
Move us into attack position.
They're coming back.
Are all the systems shut down?
Is there a problem, sir?
We forgot to shut off the medical droid.
We've got to get the power back on now.
-Can I be of assistance?
-No, thanks.
Just get in the back
and take care of the clones.
That is my programming, sir.
[Anakin] Come on,
we've got to get out of here.
[Ahsoka] I know. I know.
Sir, the enemy is attempting to flee
through the debris field.
General, I don't want any witnesses.
Energize plasma rotors.
R2, program the navi-computer.
Be ready to get us out of here.
You forgot. We turned him off.
[beeping]
Koh-to-ya, droid.
Target range almost locked, sir.
They're not going to make it.
R2, program the hyperdrive.
[beeps questioningly]
Anywhere. Hurry!
Enemy ship targeted, general.
Fire!
Master?
[beeps]
We're clear.
[roars]
Now the Republic will learn
of our ion cannon.
Your failure is most unfortunate.
I will have to discuss this
with my master.
-[growls]
-[screams]
-Get back to work.
-Roger, roger. Roger, roger.
Thanks for getting us out of there
in one piece, General Skywalker.
You have my Padawan to thank for that.
She always said
you guys would pull through.
General Plo said
someone would come for us.
We're glad he was right.
Skywalker, it is time to give our report
to the Council.
Right, the Council report.
[beeps]
Come on, Ahsoka.
You want me there?
I' figured, because of before--
Ahsoka... through it all,
you never gave up.
You did a great job.
But if I'm getting in trouble for this,
you're gonna share some of the blame too.
[laughs] So come on. Let's go.
Right beside you, Skyguy.
[beeps]
[orchestral fanfare]
[Star Wars theme playing]
[R2-D2 beeping]