[orchestral fanfare]
[Star Wars theme playing]
[male announcer]
The Clone War threatens
the unity of the Republic.
As battles rage across the galaxy
more worlds succumb
to the seductive lure of the Separatists
and leave the Republic.
On a vital mission of peace,
Senator Padmé Amidala
journeys to the Outer Rim world of Rodia,
desperate to ensure its loyalty
remains to the Republic.
Senator Amidala, I just received word
that you have ventured
through enemy territory
into the Outer Rim.
Senator Farr requested me
personally, chancellor.
His planet is in crisis.
His people are starving.
He's a very old family friend.
I could not refuse his plea for help.
I understand,
but in these dangerous times,
you should be accompanied
by a clone escort.
This is a mission of peace.
I put my faith in diplomacy.
We can't solve all of our problems
by throwing troops at them.
Yousa no needin' to worry, chancellor.
-As resempative of Nab--
-Jar Jar, look out!
[engines roaring]
-Whoa!
-Ooh!
[engines decelerating]
What is happening?
May I recommend that only
those who are qualified
for these delicate peace talks
participate in them?
I will follow your advice, chancellor.
Thank you.
Lookee, lookee, it's a swamp
planet just like home.
Meesa have to get going.
Jar Jar, you would be
doing me a great favor
by staying with the ship.
Meesa knowing meesa be big help
with the negotiations.
I need you to watch over 3PO.
You know how he always
gets himself into trouble.
Trouble, me? Really?
I won't be long.
Meesa understands, my lady.
His Excellency, Ah-Twa.
H'chu apenkee, o' diogran,
Tor-sene-ko Farr.
Chowbaso.
Oh, I've missed you so much.
I was afraid you might not come.
We are such a small and humble system.
Uncle Ono, you are very important to me.
We've been friends
since I was a little girl,
when you were my father's
strongest ally in the Senate.
Rodia is very important to the Republic,
and of course, I'd come to help you.
You speak of friendship
I have not witnessed of late.
Where was the Republic
when our supply ships
were destroyed by pirates?
Where was the Republic
as my people starved?
We have been stranded out here
without any help at all.
I know it is not your fault,
but my people starve all the same.
I'm sure the Republic Senate
will approve a relief effort.
The vote was postponed,
but you will get your food.
I am sorry. It is too late, my sweet.
The Separatist leader Nute Gunray
has promised to support us
with a very generous relief effort.
Neh-soo-bo-wah.
He is giving us food, ships
and protection.
Nute Gunray cannot be trusted.
He will bring war to your system
just as he did to mine many years ago.
I am afraid I have already done
what I must for my people.
[approaching footsteps]
Viceroy. I should have known.
You won't get away this time, senator.
Your friend made a deal with me,
and you are part of it.
3PO, come in, 3PO.
-Stop her.
-Three--
No one can help you now.
I am so sorry, my sweet. I had no choice.
There's always a choice.
To live in fear is no life at all.
Take her away!
Please, Uncle Ono, don't do this.
You have made a wise decision, senator.
I will be there within the hour
to bring food for your people
and collect my prize.
[roaring, farting]
How rude!
I'm afraid the local swamp life
doesn't have a very high opinion of us.
Whaten dey speaking?
I couldn't possibly repeat it.
Ah, theesa swamp dwellers just like meesa.
I will convince them
of our good fellowship.
Do be careful, Jar Jar.
I don't think they're quite
like your friends on Naboo.
[low guttural noises]
[speaking alien language]
Meesa make contact.
Oh, dear.
[speaking alien language]
[low guttural noises]
Oh!
I don't think that requires translation.
[low guttural noises]
Thisen is a different swamp altogether.
Sorry.
Oh, my stars. Battle droids.
Weesa in trouble now.
Stop where you are.
Wait for me!
Uh-oh.
Oops!
Jar Jar, you great webfoot,
you're squashing my circuits.
Blast 'em.
[blasters firing]
Wait, where are you going?
Oh, no! I'll be crushed for sure.
Hang on, Three-So!
-It's 3PO.
-Oops.
That was close.
What are you doing?
Get me down at once.
Whoa!
-[blasters firing]
-Whoa!
It's not too late.
Uncle Ono, you can stop this madness.
Keep moving, prisoner.
Oh, look out, Jar Jar.
A crab droid is headed right for you.
Headed for meesa?
Yes, yousa!
[blasters firing]
No, Jar Jar, go to your left. Behind you.
-[Jar Jar screams]
-Whoa!
Whoa!
-Watch out.
-Whoa!
I can't bear to watch.
-[Jar Jar screams]
-Jar Jar!
[scream fades]
Oh, no. Jar Jar's been killed.
I knew something like this would happen.
What a horrible way to die,
and it's all my fault.
He was so brave. Now he's gone forever.
Meesa OK.
Jar Jar, you're alive.
Meesa OK, 3-So. Meesa OK.
Well, if you've finished
messing around, I need help.
[beep]
[loud crash]
Ouch!
Jar Jar, kindly don't do that.
But meesa save-ed you.
[beep]
[mechanical whirring]
Oh, dear.
Well, that's the end of our ship. Typical.
Are those chains necessary?
Welcome to the Separatist way, senator.
Viceroy Gunray's orders.
I hope it's worth it to you.
Thisa one big mess.
Weesa going nowhere.
Perhaps we should try
to contact the clone troopers.
Oh, lookee.
Here's a button that's still working.
[beep]
What did you break now?
Meesa doing nothing.
Thatsa looken like a Jedi robe.
Whosa you supos'n this belongs to?
I wouldn't, um, know.
But our only hope is to hide
in this closet
until Mistress Padmé returns.
If those droids attackin' us,
Padmé's probably in trouble.
My lady gave us very specific
instructions to remain here.
Oh, fiddlesticks.
We musta hafta try and savin' her.
Jar Jar Binks, have you
gone completely mad?
You'll do more harm than good.
Viceroy Gunray,
goo-bee un-un hah-tah.
Good. I shall meet
the viceroy when he lands.
What about Senator Amidala's companions?
Saw-yed ree-wah, nahga-vee-to ko.
If there are no signs of her friends,
they must have fled into the jungle.
Yes, this is perfect.
I want no sign of trouble.
Our people need those supplies.
Wait. Meesa eyeball's stuck in the sleeve.
Just look at you.
Something's wrongo here.
The battle droids will surely
capture you, or worse, me.
Not with thisa on.
Theysa won't be recognizing me.
You can't be serious.
Come on, 3-So, we can do it.
I have a very bad feeling about this.
The citizens of Rodia
welcome you, viceroy.
Where is Senator Amidala?
Awaiting your arrival, as promised.
Excellent.
I do not wish to keep her waiting.
Shall we go?
We are holding the senator
in the detention tower.
I hope it is not too painful for her.
Sheesa up in that tower?
Weesa got to rescuin' her.
And how precisely
do you propose to do that?
Look, a Jedi.
We're doomed.
A Jedi?
Jedi? Where's a Jedi?
I do believe they mean you.
Meesa not a Jedi.
Kill the Jedi.
Don't shoot, we surrender. We surrender.
Ah! Forget surrender. Weesa run.
Jar Jar.
Is he dead?
The Jedi got away.
He slipped through this grate
and went underwater.
Sound the alarm. Find that Jedi.
I can see you're busy,
so I'll just be going now.
And take that Republic droid scum
to the dismantling center.
Dismantling center?
Oh, wait. Wait, I'm innocent.
I'm innocent, I tell you.
[low rumble]
[screams]
[growling]
Let's find that Jedi.
-Roger, roger.
Roger, roger.
Take me to Senator Amidala at once.
There's a bad boogie monster
down there, you betcha.
Don't be fearing, Padmé. Meesa coming.
[beeping]
Better watch out.
There's a Jedi on the loose.
[both] Uh-oh.
You know, you will soon be destroyed.
I can't tell you how many times
I've seen battle droids
sliced in half by a lone Jedi.
Quiet, you.
All right, cut the chatter.
I want you troops to go outside
and secure the perimeter.
[Padmé] You made it! I'm rescued at last.
Hurry, before the battle droids
figure out what's happening.
[clinking]
Quiet in there.
[Padmé] Thank you.
Let's get out of here, Master Jedi.
Jedi?
There's no Jedi in here.
Wait, there's no prisoner in here.
How did she do that?
-[grunts]
-[shouting]
-[blaster fires]
-Where's the alarm button?
Oh!
I am a protocol droid,
fluent in over six million forms of--
Quiet.
-3PO.
-Mistress Padmé!
Oh, thank the Maker you're safe.
Have you--?
Where's Jar Jar?
Well, I'm afraid he went to rescue you.
Hmm.
Well, what about the Jedi?
There is no Jedi.
It appears the battle droids
have mistaken Jar Jar for one.
That's not good.
Hang on, my lady.
This is our chance to capture
Viceroy Gunray,
but I need you to stay calm.
Go back to the ship and call for help.
I regret the transmitters
on the ship are out of order.
-What?
-The ship has been destroyed.
-Battle droids?
-No.
-Jar Jar?
-Jar Jar.
All right, then find a communications room
and send out a distress signal.
Hopefully, there are some
clone ships within range.
I'll track down Jar Jar.
Viceroy Gunray, when can we
expect the supplies to arrive?
My people are starving.
They haven't arrived yet?
I'm sorry.
Your request will be
taken into consideration
after Senator Amidala's execution.
Execution? You can't.
She's a prisoner of war. We were promised.
You are under my protection now,
and you will do what I demand of you.
Gunray, muh-skee-oh-tee.
Padmé was right.
I have made a grave mistake
joining with the Separatists.
Cho-aht-dee-vah-tay.
I know. I know.
We must appease Viceroy Gunray
so he does not destroy us all.
Be on alert for that Jedi.
He is our only hope.
Bring Senator Amidala before me.
Um, she caused a great deal
of damage to our droids,
and she escaped, sir.
-Escaped?
-It's the Jedi!
-Sir!
-Shoot him!
Ah, whoa!
Wha-ha!
Thisa rescuin' is hard jobbin'.
Whoa!
Jar Jar!
Capture her!
[blasters firing]
[beeping]
[muffled explosion]
Oh, dear.
Uh...
The Jedi has been spotted
in the south hall.
Let's move.
Roger, roger.
I think that was rather clever.
Sir, over there!
The Jedi is escaping.
Not likely.
[blasters firing]
[roars]
-Freeze.
-Surrender.
Where did she go?
What the--?
[explosion]
Jar Jar... no.
Senator Amidala.
So good to see you at last.
Hello? I say, is anyone there?
Why is there never an R2 unit
when you need one?
This is a restricted frequency.
Who is this?
-I am C-3PO, human-cyborg--
-No droids.
This code is for military use only.
This is a priority message
from Senator Amidala on Rodia.
-We require immediate assist--
-Hold it.
Oh, oh, dear.
You're under arrest.
So you didn't find the Jedi, then?
You got him, boss.
Too bad you can't take out
that slug monster.
[belch]
Yousa OK, Bogey?
Yousa save-ed me. Yousa my new palo.
[affectionate grumbling]
Mistress Padmé, oh,
were you able to find Jar Jar?
I think Jar Jar's dead, 3PO.
Not again. Oh, poor Jar Jar.
He was always such a misfit.
I want to make sure this time.
Don't do this, viceroy.
I beg you, do not kill her.
There must be another way.
Silence!
I say, I think there has been
some horrible mistake.
I am a protocol droid on a diplomatic--
Ready!
Aim.
It's the Jedi!
It's the J-J-Je--
Jedi.
Release the senator.
Uh, that Jedi is going to attack.
Shoot him! Shoot them all!
Whoa!
[shouting]
That Jedi has summoned a monster.
[roaring]
We have to get out of here.
[blaster fires]
[gasps]
Whoa!
[roars]
I made a very good friend.
Hold it right there, viceroy.
At last, we can finish this.
Onaconda, it is about time.
Blast that Jedi and shoot her!
Uncle Ono, I think it's time
to tell the viceroy
about our little secret,
how you never meant to leave the Republic
and how you truly care
what's best for your people.
What is she talking about?
Sorry, viceroy, she is right.
I am with the Republic,
and you are under arrest.
You will pay for this treachery.
Viceroy, you are going to spend
the rest of the war in a cell.
Your victory will be fleeting, senators.
[engines rumbling]
Those are Republic warships.
The clones have arrived.
We got your message, general.
What are your orders?
My message got through.
Take this Separatist scum away.
Master Bombad...
on behalf of the people of Rodia,
I thank you.
You're either the bravest
or the most foolish Jedi I have ever met.
I'm just a Gungan,
and I don't think I'm either.
Well, I think you're a...
a little bit of both.
Senator Amidala has brought
your people's needs
to my attention, and I have already sent
a convoy of supply ships to your system.
Thank you, chancellor.
The capture of Viceroy Gunray
is a major victory for the Republic.
All of you should be commended
for your courage
and from what I hear,
especially you, Representative Binks.
Ah, it'sa nothing.
[grumbles]
Can you ever forgive me, Padmé?
It is the Republic that should be asking
your forgiveness, my old friend.
Far too often, we forget
that our most important allies
are not always the most powerful.
[roars]
[orchestral fanfare]
[Star Wars theme playing]
[R2-D2 beeping]