This programme contains adult humour
Hope this doesn't embarrass you, Jen,
but I find the best thing to do
with a new employee is to size them
up with a long, hard stare.
So! So.
First day? Yes.
Scary. Yes.
Don't be scared.
Well, I'm not really scared.
You should be.
Well, I am a little bit scared.
Well, don't be.
Make up your mind.
So here you are.
Yes, really looking forward to
getting to grips with the...
I'm going to put you in IT,
because you said on your CV you have
a lot of experience with computers.
I did say that on my CV, yes.
I have a lot of experience of the
whole computer thing, you know,
e-mails, sending e-mails, receiving
e-mails and deleting e-mails.
Um, I could go on.
Do.
The web.
Using mouse. Mouses, using mice.
Um, clicking, double clicking,
the computer screen, of course.
The keyboard, the bit that
goes on the floor down there.
The hard drive?
Correct.
Aha, well, you certainly seem to
know your stuff. That's settled.
Got a good feeling about you, Jen,
and they need a new manager.
Oh, fantastic. So the people I'll
be working with, what are they like?
Standard nerds.
PHONE RINGS
RINGING CONTINUES
Hello, IT.
Have you tried
turning it off and on again?
OK, well, the button on
the side, is it glowing?
Yeah, you need to turn it on.
The button turns it on.
Yeah, yeah. You do know how
a button works, don't you?
No, not on clothes.
Hello, IT.
Yeah-huh.
Have you tried forcing
an unexpected reboot?
No, no, there you go. No, there
you go, I just heard it come on.
No, no, that's the music
you hear when it comes on.
No, that's the music you hear when...
I'm sorry, are you from the past?
See, the driver hooks the function
by patching the system call table,
so it's not safe to unload it unless
another thread's about
to jump in there and do its stuff
and you don't want to end up
in the middle of invalid memory.
Hello?
Oh, really? Really, well, why don't
you come down here and make me, then!
Huh? What, you think I'm afraid
of you? I'm not afraid of you,
you can come down here any time
and I'll be waiting for you.
That told her.
Oh, God, it's about time you
got back. It's been all go.
You had a job?
Girl on fifth.
Did you and her hit it off?
Define "hit it off"?
Did she continue talking to you
once you'd fixed her computer?
No.
And while I was working on it,
she rested a cup on my back.
No?
Yeah.
Unbelievable.
Yeah, they've no
respect for us up there.
No respect whatsoever.
We're all just drudgeons to them.
Yes, if there were
such a thing as a drudgeon,
that is what we'd be to them.
It's like they're pally wally
when there's a problem
with their printer but once it's
fixed...
They toss us away
like yesterday's jam.
Yes. Yesterday's jam.
That is what we are to them.
TELEPHONE RINGS
You know, actually that
doesn't really work as a thing.
Because jam lasts for ages.
Hello, IT.
Have you tried turning
it off and on again?
Unisex toilets.
You have unisex toilets.
Like Ally McBeal.
That's the sort of
place this is, Jen.
A lot of sexy people not doing
much work and having affairs.
Wow. Oh, my God, look at that view.
I feel like I'm on top of the world.
Well, Jen, this is where I leave you.
'Floor 34.'
Very exciting.
OK, where am I going?
All the way down to the basement.
Good luck.
'Get out of the lift.
Get out of the lift.
'Get out of the lift.'
Oh, won't be a tick.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Oh, God. OK.
Hello?
Yes, I believe it was
Tolstoy who said...
Oh, it seems we have a visitor.
I'm sorry, myself and Maurice
were just engaged
in quite a serious discussion about
books and such.
We didn't hear you come in.
Wait a second, you said it
was Tolstoy who said what?
Oh, never mind that now, Maurice.
When have you read Tolstoy?
Shut up, Maurice.
Why are you speaking in
that weird voice? When did...?
I don't remember this conversation
at all.
(LAUGHS)
Don't let me disturb
you, I just wanted to...
Oh, don't be silly...
Many people come down here to visit.
What are you talking about?
Who comes down? What people?
Why are you giving me the
secret signal to shut up?
So what can we do you for?
I'm the new head of this department.
Is this my office?
Why?
What did she...
Did she just say what...?
I am the head of this department!
I thought I was.
Well, it's one of us, certainly
not her. I'm going to sort this out.
Roy, you've got a head wound there.
Head wound!
I don't want to be rude or anything
but I wasn't informed of any
changes to this department.
Oh, did they not tell you about me?
No
and we are perfectly fine down here,
thank you very much, we're more than
capable of taking care of ourselves.
Sure, sure.
You know you're covered in blood.
Moss.
Amazon thingy.
Oh, wicked. I know what this is,
it's the new Harry Potter.
I got the
child edition and the adult edition
just to check that there are
no differences in the text.
Sorry, but I'm not going to be
able to deal with that woman!
Is nobody else gonna get the
phone? I'll get it.
No, that is not a phone.
I'm going to have a little lie down.
KNOCKING
Come in.
Yeah, Denholm, yeah, yeah.
No, no, no, no, no.
No, they've been fine so far.
Yeah,
I think we're going to get on great.
Yeah, I know.
All right then, no, you take care.
All right, yeah, I will, yeah.
OK, OK, take care, take care.
OK, bye! Bye!
So, hello. What can I do you -
what can I do for you?
Hello. I was just wondering, do you
want me to connect up your phone?
No, no, no, no, no, no,
it's working.
Um,
I was just talking to Denholm there.
But how?
Would you mind, would you mind
closing the door for me?
Oh, yeah, sure.
Yeah, from the other side.
Of course.
Like this?
That's it.
With me on the...
Thanks.
Oh.
Are you all right?
Oh, yes, Moss, I'm fine.
The nurse said I didn't do
myself any serious damage.
I'm standing over here.
I know, I know, I'm joking. I'm fine.
What are we going to do about her?
Well, I just went in and she was
having a pretend conversation.
Really?
Yes, she's a little bit
weird to say the least.
What's that?
Oh, just water. Sometimes I get a
hot ear and this helps cool it down.
She's quite the oddball.
Did you notice how she didn't
even get excited
when she saw this original ZX81?
Yeah, that was weird.
It's almost as if she doesn't
know anything about computers.
What?
CRASHING
What are you doing?
Oh, don't worry, that's why
I always make two cups of tea.
Anyway, what were we talking about?
Oh, her not knowing
anything about computers.
What?
CRASHING
< We definitely want to
get rid of her.
OK, so here's the plan.
A plan. Let me put on my
slightly larger glasses.
OK, hit me.
OK we go in.
When?
You know, like in a minute.
Will that be enough time for
me to get to know the plan?
Yeah you know what, I shouldn't
have used the word "plan".
I've gotten you over-excited.
Would "scheme" be a better word?
Although that's just as exciting,
I might even need these.
All I was going to
say was, um, we go in,
I make up a load of bollocks
about computers
and we'll see
if she picks up on it.
Yes, I can see why you didn't
want to use the word "plan".
Let me do the talking.
All right.
Ooh, Moss, Moss.
OK, we need to get this right, yeah?
We need to stay calm.
We do not want to
go in there half cocked.
OK...
Hang on, guys. >
How can I help?
Well, we were just wondering,
now that you're the "boss".
Would you like us to
access the data supplier
and connect you to the matrix?
You just made all that up.
You don't know anything
about computers, admit it!
Will you stop
trying to undermine me!
Now get in there and do some
work to do with computers.
I'll be in there in a
minute to check up on you.
OK lady, you've won this round.
But we can wait.
You will slip up, and believe you me,
we will be there when you do.
There will be some piece of evidence
that will prove that you don't
know anything about computers.
What are you doing?
Plugging in your computer.
It might be something
you say or something you do,
but when we notice it,
and believe me we will notice it,
it's going to be a long way down
for you sweet cheeks!
He'll realise in a second.
Ah-hhh!
I cannot believe
you're going to tell on me.
You're like a pair
of horrible old women.
What did she say?
She said we're like
horrible old women.
She didn't!
Hey guys. I hear you've got
something to tell me.
Yes, well it's like this.
Look at you, my IT team.
Yeah.
Team players each
and every one of you.
Yeah well she...
There's no room for people who
can't act in a team on my team.
PHONE RINGS
Excuse me. Hello?
What? Well, if you can't work
as a team you're all fired.
That's it, you heard me, fired.
Get your things and go.
Hello, security?
Everyone on floor four is fired.
Escort them from the
premises and do it as a team.
If you're a team and if you can't
act as a team you're fired too!
Dawn, get on to recruitment.
Get them to look for a security
team that can work as a team.
They may have to escort the current
security team from the building
for not acting like a team.
Team. Team. Team. Team. Team. Team.
I even love saying the word team.
You probably think that's a
picture of my family.
Uh-uh, it's the A-Team.
Bodie, Doyle, Tiger, the Jewellery
Man, the whole lot of them.
So what do you want to tell me?
Well, it's just not working out!
He's joking.
But you said...
Not working out?
Oh, no! We are getting on
like a big house on fire.
Yes.
My ear's getting hot.
You know what we should leave now
because you're a busy man and we've
taken up far too much of your time.
Jen, could you just get
the door for me there?
Absolutely, Roy.
So why did you come here?
We set up a voice activation
system on your computer.
I think you're going to enjoy it.
It might just take a little while
to get the pitch right on the voice,
but nonetheless, go ahead.
Thank you, bye bye.
Thank you. How exciting.
Hello.
Hello, computer.
But what good are you? You obviously
don't know anything about computers.
No, but OK, but I can learn.
You know, I mean for example, Moss,
you could take me through
what you're doing right now.
I'd be delighted.
I'm just working on a very simple
piece of programming code...
FUZZY CRACKLING
I see.
Oh, God, no, I'm lying again.
I didn't understand any of that, I
don't know anything about computers.
I'm absolutely useless to you, I
might as well pack up and go home.
Hi, is Roy around?
Hello there, little lady.
Are you lost?
How can I help you? I'm Roy.
You wanted me to come down, huh?
Well, here I am.
Oh, not the face! Not the face!
Yes, well maybe this will teach you
to treat people
with a little it of respect!
Is there any chance
we spoke on the phone earlier?
Oh, my God are those Manolos?
Oh, yes...
They are gorgeous.
Were they expensive?
No, no, no got them in a sale.
Oh, clever you. I'm never lucky
enough to get a bargain like that.
I should take you shopping.
That would be fun.
Oh, I'll give you a call.
Nice to meet you. Take care.
Nice meeting you!
Chairman Wow! You just defused
that entire situation.
What situation?
Oh that, yeah, oh my God
does that happen a lot?
They're fairly regular
the beatings, yes.
I'd say we're on a
bi-weekly beating.
Oh, it's not all that bad.
Oh, come on Roy, it's pretty bad.
Maybe I could help with this.
I mean, I am a people person
and people like you need
a person to deal with people.
Oh, my God, ideas are coming,
things are happening here.
OK, what would you say
if I told you that I had a plan
to raise your profile upstairs
by 100%, what would you say?
It can't be done, you're crazy.
What would you say, Roy?
Roy's passed out.
OK, I need a felt tip pen
and some paper.
# THEME TUNE TO THE A-TEAM
LAUGHTER
No, no!
Really, really it was
a true story, unbelievable.
I don't know why we don't go out
with you IT guys. You're hilarious!
Yes, we are!
Well, you guys should come
down here more often, you know.
You should see this as a new
era for Reynholm Industries.
New era for Reynholm Industries.
Oh, God, you know if you want
to hear something really funny,
you should hear what happened
to Moss and I
when we were so drunk in Amsterdam
that Moss lost his glasses. Moss!
Moss! Come here, come here.
Tell them that story about
when we were drunk in Amsterdam.
Really?
Yeah, this is brilliant.
I'm just going to get
another box of wine.
Well, go on then.
All right.
Well, one night
we were really drunk.
Yeah.
And we were so drunk that we
decided to hire prostitutes.
When they arrived at the hotel
we were too scared to do anything
so we brought them to a fair.
They were really nice. In the end
they only charged us half,
but we did have to pay
for all the rides.
Ha, ha! Isn't that just
the best story!
Oh, no.
You told me never to
tell that story to anyone.
What are you talking about,
that's a brilliant story,
Then you nearly walked
into the canal...
Oh! You mean the story
where I lost my glasses.
Yes.
What story did you think I meant?
Moss?
What did you say? What did you say?
It's all right for you two,
you're used to
being social piranhas.
I'm a very popular person usually.
That girl earlier that tried to
beat me to death with her shoes.
Did anybody get her number?
That was a nice day
at the fair, wasn't it?
With Brandy and Crystal.
PHONE RINGS
Hello, IT.
Yeah, have you tried
turning it off and on again?
Hello! Hello!