[orchestral fanfare]
♪ ♪
[Star Wars theme playing]
[narrator] Counterattack!
With the Clone army stretched
in a desperate attempt
to engage General Grievous' starfleet,
Separatist planets
that were once thought secure
are now rising up against the Republic.
On Geonosis, Separatist leader
Poggle the Lesser,
safe in his newly
ray-shielded factories,
creates thousands of terrible
new weapons
which march off the assembly line
against the outnumbered Clone army.
The Jedi, resolute in their effort
to restore order to the Republic,
mount a massive invasion
to retake Geonosis
and shut down Poggle's
factories of terror once and for all.
I cannot believe we're back here again.
It is unfortunate.
The resistance from the native Geonosians
was stronger than we anticipated.
The same can be said
for their loyalty to Count Dooku.
A fact that is often overlooked.
You're late.
Sorry, Master.
Ahsoka and I were busy routing
the Seppies near Dorin.
My squadron alone had 55 kills.
Yeah, but mine had 76.
Show-off.
Well, I'm glad you two
are enjoying yourselves.
Hey, it's just a little
friendly competition, Master.
Nothing to worry about.
What I worry about is the way this war
seems to be drawing out
with no end in sight.
Which is why it is crucial
our invasion of Geonosis
meets with success.
Agreed.
Ahsoka, contact the Outer Rim Command.
We're ready for our briefing.
They're already waiting for us.
Our ships are in position,
and we are ready to begin our campaign
against the Geonosians.
And what about Poggle?
Any report on his location?
It seems he's holed up
at the primary droid foundry here.
The factory is protected
by a shield generator.
Anakin, Ki-Adi, and I
shall attempt a three-pronged attack
through their defense lines to
a staging area just short of the shield.
Once we have landed,
we shall knock out the shield generator.
That is our primary target.
Isn't it risky committing three generals
to one area of the attack?
If something went wrong,
we could be dealt a serious blow.
To ensure that rise again
Geonosis does not,
capture Poggle we must.
Of course.
As always, I shall leave
the strategy to you, Master Jedi.
Our thanks, Chancellor.
May the Force be with you.
Good, Cody.
These are the coordinates
for the rendezvous.
[Cody] Yes, sir.
When we hit the ground,
we'll create a perimeter there.
Getting past their defenses here
will be the trick.
General Mundi will come across
the defensive lines from the north.
We will make our assault
through the middle.
General Skywalker will make his attack
on the defensive lines from the south,
and we will meet at the rendezvous point
at 0700 exactly.
If we meet with strong resistance
and are forced down away
from the landing zone,
hold out until we join our forces
before attacking the shield generator.
Their front lines are heavily fortified.
Look at that giant wall
with all the gun emplacements.
That won't be easy to get past.
Don't worry. We're not going
anywhere near that.
Come now.
What happened
to all the enthusiasm I saw earlier?
Don't worry about us.
You just make sure you get yourself
to that landing zone in one piece.
Yes. I shall be waiting for you
when you finally arrive.
Gentlemen, if you are quite finished,
we have a battle to begin.
Quite right.
Cody, prep the gunships.
I'll meet you in the hangar.
Yes, sir.
[engines whooshing]
No, sir, I wasn't involved
in the first assault on Geonosis.
Well, you didn't miss much.
Last time, I was chained to a pole
and attacked by several
humongous monsters.
That sounds... entertaining.
It was... for the Geonosians.
[engines whirring]
[energy cannons firing]
[engines whooshing]
[explosions]
-We all ready, Rex?
-Yes, sir.
General Kenobi is already under way.
Well, he's got a head start.
We'll have to catch up.
Good luck, General.
There is no such thing as luck.
[engines whirring]
Good thing those bugs can't aim.
[explosion]
[booming crash]
The flak is too heavy.
[on radio] We're down. Repeat, down.
Location, five...
I just lost contact with Skywalker's team.
Come on, get up!
We have to keep moving.
Here they come.
Watch it. Watch it!
[explosion]
[blasters firing]
[groans]
They're falling back. Come on!
Get the tanks on the ground now!
Cody, get the tanks down.
Come in, Cody.
Cody, come in! Get the tanks down!
Copy that. Pilot, begin landing sequence.
Copy that, commander. Have fun down there.
Move it! Move it!
Here they come. Bugs incoming.
Man down! Man down!
General Kenobi, don't land.
The zone is hot.
But there's nowhere else to go.
[energy cannon firing]
[explosion]
We're hit. We're going down.
[electronic beeping]
-Ah!
-Brace yourselves!
[booming crash]
[metal creaking]
[voices overlapping]
What are our losses, Captain?
We got hit pretty hard.
I think only Kenobi's forces made it
through the flak to the landing zone.
And what about Skywalker?
Captain Rex reported they're
still in the middle of a firefight.
Skywalker's tanks are gone,
and they're trying to contact
General Kenobi's forces for support.
In the meantime, they'll press on
to the rendezvous point.
Very well.
Load the injured onto the tanks.
We'll make for that ridge.
With any luck,
we can meet up with Skywalker
on his way to Kenobi's position.
[blaster firing]
Okay, Cody.
I'll speak with General Skywalker.
[Anakin] Rex, what's the word?
Can Obi-Wan send support or not?
I don't think so, sir.
Cody says General Kenobi
never reached the landing site.
They think his gunship got shot down.
Great. The one time I actually ask
Obi-Wan for help,
he's nowhere to be found.
Well, what if something happened
to General Kenobi?
-He could be injured or...
-No time for that kind of talk.
Rex, we need to mobilize. Now.
Get the men together.
-We're gonna rush the guns.
-Yes, sir.
Ahsoka, you're with me.
We need to give Rex cover when we attack.
Got it. Just give the word.
Hey, I'm worried about him too.
But you have to keep your mind
in the here and now,
otherwise we'll never be able
to help Obi-Wan.
[blaster firing]
-All here, sir.
-Ready.
Now! Go, go, go!
Take 'em out. Take 'em all out.
[screams]
Not good. The bugs are splitting up.
Boil reporting as ordered, sir.
Waxer reporting as ordered, sir.
We've got a downed gunship
five klicks east.
We believe it's General Kenobi's.
I need you to get out there
and check for survivors.
[both] Sir, yes, sir.
[energy cannons firing]
[speaking native language]
Why do we always get the fun missions?
Oh, this isn't the fun part.
Getting back to the Square
is the fun part.
[metal screeching]
Waxer, Boil, am I glad to see you.
Trapper and I
are the only ones still alive.
Good to see you, sir.
Commander Cody's established
the square just beyond this position.
The bugs are on the move and trying
to surround us as we speak, sir.
They've got the general.
AT-TE 636,
lay down cover fire at 0.35.
Take it down! Take it down!
Are you injured, General?
[Kenobi] No, nothing too serious.
What's the situation here?
Ah. We've got no air cover,
two generals on the ground
beyond our position,
and a mess of bugs surrounding us.
The enemy was more than prepared
for our attack, sir.
They knew our every move.
Well, I'm sure General Skywalker
and General Mundi
will make it to our position.
We just have to make sure
we're still here when they arrive.
[metal screeching]
Negative, Captain.
We will be unable to provide
any air support at this time.
I understand that, sir.
But we have three attack forces
on the ground
and only one at the landing zone.
This is a planetary wide
invasion, Captain.
If I devote resources to your position,
it will mean sacrificing
other areas of the campaign.
All we can do at this time
is help you find General Skywalker.
All right, sir.
I'll report to the General.
Commander Jet out.
Give me every fighter you can scrape up.
Have you located
General Skywalker's position?
We think he's somewhere
along the eastern barrier.
That's not a barrier. It's a fortress.
[blasters firing]
-Gentlemen, careful.
-[screaming]
Well, this is another
fine mess you've gotten us into.
What? Hey, it's not my fault.
You were supposed to study the holomaps.
I did!
Remember, when I reminded you
about the giant wall,
and you said, "Don't worry, Snips.
We won't be anywhere near that."
Just get ready to climb.
General, I left a squad
to protect the tanks.
Are you sure this is the shortest way
to the landing zone?
No, I'm not sure, Commander.
All I can do is trust my instincts.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
I have a wing vibration up ahead.
[shrieking]
[screaming]
[blaster firing]
Don't stop. We must push on.
Forward!
So what's the plan, General?
Just keep us covered, Rex.
There's too much laser fire
for all of us to make the climb.
Ahsoka and I will handle this.
Just be ready when that wall comes down.
[explosions]
[screams]
[blasters firing]
How many droids have you shot down so far?
Twenty-five.
Ah, you're falling behind. Let's go.
[explosion]
Focus on the droids
on the top of the wall.
[screams]
Man down!
Hang on. There they are!
[energy cannons firing]
Ah!
[shrieks]
[explosions]
Look for a hatch.
We need to put the explosives
inside the wall.
Found one.
[blasters firing]
Hey, did you get them?
-[Anakin] Catch.
-Huh? Wha...
No!
-Come on, Rex.
-Up and away.
Whoa!
Help!
[massive explosion]
[screaming]
Next time, just tell me to jump.
Now where's the fun in that?
Come on, we can't keep Obi-Wan waiting.
You heard him, lads. Let's go!
We're almost through.
Bring in the flamethrowers!
[Geonosians shrieking]
Look, what's that?
[all shrieking]
[Anakin] Master Mundi, do you read me?
We are here, Skywalker.
We took a slight detour that put us
out of communications for a bit.
[Anakin] This has been a day
for detours, Master.
Indeed. But now the road is clear.
I can see the landing zone.
It does not look good.
Can you get me Admiral Yularen?
Admiral, we're at the breaking point.
You've got to get some fighters down here.
You are in luck, General Skywalker.
I have one squadron available.
[screams]
Retreat! Go, go, go, go!
[explosion]
[blasters firing]
Make every shot count!
Give it all you got!
Reinforcements!
The reinforcements have arrived!
[engines whooshing]
[explosion]
[all cheering]
Go, go, go, go!
Move it! Move it!
You heard him, lads, let's go!
Up to the front!
Come on! Hurry, hurry!
There they are. Move it, move it!
Master Kenobi.
Well, what happened to you?
I might ask you the same question.
Our combined forces should be enough
to destroy the shield generator.
Anakin, you'll need to take
a small squad through the shield,
as close as you can get
to their gun emplacements.
From there, you'll be able to temporarily
jam their scanners
so they are unable to target
the incoming tanks.
Once the tanks knock out the shield,
Master Mundi can bring the rest of
the troops in with the gunships.
Consider it done, Master.
All units are in position, sir.
Tell Skywalker to start the attack.
Begin the attack.
[blasters firing]
Let's jam their scanners.
Droid poppers ready.
[energy warbling]
Looks like it's working.
It won't last long.
Bring up the tanks.
[energy cannons firing]
[massive explosion]
[speaking native language]
So, Master, what was your total?
Not now, Ahsoka.
Come on.
Are you afraid you lost this time?
Fine. 55, that's my count.
And you?
Sixty.
Looks like I won.
Yeah, but I called in the air strike.
Tie.
You're impossible.
I'll never understand
how you can simplify these battles
into some kind of game.
Well, take care of yourselves.
I expect to see both of you back here
by the time I've destroyed
the main factory.
We shall do our best.
Sixty-five, Skywalker.
I'm sorry?
My total. 65.
So what do I win?
My everlasting respect, Master Mundi.
Oh.
That is a gift Anakin rarely bestows,
I assure you.
[engines whirring]
[orchestral fanfare]
♪ ♪
[Star Wars theme playing]
[R2-D2 beeping]