The following programme
contains adult humour
All right! OK!
All right! Yes! OK!
OK!
Wow!
I know you want a party,
but I have to say thank you
to a few people after what has been
a momentous week for this company.
Project Icarus has increased
our productivity tenfold.
Every department is working at three
times the usual speed due to the
increased interconnectivity
of our computer system.
Good, good, good. Okaaaay!
How can I talk about all that
computer stuff, all of that computer
gobbledegook without
saying a word about the lawyers?
They cut the red tape. They cut
the red tape. They cut the red tape.
Come on! Yes!
You cut it! You cut it! You cut it!
That's enough. And when you're
talking about computers, how can
you fail to mention Accounts?
Yes!
He's building up to us, he must be.
And finally, last but not least.
These three people proved
time and again that they have
the right stuff.
The toilet cleaners!
They said we couldn't do it.
They said outsourcing our toilet
cleaning would be inefficient.
Dirk, Banhead and Doodles
proved them wrong.
Toilets!
That's right, Doodles.
Where are you going?
They do this every time.
They never remember us.
They... You did the work.
We did all the work.
Does this mean we're not
going to the thank-you party.
Course we're not. Why would
we go? We weren't thanked.
RINGS
Hello. IT. Have you tried
turning it off and on again?
Have you tried
sticking it up your arse?
Oh,...yeah, yeah.
I just realised that was my mother.
Oh, I was really looking forward
to that, you know. Fancied a dance.
I'm glad the toilet guys
got the nod, though.
They do good work.
Have you been to the toilets on 12th?
It's like going on holiday
and I try not to go at home now.
I save it up.
Oh, Jesus! Will you please
do something about that poster?
What poster?
Oh, bloody drawer.
The one with the monkey
- it's horrible.
What's wrong with the monkey?
He's not horrible. He's lovely.
He's a lovely little monkey.
What's he doing in goal?
Not that monkey. That monkey.
Oh, right.
Well, that is a bit frightening.
Anyway, I'd better fix this drawer.
Moss, do you have the hammer?
You're not listening to me!
I hate it when people don't listen!
Oh, God.
High-end screeching.
Like someone's killing a cat.
A kind of shouty cat.
Oh, God. I'm so sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm just...I'm just a little
bit...you know, you know.
What?
Well, I've got,
you know, at the moment, so...
What?
I've got Aunt Irma visiting.
Oh. Do you not like Aunt Irma?
I've got an aunt like that.
It's my term for
my time of the month.
Oh!
What time of the month? The weekend?
No.
Does Aunt Irma visit on the weekend?
Moss...
You know, it's high tide.
But we're not on the coast.
I'm closed for maintenance.
Closed for maintenance?
Moss!
I've fallen to the Communists.
Well, they do have
some strong arguments.
Carrie, Moss. First scene in Carrie.
Oh, OK.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. No, no,
yeah, no, Uh-uh.
Yeah, you know, people tell me I'm
not great during this time,
so I thought I should warn you.
Right, not great in what way?
Just generally.
I'm not great to be around, so
try not to get on my nerves.
I've had a few girlfriends.
I'm not completely oblivious.
You won't even know I'm here.
Oh, when this is working,
the action on it's so great.
Look at that. So smooth.
Stop doing that!
Oh-aagh!
Oh, my God! Sorry, sorry.
But you see what I mean?
You have to be careful.
I'll be careful.
Has she gone yet?
Yeah.
What was all that about? Cor,
dear me. Ladies. God bless 'em.
What would we do without them?
With their ways.
Their mysterious seasons,
the moon, Glenn Close, Sheena Easton,
all the different kinds of women.
Oh, smashing.
Oh, my appointment. I've got
to go and see the psychiatrist.
I can't believe
there's a psychiatrist here.
All because those two
from Accounts just had enough
and wanted to go to the seaside.
The seaside?
They committed suicide, Roy.
That's right. Yes, of course.
Why do you have to go and see her?
Oh, because I said
Jen was dead that time.
Oh, yeah, yeah, that'll be it.
She said it was something only
a severely disturbed person would do
and that now I have to spend a lot
of time in therapy. Isn't that great?
Oh, well, yes,
that's clearly terrific.
No, no, that's bad.
Why do you think that's great?
The psychiatrist
is a very attractive lady.
Ah, I see. She's of the female...
Genre, yes.
A Dr Melfi to your Tony Soprano.
She's a glamorous older woman.
Oh, the things
you could learn from her.
Or from any woman.
Is Jen in her office?
I need to get her to sign something.
Um, yeah...
Moss, Moss, don't get on her nerves.
How would I get on her nerves?
Hello?
GROWL
Shouldn't I be on the couch?
No, Maurice, not today.
I've got some good news.
I think you've turned a corner.
I'm not going on the couch?
You don't need me any more.
What?
Well, there's obviously
nothing wrong with you
and I think you're ready
to do without our sessions.
But I've been feeling depressed.
Really? Why?
Because I'm pregnant.
What?
I mean,
I had a dream that I was pregnant.
Well, there's
nothing unusual about that.
But when I had the baby, I looked
down and saw that it was my father.
That's normal, Moss.
Really? That's the maddest thing
I could think of.
My mother? What if it had two heads?
Moss,
I think you're fine and there are
other people here who need me more.
But I've been having dark thoughts.
Dark thoughts?
Yes, thoughts about dark things.
What sort of dark things?
Things that are dark.
Like what?
Darkness.
Night.
Things of the night.
Dracula.
You haven't been
thinking about self harm?
Self harm, yes.
Harm...harm of the self.
Suicide?
For starters, yes.
Moss, I do not think
that you are suicidal.
W-why not? I tell you,
I'm at the end of my flipping tether!
Moss! It's not like you
to use that sort of language.
Flip off!
Moss!
For God's sake.
Yes!
Roy!
I may be speaking louder right now
because I'm wearing ear plugs.
Why are you wearing ear plugs?
That's right.
What?
What's this contraption?
Oh, um...
I'm stealing food from this machine.
You know I do, huh?
Oh, by the way, your work
on Project Icarus was very good.
Well done.
You did a great job. Thanks.
Yep, I can hear you.
What's wrong with you?
Oh, my God, you're crying.
I'm not crying. You're crying.
What's wrong?
Nothing's wrong. Will
you stop getting at me?
I'm not getting at you.
Stop shouting at me.
Why are these always so hard to open?
Oh, my God!
Calm down, everybody!
What on earth is going on?!
I don't know. I feel weird and I've
been swearing like a flipping docker.
Denholm just thanked me for Project
Icarus and I started crying like an
actress. What's going on?
Maybe it's all this stuff
that you both eat.
Oh, will you get off that.
OK, what did you
have for breakfast this morning?
Smarties cereal.
Oh, my God. I didn't even
know Smarties made a cereal.
They don't. It's just
Smarties in a bowl with milk.
Case closed.
It's too much sugar, that's all.
No, hold on now.
I live on sugar and we've
never had these problems before.
Well, the only
other explanation is...
No, no, it's silly.
What?
Well, I feel ridiculous
even saying it, but where I
worked before, it was me and a few
other girls, Liz and Suzanne, and
whenever Aunt Irma was visiting me,
we all kind of...
synchronised.
What's that got to do with us?
Well...
You think...?
Maybe. You're not saying...
I know it sounds crazy.
Whoa! You don't think that
Aunt Irma's visiting us?
The symptoms, Roy.
I am a man! He's a man!
We're men!
OK, OK. Tell me how you're feeling.
I feel delicate...
..and annoyed
and, um...
I think I'm ugly.
That's her.
This is ridiculous! I've never heard
anything so bizarre in my life.
Stop shouting at her. You're always
shouting at her and it's not fair!
You don't believe this theory,
do you?
No.
Oh. It's nonsense, isn't it?
She's so silly. Sugar!
Yeah.
What?!
That's not what's causing it.
You think it's Irma?!
Yes, don't you?
No! I'm a man! We're men!
If it's true, it's the scientific
breakthrough of the afternoon.
It's not true.
I wasn't about to foolishly
jump to conclusions,
so I've sent an e-mail out,
asking everyone's opinions.
Right, well, that's a good idea.
No, sorry,
could you run that past me again?
I've sent it to everyone in my
address book. You should have one.
What?!
"Do we have PMT?"
You sent this out?!
Oh, you signed it from both of us!
You signed it from both of us!
Yes, along with a list of symptoms.
"Headachy, weight gain, irritability,
anxiety, breast tenderness"!
I get that, don't you?
Yes, but you cannot tell the entire
IT community that we have PMT!
Come on, no-one would use that
sort of information against us.
Wait a second, they would! Oh, no!
There's probably a website
devoted to us already.
Oh, I only posted it
about an hour ago.
Google our names.
Oh, no!
What are we gonna do?
I don't know.
Come on, it's my
turn with the bottle.
(SHRIEKS) God, sorry, Richmond,
I always forget you work here.
Yes, I wouldn't normally
come out this far,
only could you have a
word with Moss and Roy?
Since they got famous, they've
been at each other's throats.
They're famous?
Yes, Google their names.
My goodness,
how many entries do they have?!
Thousands. Moss's e-mail's
spreading like a virus.
They've unleashed a monster
with that Aunt Irma business.
Yes, Richmond, tell me. How come
Aunt Irma isn't affecting you?
Of course it is. I've been
feeling very gloomy all day.
Not my usual cheery self at all.
Yeah, it's just difficult to tell
underneath all that make-up.
I'm not wearing make-up.
Could you have a word?
They're driving me out
of my tiny little mind.
Guys you're going to have to...
Oh, my goodness,
what happened to your face?
We had an argument.
My God, have you seen this?
What's happening?
Sssh. Sssh.
(REPORTER) 'The rioting
has been going on all night.
'The men involved are young, angry,
'and almost all of them
work with computers.'
This is insane! What's going on?!
'In Tokyo, two games designers
'went on the rampage in a shopping
centre and frightened a dog.
'In Hamburg, a group of software
developers shouted at a bus.
'The situation is
completely out of...'
And it's all because of Aunt Irma.
But how?
You shouldn't have sent out that
e-mail detailing the symptoms.
You know how suggestible
IT people are.
That's not true.
Yes, it is.
No, you're right. Of course it is.
You shouldn't have
sent that e-mail, Moss.
Don't blame me.
It's your fault!
Guys, come on, you're fighting,
it's like you're in a trance.
No, we shouldn't be doing this.
This isn't us, we never fight.
We have to do something.
Yeah, whatever.
I'm going in.
I never thought
it would come to this.
Well, it has. She's the only one
that's had direct contact with Irma.
If we can just calm her down,
then we can hope and pray that
everybody else calms down, too.
You've got big balls, Roy.
Thanks.
You're very welcome.
Hiya!
(DISTORTED) I can never
find a bloody pen in here!
How's my soldier?
(DISTORTED) What do you want?!
I came in for a little chat.
Wow, you are looking good today.
(SOFTER VOICE, STILL DISTORTED)
Thank you.
So slim.
Yeah, I try and stay in shape.
Oh, your hair looks great.
New conditioner.
The action on this is great.
Oh, hello.
Hello, Maurice.
I have to tell you I've a
little confession to make.
As you may or may not know,
for ethical reasons,
I'm required not to have any
relations with any of my patients.
But for the last few months,
I've been developing some...
warm feelings towards you.
And the real reason
I terminated your therapy
was so that I could explore
some of these feelings.
I see.
I was wondering, when you were
working in your job with the girls,
if things ever got on top of you,
what would you do to...relax?
We'd have a big girls' night out.
I'd love that, actually,
a big girly night out.
Fat chance of that round here.
Not necessarily.
Mum?!
This is my psychiatrist.
Oh, no, I'm sorry, it's just that
you look exactly like my mother.
No, but don't be offended by that,
she's a very sexy woman.
Not that I would
want to have sex with her.
I know that that's what you
psychiatrists think,
but I swear to God that there's
nothing to it in my case.
My mother wouldn't stand for
any of that kind of nonsense.
I can just hear her now.
"What are you doing, Roy?
What are you doing?!"
You handled that well.
That's the psychiatrist?!
I think she's my girlfriend now.
Whoa! No, Moss, listen to me.
You can never see that woman again.
She looks exactly like my mother.
You're exaggerating.
She's the spit of her!
What went on in there?
Right, OK,
what would you say
to a big girls' night out?
How big are the girls?
I can't believe I'd never
seen Steel Magnolias.
Oh, my God, it's good, isn't it?
I know what we can watch next!
Yay! You really liked that film?
Yes, didn't you?
No! It was heartwarming!
Well, I feel like a princess, Roy,
and don't tell me you
don't feel the same.
Well, my breast tenderness has gone.
No! What am I talking about?
I'm a man! We're men!
It's the worst night of my life.
Hiya!
OK,
Beaches or Dirty Dancing?!
Oh, Beaches! No, Dirty Dancing!
Oh, I can't decide!
Dear God! I don't know
which one to watch either!
But you know what we should do?
What?
Something else.
Um, ooh, I know, why don't
we go to the thank you party?
I thought you didn't want to go?
Well,
everybody else is there, and they
did nothing, and we did all the work.
Yeah. Screw them.
OK, come on, let's go, girls.
Yay!
OK, but first,
ten minutes of Beaches.
SCREAMING
Congratulations!
WHOOPING AND SCREAMING
Oh, wow!
Wow!
Oh yes, I should just say
I asked Dr Mendall to join us.
What?!
Moss! Over here!
What's wrong with you?
Nothing. I just really
need to get drunk.
Yeah, I'd like to get drunk.
We should get drunk together, then.
OK, yeah.
Let's get so drunk
we don't know what's going on.
All right.
And, turned round,
four dead cyclists, all my fault!
ALL LAUGH
Brilliant!
IT guys! Gangway!
# DISCO MUSIC PLAYS
# SLOW MUSIC PLAYS
Oh, dear.
TOILET FLUSHES >
Oh, my God! I didn't. I didn't.
Good morning!
(SCREAMS)
I've made you a cup of tea.
Oh, thanks, Mum.
"Mum"? That's interesting.
(SCREAMS)
Subtitles by Red Bee Media Ltd
(BOTH SCREAM)