This programme contains adult humour.
# We don't need no education... #
Yes, you do.
You've just used a double negative.
Notice anything?
What? Guess.
Something wrong with your eyes.
No, I have a new cup.
What's wrong with my eyes?
It's not very distinctive. How's
anyone supposed to know it's yours?
There's a picture of me on it.
No, there isn't!
Yes, there is.
No, there isn't, Moss.
Yes, there is. I am sick of
my things going walkabout.
With this picture, everyone knows
that a certain Mr Moss
might be looking for his cup...
There is nothing on the cup!
Wrangle with him and you'll
find your hand full, my friend.
Wrangle with who?!
There's no-one there!
Morning.
D'you have a nice weekend?
It was all right, thanks.
Not you.
I did too.
I'm not wearing a scarf.
Not you, Moss!
Notice anything new about Moss?
His eyes?
What is wrong with my eyes?!
No, he has a new cup.
It's the talk of the office!
Yes, I think I read about it
in Heat.
Receptionist, third floor,
Gloria what's-her-name,
have you seen her baby?
I didn't even know she was pregnant.
She was out to here.
Yeah, I thought she was
stealing office equipment.
That's how I got that monitor home.
Do you want to sit here?
What?
Ask me where it is.
Where was it?
The picture.
Where's the picture, Moss?
It's on the base, Roy.
OK, well, let's see it, then.
Sure. I pour hot squash over myself
and we all have a good chuckle.
Everyone except muggins here.
I'll show you in a minute.
Can I ask you two a question?
Please, Christ, yes.
Wait, one moment.
OK, go.
How can you two live like this?
How can you two...?
Don't Google the question, Moss!
What are you talking about?
It's so disgusting in here.
I know nobody comes down here,
but it doesn't mean
you have to live like animals.
You can clean that window
and you'd have a bit of light.
What window?
That one up there.
Yeah, that's not a window.
Yes, it is. Get it clean,
you'll have some light in here.
I think that we have plenty of light.
I think that's fine!
Look at that CD tray.
Isn't that important?
Wouldn't you like to actually
put CDs in there at some point?
Yes, ideally, but
I haven't the heart to move them.
How did that even happen?
OK, now I'm curious.
Give us a look at the picture, then.
What picture?
The picture on the cup!
Right.
Behold!
There's nothing there!
What?!
This isn't my cup!
What is that?
Goat's cheese salad.
Ugh!
You don't like goat's cheese?
I don't like goat's anything!
I don't like goats
being involved in
any stage of
the food-production process.
Would I blow everyone's mind
if I ate dessert first?
What are you eating, anyway?
It's a bucket of fried chicken.
It comes in a real bucket now.
Tell me,
what's behind that red door?
CRASH
BOTH: Nothing.
There must be something behind it.
There's nothing behind
the red door, Jen.
Well then, I can just...
No, Jen, it's just a boring
old store room, that's all!
It's just a store room
where we keep the snibbits.
What's a snibbit?
It's a kind of plange.
Oh, a plange for the computers?
Yes, computer plange!
If it's a store room, we can store
some of this stuff in...
No, Jen! Look, I know that
you want to make your mark down here,
and that's really sweet,
but you can't
just go messing around with
the snibbit store room willy-nilly!
You can't upset the whole
harmony of the place!
Harmony?! What harmony?!
I know that the place looks like
a bit of a mess,
but it's actually
a very delicate ecosystem.
Everything is connected.
It's like the rainforest.
You change one thing,
even the tiniest bit
and the whole rainforest dies!
You don't want
the rainforest to die, do you?!
No, I really don't want
the rainforest to die.
That's what will happen
if you open the red door.
PHONE
Hello, IT. Have you tried
turning it off and on again?
OK, are you sure
that it's plugged in?!
OK, I'll be up in a minute.
What was that about?
Girl on fourth.
Ooh, job. You gonna go?
Yeah, in a while. It can wait.
Why can it wait? She probably needs
to get on, she needs a computer.
I am reading a comic.
I knew it. Every time
I used to phone IT in my last job,
it'd take a good couple
of hours before someone got to me.
That is how we do it.
You can't go off straightaway
or they'll all expect it.
You're killing the rainforest!
Stop saying that!
It's more than that. Me and this
girl, I asked her out, she said no,
it all got a little bit embarrassing
and ever since then, when I go up,
she treats me like I'm some sort of
sexually frustrated cretin!
Get up there now, please.
You are not the head
of this department!
No, I'm relationship manager.
I'm the one who gets the complaints.
I'm the one whose name is on the...!
Oh God, all right, I will
go up just to shut you up.
(MOUTHS)
God's sake!
There's someone under here.
Yes!
Hello?
Hello? Hello?
You should get it fixed. >
Oh, yeah. Well, I left him to it.
Yeah, I like it when they just go.
Oh, dear me!
What are you laughing at?
This flipping circuit board, Jen.
Some chump has run the data lines
right through the power supply!
Amateur hour!
I've got tears in my eyes!
MOBILE BLEEPS
Roy's stuck under a desk.
Stuck under a desk?!
Yes, it is an unusual text,
isn't it? It's not just me.
No, it's unusual.
I'd best investigate.
Yes. You investigate.
I'll hold the fort.
(SCREAMS)
Listen, I'm really
sorry about your hand.
Oh, don't worry about it.
I must have cut it when I swooned.
I startled you.
I didn't know there was anyone else,
I thought it was just us three.
I often work nights, so perhaps
that's why you haven't seen me.
Gosh, it's very cold
in here, isn't it?
Air-conditioning,
keeps these things cool.
Yes, what are they?
I've no idea.
They put me in charge of them.
Moss and Roy?
I don't know their names.
I mean, I don't know what
any of this stuff even does.
What's going on there?
I don't know.
Is it good that it's doing that?
Occasionally it doesn't do that
and I think I should tell them
but often I just look away.
And this one, flash, flash, flash,
and wait for it, nothing
for a while, here it comes,
double flash.
Brilliant.
Wow.
It's obvious you're going mad.
So, let me get this straight.
You stay down here all the time.
I pop out occasionally
when I have to get supplies.
And you don't know why you're here
or what you do?
Correct.
So this is your job. This is
what you want for a career?
No.
You don't understand.
I'm not here because
I want to be here. This is...
this is my punishment.
You see, I used to be
Denholm's second-in-command.
Do I amaze you?
So, how did you end up down here?
That's the question I've been
asking myself for four long years.
Oh, I couldn't help
noticing you're bleeding.
No, it's fine, it's just a
little nick.
I'd rather deal with it myself.
No. Honestly. Oh my...!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Please. Excuse me, excuse me, what
are you doing? Get off me! Get...
Thank you.
That should clear up nicely.
Yes, there was a time when
things were very different.
'I was one of Reynholm
Industries' top guys.
'You should have seen me, I was
magical. Here's me saying some
'pretty important stuff to a group
of people circled around me.
'In the boardroom I was a wizard.
'A punchy character.
'There's me with a graph.
'Things were moving fast, so fast,
'my career was advancing
by leaps and bounds.
'Denholm saw great things for me.
'They were crazy, heady days.
'It seemed like those days
would last for ever.
'But it all changed.'
Wow. So what happened?
It's quite a long story, actually.
Really? Don't worry about it, then.
Oh, my good gracious me!
Wow, quick.
What is it?
I can't explain it. You're just
going to have to come over here
and look out this window
for a while.
Whatever it is, we're not interested.
Well, I have to say
you're missing out.
Fine.
Jimminy Jones! Look at the nature
of the thing that is happening
has changed slightly,
rendering it yet more impressive.
Someday
I'll tell my kids about this.
You can't even tell us. How are
you going to tell your children?
You of no interest in the world!
(MOUTHS)
Are you sure it's OK to come out?
Don't you worry about those two.
Listen, Richmond,
I've always wanted to know.
Why do you never see
any cockney Goths?
Too cheerful.
They spoil it for the rest of us.
How come you never
see Goths driving cars?
Oh, we drive cars.
We're just like you, really,
except we listen to Cradle Of Filth.
Cradle Of Filth?
I presume that's a band?
It's not literally
a Cradle Of Filth?
Oh no, that would be horrible.
Cradle Of Filth are actually
one of the best contemporary
dark wave bands in the world.
I'll never forget the
first time I heard them.
It changed my life.
'Blew my mind.
'It was lucky I discovered
them when I did because it
'was around that time that things
started to go wrong for me at work.
'I don't know what happened.
'Suddenly people just
weren't returning my calls.
'At strategy meetings people
seemed distracted, distant.
'I couldn't put my finger on it.
'Something was wrong.'
I'll tell you, it was good to
have the Filth to come home to
after another disappointing day.
You've got to help Roy.
Richmond's out of his room,
he's not in his room.
He's supposed to be in his room,
why is he out of his room?
Well, he's going to come out
and play with us for a while.
But the rain forests...
What's wrong with you, Moss?
Roy's stuck
underneath a lady's desk.
What, still?
This would be funny but he's
been under there too long for
a reasonable explanation.
If that woman looks down she'll
assume he's a desk rabbit.
A desk rabbit?
I just made that up.
But that's be what they start
to call people like Roy.
But Roy isn't a desk rabbit, he's
my best friend and unless you
do something it's just going to be
you, me and Tim Burton over there.
What could I possibly do?
She could look under any minute,
it could be too late.
But I don't know what to do.
You're Relationship Manager!
All right, all right!
Just to shut you up.
Hello, Richmond. How are things?
You know, not brilliant.
He's supposed to be in his room.
Oh, there's a builder outside
taking off his shirt.
Like in ads?
Yeah, like in ads.
Everything all right downstairs?
Yes, fine, I left
Moss and Richmond in charge.
Good, well...
Richmond, out of his room?
Yeah.
What did I say about the red door?
I said don't open the red door!
What have you got against him?
(I just don't like him.)
You're just like the rest of them.
The people who turned their backs
on him as soon as he became a Goth.
He obviously hasn't told
you about the funeral. Mm.
Ask him about the funeral.
(MUTTERS AND CHUCKLES)
Hello, Denholm.
Hi, Jen, I'm just enjoying
this cup of tea.
(CHUCKLES) Brilliant!
How are you doing, Jen?
Yes. Just to say,
I met Richmond.
I see.
It isn't like for me to say,
but it sounds like you two had
a good relationship at one point.
You should speak to him.
I'll thank you to
keep out of this, Jen.
Goths are people, too.
Enough.
There's absolutely
no point to anything.
You're right.
No point, it's all futile.
I can't even find my cup.
You try to look on the bright side.
Ha. The bright side.
Sometimes you think, "What would
change if I just killed myself?"
You're right.
I could just kill myself.
It'd be so easy, wouldn't it?
So very, very easy.
Richmond! Get back to your room.
What's the point of sending him
back? What's the point of anything?
Quick, get the brush.
But she said I could come out.
You're bringing everyone down.
No, I'm not.
Yes, he is.
Come on.
Thank you.
Tell her why they sent you down
here. Tell her what you did.
I don't know why I'm down here.
So Denholm just demoted
you for nothing, did he?
No, he changed,
after his father died.
I don't think he ever
fully recovered.
From the moment
I saw him at the funeral
I could tell there
was something different.
Bloody good of you to come, thanks.
Thanks. Bloody good service,
wasn't it?
Thank you very much.
Jackie, watch your bloody hat.
I'm so sorry.
Here, it's Cradle Of Filth.
They got me through
some pretty bleak times.
Try track four, Coffin Fodder,
it sounds horrible, but
it's actually quite beautiful.
Relationship Manager.
Yes, yes of course.
First thing tomorrow.
That was Denholm.
He wants to see you.
What is it?
I can't believe you want me back.
You've got Jen to thank.
Her words the other day moved
me deeply, very deeply indeed.
Really, what did she say?
I can't remember.
Point is, it's the effect of
the words that are important.
Treating someone differently cos
of ther skin colour is wrong.
I don't see why things can't
get back to the way they were.
I don't know what to say.
You're back with the
big guys, Richmond.
Great.
But that's if you're
prepared to take me on.
You know how demanding I am.
Stop it.
You know how changeable I can be.
Yes, Mr M.
Call me Denholm.
All right, thanks, Denholm.
Oh no, I don't like that,
don't do it again.
All right, sorry.
In fact I've changed my
mind about the whole thing.
What, you mean I have
to stay down here?
Yes, leave me alone, you goblin.
I suppose it isn't quite so bad now
I don't have to stay in that room.
Yes, yes, we're happy to have you.
Oh!
My milky lens has popped out.
Don't step on it.
You've got to help me find it.
Oh, actually, I think it's
just popped round the back.
It does that sometimes.
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
Go on.
It's almost ...
How about that, then?
That looks great.
Told you it was a window.
Bloody lens.
(YELLS) Bit bright, isn't it?
No, it's fine, it's just that...
Oh! I really ought to...
Actually I'm gonna...
Thank God.
At least everything
is back to normal.
As long as no-one
goes through that door.