'Tonight, I move my eyes...
'..Richard vandalises a road...'
There you go.
'..and James says, "Cow." '
Cow!
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
Hello.
Hello, good evening, and welcome.
Thank you so much.
Now, this is a mobile telephone.
It's fully functional
and what I'm going to do...
is throw it in that lavatory.
LAUGHTER
I know that's the first time
you've ever seen a programme
start that way, but bear with me,
because if we now look...
Yeah, it's only been in the water
for a few seconds,
but it's ruined for ever.
LAUGHTER
If you wanted to communicate
with somebody,
you'd be better off using
a Brussels sprout.
LAUGHTER
Of course, because if you expose
your phone to any form of moisture
or heat or dust or vibration,
it will break.
It's not just phones,
it's everything -
printers, laptops, Wi-Fi routers.
My coffee machine breaks even
when you expose it to coffee.
LAUGHTER
Anything with a circuit board is
as reliable as a Greek accountant.
LAUGHTER
It is. Except, weirdly, except cars.
Now, we were talking about this
in the office the other day,
and there was a bit of an argument.
We were saying you can drive a car
across the Sahara, the Arctic,
you can run it through hurricanes
and dust storms and it'll be fine.
Hmm, but the producers
are saying
that because modern cars are
so complex and so electronical,
they are bound to suffer from
reliability problems
like everything else.
Right,
so to see who is correct,
the producers said to us,
"Go out and each choose
your favourite modern GT car,
"and then report with them
to what's billed
"as the most hirsute and manly
proving ground of them all -
"Austria."
No, James, Australia.
LAUGHTER
Same thing.
'This is the hirsute and manly
proving ground in question...
'..the vast, almost completely
uninhabited Northern Territory,
'better known as the outback.
'Richard had chosen to take on
this brutal and enormous wilderness
'in a car that was designed
for the car park at Old Trafford -
'a Bentley Continental GT.
'James had gone for a car engineered
for the velvet smoothness
'of the world's racetracks -
a Nissan GT-R.
'And I was in the ultimate
Monaco-to-Munich mile-muncher -
'the BMW M6 Gran Coupe.'
I tell you what.
What?
I think this is the first time
in all of Top Gear's history,
where all three of us
like all three of the cars.
Normally, I go, "Yours is rubbish,
and you've made the wrong decision,
"and I'm the only one
who's done it properly."
It's a good point, actually,
cos I do like your car
and I do like your car, Hammond,
and I like my car, obviously.
It's a GT-R.
You can't not like a GT-R.
If you like driving above all else
and to the exclusion of
all other considerations,
you have to have one of these.
If you have a Ferrari
or a Lamborghini,
what you're saying is, "I'm not
that interested in driving."
It's showing off.
Speaking of which,
the Bentley Continental...
Now, what happened there?
We used to think it was a bit dull,
but now it's sort of good.
But it was overnight. It was.
We all must have woken up...
I hate the Bentley Continental.
God, I love the Bentley Continental.
I don't understand that. Cos they
haven't changed the styling much.
It's been around a while now.
But then you just woke up
one morning and went,
"That looks really good."
I'd actually have a yellow one
as well. It looks tremendous.
But while we're on the subject
of styling...a-hem, a-hem, a-hem!
Oh, how we mocked when they said
they were going to do this.
Right, so you are going to do
a four-door version
of a two-door version
of a four-door saloon car?
And then it came out and you just
thought, "That is so good looking."
I love that back wheel. That dished
back wheel looks so fantastic.
Almost a double-bubble roof.
I know it's carbon fibre,
which is a little bit...
We can gloss over that.
But, God, it looks good.
'As we continued our three-car
love-in, a challenge arrived.'
Here we go.
"You will drive to a farm,
which is four days from here."
Everything is four days
from everything in Australia!
"And when you arrive you will use
your cars to round up 4,000 cows."
But... Can you do that?
"The farm is a big one.
Three million...."
Three million acres?! No, it's not.
You read that wrong.
It's in words. It's in words, yeah.
Three... It's not...? Are you
sure...? It isn't 300,000?
Three million in the country?
That's a big farm.
Never mind that. Rounding up
4,000 cows using... These.
HE GASPS
Oh, God, James, what have you done?
What's he done, what?
As we know, there is a strong
republican movement in this country,
people who think it's ridiculous
to have a head of state
living in London
on the other side of the world.
He turns up here
with that on the number plate.
What?
Can you not see that? It's obvious.
No. "Charles and Camilla."
You've done it on purpose,
haven't you, James?
Let me explain.
You blithering idiot. You idiot!
Oh, no! Mine says, "Big Royalist."
It does. It totally does.
You can see it.
"Big Royalist."
Luckily, mine just says BMW 001,
cos I've covered myself
on this occasion.
No, you idiot. "Bloody Mrs Windsor."
Oh, no! "Bloody Mrs Windsor."
We're in trouble now!
How could he possibly know?
I rang them up
and said, "Can you provide a car?
"Can you make sure the number plate
doesn't say 'convict'
"or anything on it?"
And they've done that!
We're going to have
to drive through...
We'll be stoned by republicans.
'As we set off, though,
we had a more immediate problem.
'Could our complicated cars
really cope
'with this vast,
superheated dust bowl?'
Vauxhall once thought they'd try
and sell the Senator in Australia,
a big old saloon
made in Germany in the '80s.
So they shipped one out here
and it lasted a couple of days
and then it split in half.
Split in half!
That's how brutal the outback is.
This car has
electronic valve control,
electronic gearbox control,
an electronic differential.
Everything is electronic.
It actually has a sensor
in the engine that adjusts