This programme contains
strong language and adult humour.
Who owns the Infinity Gauntlet?
'Thanos.'
What was Thor's father's name?
'Odin.
'Sorry, Moss, I've really got to go.'
Awww, just a few more,
just a few more...
No, no, I'm sorry,
you've done more than enough.
OK, all right, baby, see you later.
Bye-bye. Wow! Right?
That's an impressive knowledge
of the Marvel universe. I know.
Well, you've done it.
You've finally found a woman
I can do business with.
Yeah, no,
don't say things like that.
I'm sorry, I'm just so excited
for us! No...
If you don't go in all the way,
it doesn't really count.
SHE LAUGHS
Hey, Red! Stand back, stand back,
this one's mine.
I'm going to do everything for you,
really nice.
Stand back, stand back,
she's all mine.
It's tight. You're so strong.
SWIRLING MARIACHI-STYLE MUSIC
FROTHING HISS
Oh!
Ah, yes, yes.
It's bubbling over.
It's on the house...for you.
Oh, my God! You inspire me.
Have a great day. I will...and you.
Thank you. Ciao.
BABY TALKS FRENCH
Moss, have you seen this video
of the baby speaking French?
It went viral at 10:30, Roy,
of course I've seen it.
I must have been in the toilet.
Ah, Jen, exciting news,
I've just uploaded
the second episode
of my board games review show.
Care to have a look?
That was fast.
Seems like only yesterday
we had to sit through the last one.
It was three months ago, Jen.
Really?
It feels like it just happened.
Roy, did you hear that?
Moss has done his board game review
show again. I'm not watching that.
I'm not watching that again.
Jesus Christ,
we don't have to watch it, do we?
We only sat through the first one
the other day.
It was three months ago. My God!
Wow, it feels like it just ended.
It was so boring! It was like being
insane, it was so insanely boring!
Roy's not a fan
but you said you liked it.
Where did you get your coffee?
A new place. Any good? Really good.
You specifically said, and I quote,
"You must show me the next one,
Moss." Did I?
Did I really? My God!
PHONE RINGS
Oh, if you'll excuse me,
that'll be my lady love
from the seventh floor.
That's going well? Oh, yeah!
He's cock-a-hoop over this Sheila.
OK, so that'll be over soon, then.
Hey, I'll have you know
that Alice is nuts about me.
She thinks that I'm emotionally
artistic. Well, what does that mean?
Erm, she said that emotionally
I was on the artistic spectrum.
I think it means that I'm creative
about my feelings, you know,
more in tune with her wants
and needs than most men.
Oh, she's rung out...
That keeps happening.
All right, if I'd said I'd watch it,
then I suppose that's what
I'm going to have to do.
That's the spirit, Jen.
Come on, let's get it over with.
Now, keep an open mind.
I know the first show was a bit
"bare boned" but I think you'll
really enjoy my new episode,
or "webisode", if you prefer.
I don't prefer that, no-one does.
Come on, come on, sooner it starts,
sooner it's over.
FUNKY BASS GUITAR
Game board.
Game...game...game...
Game... Board.
Board...board...board...board...
Hello and welcome to Games Board.
Today on the show, we have...
So, guys... I've been playing...
What's coming up on the show...
..guys? I've...
I've been playing Ports of Essen.
A strategic trading game,
where each player takes
the role of a Danish fishing port
merchant in the 16th century.
And for a change of pace,
I've been looking at the expansion
to Textile Merchant.
Textile Merchant, Norfolk Edition.
Two games by Reiner Kiniksi?
Hold on to your hat,
it's going to be a bumpy...
FUNKY BASS GUITAR
Let's talk about components.
Shouldn't we do rules
before components?
It won't make any sense
if we do it before the rules.
Don't forget to cut this
conversation.
What? Well,
don't let the actual programme...
FUNKY BASS GUITAR
How long is this? Even hearing it is
bad. I need to stop hearing it.
Sorry, Moss, I can't do it, it's
unbearable. Where are you going?
I'm jealous of your coffee.
You literally can't watch it?
I literally can't watch it.
So what can we do to make it better?
Well, I don't want to say anything
that might hurt your feelings.
It's all right, I can take it, Jen.
I'm a big boy.
Well, as I say, it's slow,
it's so slow.
OK, good, it is a bit slow,
we can work on that.
And I guess the other thing is that
it's terrible.
It's slow and terrible.
If a friend asked me to describe it,
I'd say it's a slow,
terrible thing on the internet, that
I could only watch for a minute.
Is this helpful? Arr...pfft!
So helpful! God! Slow, terrible,
could only watch it for a minute.
Wow, a lot to get our teeth
stuck into there.
OK, well, let's see if I can
help you with anything else.
Erm, none of you are any good
in front of a camera.
None of us, yeah...
You've got really annoying voices.
The voices are a pain, yes.
I guess that's because
you haven't got any confidence.
No confidence. I mean, if there's
one thing you need, it's confidence.
It is confidence. Absolutely.
Well, Jen, I can only thank you,
once again... And another thing...
I'm not listening any more!
Douglas, you're incorrigible.
I'm incorrigible?
You're Raymond Peterfellow,
owner of the finest lap-dancing
establishments in Soho.
If anyone's incorrigible it's you,
you perfumed porno vampire.
THEY LAUGH
Perfumed porno vampire, I like that.
So you're thinking of having 500 of
these travelling across London?
That's what I said. Sexy and classy.
And that's difficult to pull off.
This will get people talking,
all right.
Consider me one happy shareholder.
Right. Oh, big party coming up on
Thursday night, if you're up for it?
Damn, I'm supposed to be doing
Secret Millionaire.
BLEEP it, I'll cancel.
I'll tell my assistant.
Hi, Joan. Jen. I'm not your
assistant, Mr Reynholm.
I want you to cancel
Secret Millionaire for me.
I'm not your assistant,
wouldn't know who to call.
Just say anything, work your
usual magic. 'Not your assistant.
'I am not your...'
Oh, I'm sorry, I thought
this was the toilet.
Didn't this used to be toilets?
Yes, I moved my office here to be
closer to the ladies toilets.
Must get someone to take
that sign down.
What's wrong with you, Ross?
Small mocha, please.
Small mocha, please. Okey-dokey.
Or medium...
Yeah, you know what? I've changed
my mind, I think I'll have a medium.
So, you don't want a small one?
Small's fine, small is just as good,
so I'll...just...
Yes, that is what I'll have, I'll
have a small mocha, my little man.
My good man.
OK, coming up.
Got it?
OK.
(Fuck's sake.)
Thank you for the virgin
gin and tonic.
I suppose you could just
call it tonic. Yes.
So, Ross, how goes it
in the world of computers?
Or PC world, if you will?
We're all very happy,
thank you, Mr Reynholm.
Very happy indeed. Forget this "we"
malarky, I'm talking to you, Ross.
Are you happy? Very happy,
thank you, Mr Reynholm.
Look, I'm not your boss.
We're just a couple of guys,
a couple of guys,
shooting the shit,
now tell me the truth.
Well, I suppose, sometimes I do
feel I lack a little confidence.
I know, it's silly.
No, I've just realised what
a funny voice you have.
Now, Ross, I'm going to
tell you something.
Confidence is a confidence trick.
Look at me, what do you see?
A man who inherited his father's
successful business.
Wasn't that successful.
It was pretty successful.
A lot more successful than it is
now, that's for sure.
All right, all right,
just say the right thing.
Say the thing I want you to say.
Say, "A confident man", say "A
confident man". A confident man.
I wasn't always this way. There was
a time when I was just like you.
But then I discovered the secret.
And, Ross, I'm going to tell you
what that secret is
but you must keep it to yourself.
I will take my ears to the grave.
Two words. Women's slacks.
I'm sorry?
Women's slacks.
Women's slacks? Yes.
I'm wearing women's slacks.
You're wearing women's slacks? Yes.
That's nothing like what I thought
you were going to say. Is it not?
It is not.
I thought you were going to give me
a book recommendation, or something.
HE LAUGHS
Book recommendation? I can't read.
No, I don't know what it is,
but women's slacks give me
the confidence I need to survive
in a tough business world.
They're lighter, airier and less
constricted than men's trousers
and I'm pretty sure
it doesn't make me a transvestite.
Look at that shit, look at it.
I can't... How am I supposed to...
It looks like he milked a cow over
it. You're so fussy about coffee.
It's very annoying. It's ruined.
He ruined my coffee.
Don't just chuck it like that.
That fellow shouldn't be allowed to
be a barista. Why not?
Because he's too small, Jen. He's
clearly too small to be a barista.
What? You're being a bit of
a small person racist, Roy.
A small person racist?
That's not a thing.
You can't have tiny baristas, Jen.
For God's sake,
the man works with steam.
I'm going
to have to have a word with him.
Have a word with him?
That's right. About his height?
I think he'd appreciate
the feedback. About his height?
That's not what people do, Roy.
Well, I'm not people, Jen,
and I think that's a good thing.
I'm not afraid to cut through
the bullshit.
I bet this is exactly what Alice
was talking about. Autistic.
She said, "Autistic."
That's what happened.
No, I don't think so. There is no
artistic spectrum.
But she's so...
Did she say it during an argument,
by any chance?
She did say it during a...
She did say it...
You know what was weird, was
we were having quite a big argument
and then suddenly, out of nowhere,
she paid me that lovely compliment.
PHONE RINGS
Hey, baby.
Oh, oh, good, good, yes.
Sure, yeah, I'd love to.
Yes, OK, well I'll see you there.
What? Why? No.
Hello? Alice?
That was weird. What? OK,
so, what the hell is that?
So she tells me that her grandfather
died, she wants me to go to the
funeral. I say that I'd be
delighted, then she hangs up on me.
Her grandfather's funeral? Yeah.
That's what you were just talking
about just there. That's right.
You sounded like you were being
invited to Glastonbury.
Oh, funerals are sad. You did not
sound sad.
I wasn't concentrating.
Emotionally artistic? You're
emotionally colour-blind,
that's what you are.
Maybe I am emotional colour-blind.
I was about to confront that
little man. I know.
I was going to give him shit about
his height.
Glad you realise now how
inappropriate that would've been.
I'll just leave him a note.
I'm here on purpose. Oh, yes.
I'm interested in women's slacks.
I see.
I'd like... Sorry. Hot ear.
I'd like to buy a pair
of women's slacks.
For me, not for a woman.
Oh, yes,
well, that shouldn't be a problem.
I'm not trying to look like a woman.
I understand.
I'm not a confident man.
Quite. Well, let's see what we can
do for you.
I don't know about this.
Oh, just ask them, Jen.
Me and Juan, we have a thing.
I don't want another splashy-splashy
coffee from the teeny-tiny
coffee man. Poor woman.
No, no, no, don't give her money.
You're not supposed to do that.
I'm actually a person,
Roy, with human feelings.
SHE GIBBERS
I'm sorry, I thought you were...
I don't know if you want money. I'm
sorry, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry. What happened?
Never mind, just go.
SHE GIBBERS
What do you think? I think...
you just sold a brother some slacks.
Help, help, get off me!
Let go. You're a bully.
Need to save that old woman,
but I have no confidence.
Hey!
Thank you.
Hey, come, come, no queue for you.
Come on.
Hello, Juan. I'm with her.
It must be my birthday. I get to see
you twice so quick. Back again.
Same as usual, please.
Could I ask you a huge favour
and ask you to make Roy's
coffee for him, too?
I've been going on and on about you.
And I like what I heard.
Would that be OK?
Would you mind?
Of course, anything for you, my
sweet. OK.
Slippery fingers.
It's all right. It's not all right.
Look, it looks like me with a beard.
I don't want this. It's horrible.
Oh, my God! I didn't mean to.
I don't hate you.
None of this is on purpose.
SHE GIBBERS
What can I do?
Let me give you some money.
I'm not with her.
Oi! Oi! Did you write this comment?
What? No.
You've got a problem with
smaller people?
I don't have a problem with small
people, OK? I don't.
I just don't want you
making my coffee.
Because you're bad at it.
You're bad at making coffee.
You're too small. You're too
small to make good coffee.
You know what? Up yours. No!
Little man, watch out!
It's being called
the viral video of the year.
A woman throws her coffee
onto a tramp
and then a man has an argument
with a small barista.
You're just too small.
The barista goes to cross the road
and is hit by a van with breasts.
The woman who's been dubbed by
various online commentators
as Coffee Tramp Toss Bitch
has not been identified,
while the man known as
Small Person Racist was also...
Small people are not a race.
This isn't Game Of Thrones.
They're actually calling me
a bitch on the news.
What the hell happened there?
How did you find out it was us?
It's all here in the weekly
surveillance report.
What's going on, Joan?
I expect better from my assistant.
I'm not your assistant.
My name isn't Joan.
What's your beef with the homeless?
I don't have any homeless beef.
Ah, so it's women you hate.
Well, that I can understand.
Whoa, whoa, you record our
e-mails and tape our phone calls?
All right, dry your eyes, Bono.
If you've nothing to hide,
you've nothing to fear.
It wasn't my fault Mr Reynholm.
I would never throw coffee over
a homeless woman.
I would never abuse a small person,
certainly not enough to make a van
with tits hit him.
Although, I suppose I sort of did.
I sort of did my one, too.
It's frustrating that we did
both of our things. Yes, it is.
All right, spare me.
I was young once, but if this gets
out, this could deeply damage
Reynholm Industry's ability to make
that product that we make.
What do you want us
to do, Mr Reynholm?
Don't do anything. Stay
out of trouble and remain there.
There are places lower than
the basement.
Stop worrying, Jen. Nobody can
make us out in that video.
It's just like early footage of
happy slapping. Just relax.
I can't relax. It's all
right for you. I have plans.
I want to get up there. I will not
be a social piranha. A what, now?
Jim, take a look at this. What is it?
It's the new-look game board.
200,000 views?
I know. It's a bit different.
Check it out. Game board.
Shut the fridge. It's...
Game board.
BLEEP game board.
Say what?
Wow!
You all seem different somehow. Yes.
We're all wearing women's trousers.
Oh. Right.
Hey, what's going on? Let's get the
game board.
He is... Newton Sinclair.
This guy is... Roger Booth.
And I guess I'm still Maurice Moss.
Are you wearing your trousers now?
I couldn't wear them all the time,
Jen - I'd have a heart attack.
No, they're safely locked
away in my fortress of solitude.
It's funny - when I wear them,
I'm a dynamo.
A young Leonard Kravitz,
people hanging off my every word.
And then as soon as I take them off,
I'm just back to being the same...
She's gone, hasn't she? She's gone.
She went quite a while ago. Yeah.
Oh, Michael Buble's here.
No, no, it's a funeral, Moss.
I have to go to this
funeral for Alice's grandfather
and I'm not looking forward to it.
Funerals are pain in the crack.
Even in the best of circumstances,
they're no picnic,
but now I've got Alice on my arse,
like the emotion police.
I'm going to have to look
convincingly sad
for the majority of the day.
She's not going to expect me to cry,
is she? No. What if she does?
I can't cry on cue. What do I do
then?
Do what I do when I need to cry.
Use a mild pepper-spray solution.
Now that makes sense. See?
That makes more sense than
having to feel something.
Do you have any of that stuff here?
Why do you think
we have a mini-fridge?
Good evening.
You've got quite a lot of it.
I suppose I have made
quite a lot of it.
And what's in here? Just Tabasco,
wasabi and a bit of tear gas.
Those sound like bad things to put
in your eyes. It's extremely mild.
It's mainly water. OK, I'll take it
as a last resort. As a last resort?
In case I find myself out
of my emotional death. There you go.
All right. Thanks, Moss.
Bye. Bye.
Oh, don't forget to add the water.
CHURCH BELLS CHIME
ORGAN MUSIC PLAYS
Oh, poor Pip Pop.
Sorry, what?
Pip Pop...
We always called him Pip Pop
because he was so short.
All of my family on that side
are really short.
Is that right?
SHE WEEPS
Oh...
Oh, Alice.
Shh...
Oh!
Roy, are you all right? Holy...!
Yeah, it just really hurts.
Oh, darling.
Oh, it hurts. I know. I know.
Oh...
Oh, Christ,
why is this happening?
COMMENTARY: 'Will we ever find out
just who this person was?
'Unfortunately, with current
technology we can't depixelate
'the picture, so it's very unlikely
we'll ever find out
'the identity of
this dreadful ginger cow.'
Oh, are you still crying?
I don't seem to be able to stop.
One of the pallbearers wasn't able
to make it. Oh...
Look, I know this is a bit weird.
Do you mind stepping in?
I'm happy to. I mean, I'm sadly
happy to. Yeah, that's fine.
That's fine.
Hi, thanks so much for helping us
out. No problem.
Hey!
Hello. Oh, there's another one.
Hi. Are these the other
pallbearers? Yeah.
So you guys and me, we are going to
carry the coffin together? Yes.
We are going to put the casket
on our collective shoulders
and walk in a straight line with it?
No, it didn't go well, Jen.
It didn't go well at all.
I mean, thanks for asking,
but no, it wasn't a success.
It wasn't a successful funeral
for me.
It didn't have the required
gravitas.
Gravitas? No, no.
It wasn't very dignified.
It wasn't dignified at all, Jen.
If I had to pick a word to describe
Pip Pop's final journey
to the grave, it would be "funny".
It was so funny, Jen.
Of course, I tried not to laugh
and I tried to put
other things in my head,
but every step that we took
was a fresh reminder
of just how funny
the whole thing was!
You didn't laugh, did you?
I laughed my hole off.
I can't believe
she's still with you.
I suppose, but, I mean, I'm hanging
on by a thread, Jen.
I think I'll just get through it
as long as nothing else bad happens.
TELEPHONE RINGS
There's the phone now.
COMMENTARY: 'The new footage has led
to the pair being identified,
'Jen Barber and Roy Trenneman, both
employees at Reynholm Industries.'
What the hell were you thinking?
I told you to keep a low profile
and you do it again!
No, no, no, no, no, it's new
footage, Mr Reynholm.
Bum your excuses!
Reynholm Industries has
a reputation to uphold.
We're not News International,
for Christ's sake!
I'm going to have to do Secret
"Pissing" Millionaire now
just to undo your damage!
And I'm missing out
on a massive party!
You're no longer my assistant.
I'm furious.
And I'll tell you something else,
when I return from the estate,
it's...
..for you.
Oh...
MOBILE PHONE RINGS
Oh!
Oh, hey, baby.
Oh, yeah, of course.
No, absolutely.
All right, OK. Bye-bye.
She left you? She did. Yeah.
As the identities
of Coffee Toss Tramp Bitch
and Small Person Racist
are finally revealed,
we at Channel 4 News ask,
"What the hell
is wrong with people?"
I've got a lot of new
followers on Chitter.
Loads more followers, yeah.
They're all very abusive.
They wish we were dead.
Wait.
What? Chitter.
We can use Chitter
to explain ourselves.
Yeah.
Chitter is the perfect place to
explain a complex situation.
I know that.
"I didn't mean to throw
coffee on that woman.
"I didn't know she was there.
"I went back to try and find her
but..."
Oh... Too many characters.
Too many characters.
Got it.
"Hate the homeless.
"And I suppose I hate women, too?
"LOL."
Send.
Whoa. You didn't just send
that, did you? Yes.
That didn't sound so good.
People get the sense of it,
that's the thing about Chitter.
It's best if you're conversational
and off-the-cuff.
Here it is.
Oh... You didn't put a question
mark after the first sentence.
You don't need to
use proper grammar on Chitter.
What you've Chitted here, Jen,
is,
"Hate the homeless and I suppose
I hate women, too. LOL."
Phew, I'm glad all that's over.
JEN GROWLS
EVIL LAUGHTER
SCREAMING
You're too small,
you're just too small!
too small, too small...
'Which then leads to him
being hit by a van with tits.'
And now Anonymous are after us.
Well, that's just ideal.
Oh, a bunch of nerds sitting
at their computer, what can they do?
We pissed off the Internet, Jen.
The Internet is coming to get us!
Well, let's get IT
before IT gets us.
What are you...?
Oh, I don't want Anonymous after me.
I'm in anonymous...
I think.
Let's hide it.
What?
The Internet.
Oh...
Because we told you
that was the Internet?
Yes.
We never told you
it wasn't the Internet?
No.
Well, the thing is, Jen...
that's not the Internet.
What's Jen doing with the Internet?
We're not doing that. Oh...
Crickets!
Right, don't be scared, yeah.
We're all friends here.
Tell Dougie your story?
OK, but who is he again?
I'm just your average social worker.
Yes, just in the area
having a look around.
Please just pretend I'm not here.
Do you ever have anyone come round
and help you and stuff?
Granddad, sometimes.
He's hardly around.
What about your dad?
He's never around, either...
BEEPING INTERRUPTS
Sorry, my friend, I need to stop you
there. I must take this.
Reynholm...
What? Well, increase the bid.
I don't care what I said
the ceiling was.
I want that artwork by Madonna.
Now, 22 million is the minimum
but I'm happy to go to 50.
In fact, make 50 the new minimum.
Yes, yes.
I can't talk right now.
I'm doing Secret Millionaire.
That's very sad.
Do you want to shut up,
we're filming Secret Millionaire.
Check your privilege.
How am I finding it so far?
To be honest with you, it's not as
god-awful as I thought it would be.
People have been terribly nice.
They're actually quite clean.
I have been invited
to a party this evening.
The last party I ever went to was
when Elton John's dog had a baby.
LOUD MUSIC PLAYS
I tell a lie. The last party I went
to was when
Conrad Black got arrested.
Conrad Black, who's that?
Oh, no-one, just an old friend.
Let's get in there.
Yeah, sure.
So I thought with Game Board's
increased viewership,
perhaps it would be a good place
to put my side of the story and
show the world I'm not the monster
I'm currently supposed to be.
Boo! Boo!
Don't boo, please.
That is a horrible T-shirt.
So the question everyone is asking,
Jen Barber, do you hate women?
Oh...
Thank you, Jen Barber.
Coming up, what was it like to be
a 14th-century grain merchant?
Wait, I don't know if that was
clear. Sorry, it's these trousers.
They make me want to move
onto the next item. It's better
broadcasting and the slacks know it!
Coming up. Will you stop saying,
"Coming up". Next... I don't know
if they got my point!
Oh, gosh!
Oh!
Oh, gosh.
Richmond, do you work here or not?
I don't get paid,
but I like to come in.
So that Goth to boss thing didn't
work out?
Does it look like it worked out?
Anyway, how have you guys been?
Everyone thinks I'm a misogynist.
Roy lost his girlfriend because
he's emotionally colour-blind
and Moss is wearing trousers
that make him good at telly.
Any gossip?
What's going on with you?
Oh, you know, keeping busy,
voice-over work mainly.
Really, how did that happen?
Someone just noticed
I had a beautiful voice.
Oh, Richmond.
Things aren't going well at all.
Just get in there.
It's just not the same
when you guys aren't together.
Anyway, if you want me,
you know where I am.
I don't, though, Richmond.
Don't...lurk!
Where did he go?
Where did who go?
Does it ever seem to you that
the things that happen to us
are sort of...
strange?
How so, Roy?
Well...
remember when I had to pretend
to be disabled
and I ended up in Manchester?
That wasn't a normal thing
to happen, was it?
Or when you ended up spending
the night in that arcade machine.
That was odd.
I suppose those were unusual events.
And this is strange.
What's happening to us
right now is strange, isn't it?
Well, at least,
it'll all be over soon.
Douglas is bound to fire us
when he gets back.
Come on, guys, this isn't us.
Are we just going to sit here
and take it?
What do we normally do
when we get into a scrape?
We normally make things worse
and worse and then it ends.
No, we don't. We stick together.
That doesn't sound like us.
Don't know where you're getting that
from... Come on, who are we?
Who are we? I want to hear
you say it!
We're the IT... We're the IT...
..Department.
You're goddamn right we are!
Are you wearing women's slacks?
Yes, I am.
This is exactly what
I'm talking about.
Let's get into a car
and cruise around.
How to get into a car?
Smash a window. Great idea.
That's the one.
I'm such an idiot.
I've got a robot hand.
Hang on a second. This is MY car.
HEAVY BASS LINE PLAYS
MELLOW CLASSICAL PIANO PLAYS
HEAVY METAL PLAYS
POLICE SIREN WAILS
Oh, shit. Wow-wow-wow.
It's all right, everyone, be cool.
I'll handle this. Take that.
It's all right, Officer, I'm doing
Secret Millionaire.
Come on, come on, come on, people.
What's going on?
How long has he been wearing the
trousers? He won't take them off.
OK, come on, come on, come on...
What's going on, what's going on?
We don't know what's happening.
OK, come on. To every problem,
there's a solution.
What's our problem here?
What's our problem?
Everyone thinks I'm a cow who
hates women. You're a cow.
Terrible cow. Women, OK.
Roy, hurt me.
Erm, the woman I love thinks that
I hate small people.
Small people, thank you, Roy.
I'm probably going to die alone
in front of computer pornography?
I'll just draw a sad face.
OK, so what do women and
small people both like?
What do they both like? Chairs.
Films. I really don't know.
I'll tell you. It's just they seem
like very different groups.
Very different groups.
Not being attacked.
They both love not being attacked.
Well, I can't speak for small people,
obviously, but as a woman,
I certainly like not being attacked.
Where are you going with this, Moss?
I'll tell you exactly where I'm
going with this, Roy.
I'm saying that we use this brief
window, while Douglas is away,
to produce a pepper-spray
solution for small women,
using that stuff I gave Roy earlier.
That sounds really weird.
Jen Barber, not a hater of women
but their defender, their champion.
I love it now.
And I can do a massive presentation.
A self-defence pepper spray for
small women suits my purposes also.
It will show Alice that I care and,
as a woman with small relatives,
she's sure to come to Jen's
presentation.
You know, when I first stocked
that mini-fridge
with pepper-spray solution,
I thought I'd made too much...but
only now do I realise
that I'd made exactly the right
amount for our current purposes.
It almost seems like it's
too good an idea.
You see what we can do when we work
together? With my business acumen...
My scientific know-how...
And I'm also here...
We can do anything! Yes! Yes!
I need a trouser break.
You coming, Roy?
I can't seem to get the wording
of this speech to Alice right.
You're doing a speech?
Yeah, I need to show her that I'm
not emotionally colour-blind.
I'm actually a very sensitive human
man, and she needs to know that.
Oooh, what's a more romantic word
for "knockers"?
A MORE romantic word?
Come on, guys. Let's protect women!
I'll meet you up there. Good luck.
Thanks.
Eartha Kitts!
Right, is everything ready?
Yeah, well, I've got the posters up
and I've put gift bags with pepper
spray beside each chair.
Now, I think it was a master stroke
to put the spray in these
elegant bottles.
Why not look stylish
while you defend yourself?
Something's bothering me, though.
Are we missing something that's very
obviously wrong with this idea?
I really don't think so. Oh, look,
here comes everyone.
Hello, and welcome to this
very special
presentation for women by a woman, me
a woman, who loves women.
By your seats you'll find a gift bag,
and in that gift bag
you'll find our very
exciting new product.
No, don't do that.
SCREAMING
No, you're not supposed to...
Yes! I have some things
I have to say to you!
No, I need to go.
No, you are going nowhere.
Now, I know in the past that you
have accused me
of being emotionally colour-blind.
SHE SCREAMS
Shut up and listen. But now I've
changed - my sight is perfect.
Now I know what was wrong
with the idea.
With your sweet lips and, of
course, your lovely bangers,
I know you're the one for me.
I'm in terrible pain.
Me, too, Alice, me, too, but that
ends now. It ends now.
That could not have gone better.
Oh, no, Roy, that didn't go
well at all.
Oh, right, because we're going to
lose our jobs.
Argh!
Mr Reynholm...
So, that's the thing. I gave the boy
the can of lager,
so technically I'm guilty of
corrupting a minor.
So it's the reason why
I bought the tramp uniform
and I've had to make myself scarce.
So, you need somewhere to hide out?
Yeah, somewhere off-piste.
Somewhere where no-one will find you.
Bottom of the world.
You can use our office
if you'd like. Whoo.
Well, I'll need someone to take
care of business upstairs.
We're not doing anything.
Well, this is perfect.
My wonderful assistant, Joan,
and her two friends, Ross.
I'm going to go and piss around
on the internet
but actually I'll need some food.
I've already eaten one of
the toys in here.
Did he just say what I think he
said? I wasn't really listening.
Is this... Is what's happening good
now? Is this good?
Yes, it's a very good outcome.
Oh, my God!
I think we've come out on top,
I can't believe it.
We've come out on top.
'Jen Barber.'
Oh, I forgot about you.
Oh, God, that's impressive.
They're actually watching us.
Hey, mate, am I an anonymous?
Silence, you person wasters.
Greetings, Jen Barber.
This is your sentence.
You've been found guilty of the most
appalling lack of basic human
kindness and decency.
KNOCKING ON DOOR
Come in.
Shush, you. Peter, what are you
doing in there? Shut up!
You've been there for hours.
I'm doing something. Go away!
Peter, your mum and I are worried
about you. Get out.
You need to get off this computer.
Who is this? Are these your friends?
I'm sorry. Peter can't play any
more. He's coming outside.
'You said I could stay
here as long as I wanted.'
We said that you had to come out.
MUFFLED VOICE ON MONITOR
'..do my homework...
'I've done my homework...
'I know my rights...'
WAILS ON MONITOR
This internet's not working.
I can't connect.
Just try turning it off
and on again.
Thanks, Ross.
RICHMOND: Reynholm Industries
is changing.
New opportunities, new faces,
a new direction.
A better workplace environment.
Exciting new products.
An inclusive hiring policy...
I am sounding happy?
Can you be a little bit more...
Yeah, this is me being happy.
Just be a bit more, I don't know...
I'm being upbeat.
No, I just want you to speak...
Ah, forget it, let's just stop.
Subtitles by Red Bee Media Ltd