[orchestral fanfare]
[Star Wars theme playing]
[male narrator] Missing in action!
Anakin Skywalker's
heroic droid navigator R2-D2
was lost in battle.
When a desperate search
fails to locate R2,
Anakin is forced to take on
a new navigator, R3-S6.
Now the Jedi embark
on a dangerous new mission,
to find the secret enemy listening post.
Meanwhile, R2-D2 has fallen into the hands
of a vile droid smuggler
and is on his way to General Grievous,
who will surely plunder
the Republic secrets
hidden within him.
I am entering your orbit now, general.
I will be at your station shortly.
And, general...
What is it, Gha Nachkt?
I prefer to get my reward in cash.
[growls]
[sinister chuckle]
We've searched their supply grids, sir.
There's nothing to indicate the presence
of an enemy outpost.
[rock music playing]
-[beeping]
-Huh?
Master, I'm receiving
a strange transmission.
-I can't seem to make it out, though.
-[warbled sounds]
Boost the volume, Goldie.
[beeps]
No, you're losing it.
-[distorted beeps]
-That's R2.
Uh, that doesn't sound like R2.
It's him. I could never forget that voice.
Trace it, Rex.
-Sir.
-What is going on here?
[beeping]
You sneaky little scrap pile.
[fizzling]
[screams]
You'd better be worth all this trouble.
[whimpers]
[laughs]
Master, our orders were to find
the Separatist listening post.
Perhaps R2 is at the listening post.
Did you consider that?
We have a lock on
the droid's location, sir.
Prepare to jump to those coordinates.
Yes, sir.
[whirring]
Hold on, R2, old buddy.
We're coming.
What is it, Gha Nachkt?
I've arrived.
Could you lower your shields?
-[speaking in alien language]
-[zaps]
-[beeps]
-Keep moving, grease spot.
[speaking in alien language]
-[beeps]
-Ah.
This is the droid those Jedi
came looking for, general.
What secrets do you carry,
my little friend?
[beeps]
So defiant.
No need for fear.
We're all droids here.
[laughs]
Rip this little runt apart
and find out everything he knows.
Ooh!
-Right away, general.
-[zapping]
[beeping]
Sir, the last transmission came from
that moon's upper atmosphere,
directly ahead.
[beeping]
That's a Separatist battle sphere.
I'm picking up a lot of encrypted chatter.
Contact Obi-Wan.
Stubby, scramble Secret Code Set 1477.
I don't want that station to pick this up.
Anakin?
Master, I believe we've found
your Separatist listening post.
Excellent work. Back off and wait.
I'll send two mainline cruisers
to help you destroy it.
But R2.
We believe my droid, R2, is on board.
He's the one that led us here.
Hmm, this complicates things.
You must sneak aboard
that station and destroy it
before they crack R2's memory banks.
I know you're fond of that droid,
but he's fallen into enemy hands.
I could rescue R2.
No, this is not a rescue mission.
Keep jamming their scanners.
If they spot us, we're dead.
We're bringing the droid?
We'll need Goldie to open secured hatches
and access the station's computer for us.
Oh, and, Rex, you get to carry him.
-[beeping]
-Ah, that's just great.
Follow me, boys!
Take this upstairs
and be sure not to drop it.
Whoa! Ow.
Those 631s are not the brightest lights
on the ship.
Next time, you're lugging
this astromech around.
[laughter]
[metal grinding]
All this moisture is
corroding my servo-motors.
Go up to level eight.
Get your head adjusted.
It feels great.
That'll feel gr...
What the...? [grunts]
All right, Stubby. Get to work.
We are here.
The reactors are 30 levels
below us, there.
Ahsoka, you take the squad
and blow up those reactors.
Gravity will do the rest.
-We'll meet in the landing bay.
-Where are you going?
I'm just gonna have a little look around.
I hope you find R2 in one piece.
[beeping]
This is... This is...
General Grievous!
What is it?
It appears this droid's mission memory
has never been erased.
It contains every Republic formation
and strategy they have.
Good work.
You certainly earned your fee this time.
More than my fee.
This droid is worth more, I get paid more.
Now, I suggest... [screams]
[laughs]
There is your bonus.
[beeping]
Report, Agent R3.
The Jedi are here?
Delay them until I arrive.
[beeping]
Goldie, where are you?
Sound the alarm.
-What are you doing back here?
-[beeps]
Come on.
Now we will transfer
all your secrets to me.
-[whirring]
-Don't worry,
I won't let anything happen to you.
[whirring]
Republic troops have infiltrated the base.
Keep this droid secure.
[speaking in alien language]
I will deal with the Jedi myself.
[beeps]
We found the reactor room, sir.
The alarm triggered another security door,
ray-shielded.
This could take a while to bypass.
-Good luck with that.
-Go ahead, Goldie.
Make me proud.
Oh, this'll be good.
[footsteps marching]
Those droids are getting close, sir.
Do you think R3's going
to open up that door anytime soon?
He's working on it.
Patience, captain.
[footsteps approaching]
I can always hot-wire it, sir.
-Hurry up, Goldie.
-[whirring]
I think we've run out of time.
-Blast 'em!
-[zapping]
Rex, droid poppers, now!
Droid poppers!
[beeping]
[fizzling]
Take the captured R2 unit to my ship.
They sent a child to destroy my station?
The Republic must be running out of Jedi.
You must be General Grievous.
[laughs]
[coughing]
He's just another tinny, boys.
Let's scrap him like the rest.
[lightsabers zapping]
Oh! [grunts]
Sorry to interrupt your playtime, Grumpy,
but wouldn't you prefer a challenge?
That wouldn't be you.
[roars]
All units, stay on high alert.
Watch out for a second Jedi
loose in the station.
-[beeping]
-R2!
[zapping]
Hang on, R2!
Where is the fight
you promised me, youngling?
[beeping]
Ahsoka, it's me, Rex.
There are only two of us left.
Should we abort the mission?
No, complete the mission.
Set the charges
and rendezvous at the landing bay.
-[Rex] But, sir--
-That's an order, Rex.
I'll keep the general busy. Ahsoka out.
She's distracting Grievous. Come on.
We've still got a job to do.
Come here, child.
I'm looking for you.
So far, you have failed to impress me.
Goldie, over here.
[beeping]
Goldie, no! [gasps]
[Rex] Ahsoka, we're in the reactor...
Your friends won't help you.
You're stuck with me.
[lightsaber whooshes]
You have something that belongs to me.
[beeps]
[fizzling]
Thanks, R2.
[beeping]
It's great to see you too, buddy.
You don't look so good. You okay?
[beeping]
[beeps]
Rex? Rex, can you hear me?
R3? R3, is that you?
I've got R2.
I'll meet you back at the landing bay.
[beeping]
R3? Uh, yeah.
I had to get a replacement droid.
Look, sorry, R2.
-[beeps angrily]
-It was Obi-Wan's idea.
Look, we'll talk about this later.
Twilight, this is Skywalker.
Rendezvous at the south landing bay
immediately for evacuation.
Acknowledged, general. I'm on my way.
R3, what have you to report?
[beeping]
That stubby little backstabber.
So Skywalker has come for his R2 unit.
[laughs]
Go and make certain they do not escape.
Great, there's the Twilight.
Now where's everyone else?
-Sir.
-[R3-S6 whirring]
Hey, Stubby, where's Ahsoka?
General Skywalker.
Explosives are in place, sir.
Objective completed.
Where is Ahsoka?
She engaged General Grievous.
Alone?
She distracted him
while we completed the mission.
It was on her orders, sir.
-The droid was with her.
-We got to find her.
I can take you to her, sir.
What is the matter with you?
Are you trying to get us killed?
[squeaks]
[metal clanging]
I've got a bad feeling about this, sir.
That double-crossing droid is a spy.
[beeping]
[zapping]
[growling]
[grunting]
Another lightsaber
to add to my collection.
My spy droid, R3,
has trapped your precious master.
When I've finished with you,
he's next.
You're wrong.
He's gone by now,
and he's gonna blow up
your precious spy station.
Not this time.
[zapping]
Captain, trigger the explosives.
But, sir, we're still in the station.
You just let me worry about the details.
Sir, yes, sir.
[explosions]
[rumbling]
[growling]
[zapping]
R2, I need you to get
the hangar door open.
See if there are any controls
on the outer platform.
[beeping]
-[fizzling]
-[whirring]
So, what did I miss?
Oh, the usual.
It was foolish of you
to take on Grievous by yourself.
Well, I was leading the mission,
and it seemed like
a good idea at the time.
[zapping]
Did he tell you your stubby little
gold droid pal works for him?
He might have mentioned it.
I guess we were all fooled.
General Skywalker,
there are fuel cells over here.
Get ready, Rex.
-R2 did it.
-Of course, he did it.
Now let's get out of here.
R2, where are you?
[explosions]
[beeping]
General Skywalker has
gotten into his fighter.
Where's he going?
He's going after R2.
I'll be right back. Don't wait for me.
[beeping]
[screaming]
Come on, R2.
[beeping]
So let me get this straight, Anakin.
You risked the mission, all your men,
even your Padawan
to save a droid.
R2 found the listening post,
and he saved our lives.
We couldn't just leave him there, Obi-Wan.
Oh, Anakin.
One day...
I'm glad we got R2 back, master.
But Obi-Wan does have a point.
Ahsoka, I knew you would
complete the mission.
Besides, R2 is more than a droid.
He's a friend.
[beeping]
[orchestral fanfare]
[Star Wars theme playing]
[R2-D2 beeping]