This programme contains adult humour
Which means...
which means a profit so far
this year of 18 hundred billion
billion.
Splendid.
Not including the added revenue
arising from your takeover of ITV.
ITV, I'd forgotten about ITV.
Brilliant!
Gentlemen, when I first started
Renham Industries I had just
two things in my possession...
Today, I have a business empire
the like of which...
The world has never
seen the like of which.
I hope it doesn't sound
arrogant when I say that I am
the greatest man in the world.
Hear, hear.
Gentlemen, to the future.
Oh, you don't have any glasses.
Just pretend. The future.
The future.
Sorry to interrupt
but there are some policemen here.
They say they need to speak
to you about irregularities
in the pension fund.
I see. Could you make them
a cup of tea, please, Stephanie?
Nice.
Isn't she a beauty?
It's certainly a phone.
160 ppi screen, wi-fi enabled...
Ask me what kind of phone I've got.
What kind of phone have you got?
It doesn't matter.
Voice recognition.
So if I wanted
to call my mum, I'd say "mum"
and it calls her. I don't need to
do anything. It's the dog's bollocks.
Hello. Hello.
Oh, no. Mum, mum, no... no I'm sorry.
No, Moss said that.
I'll call you later. Bye.
Only problem with it is that it's
got a very weedy vibrate setting.
I mean it... Watch this.
I mean what is that?
I'll sort it out.
Oh, could you? Just...
welly up the vibrate on it a bit.
OK, all right.
Now will you answer this question?
Oh... are we still on this?
We would have been done ages
ago but you keep interrupting...
All right, all right, OK, go on.
Question 39, when was
the last time you exercised?
Ahh, the last time
I exercised was never.
I'm still reeling
from your answer to question 12.
What was question 12?
You brush your teeth in the bath.
So?
That's where your balls are.
OK, question 40, do you
get your five fruit and veg?
Oohh, oh, I mean I certainly try to.
I would say I prob...I probably do.
A day.
A what?!
OK, you are going to love this.
This website takes all that
information you just gave me
and guess what it does? It actually
estimates the date of your death.
WHAT?!
Unbelievable, isn't it?
Wait a second.
I know about those.
Everyone knows about those.
Oh, right, so you've already
done it. So when's the big day?
No. I haven't done it.
Why would I want to do it?
I go March 2nd, 2079.
Oh, my God.
I've got 70 more years.
OK, Moss, close that window.
I do not wanna know.
But I've written it all in now.
Moss! I do not wanna know
the date of my death.
Close it.
Hello, IT.
Have you tried turning it off... You
know what, I'm sick of saying that.
What do you want?
OK.
Yeah, someone'll be up in a minute.
Maybe.
You looked! You know!
You know when I'm going to die.
I do, yes.
I told you not to look.
I made a mistake.
Oh, aww.
When is it?
You don't wanna know.
You can't say that to me now.
My advice, Roy,
is to forget all about this.
Why, how long have they given me?
20 years?
It's less than 20?
You see I don't think this is
taking into account leap years
so that could well be
something to hang on to.
What does it say, Moss? Does...
does it say I'm already dead?
Oh, no, that'd be terrible.
It's Thursday.
WHAT?!
Thursday?!
Again, remember, leap years.
It's Thursday! Thursday's the 3rd.
Although not till late afternoon
so that gives you most of the day.
3pm.
How can they be that specific?
Yeah. It's silly.
Yeah.
These things are at best
79% accurate.
Oh, good.
I would take
no further notice of it.
Yeah.
Yeah, no, you're right. It's silly.
I will take no further notice of it.
There's something wrong
with all the computers on seven.
Who wants it? Roy?
Ohh, you look terrible.
Are you ill?
I don't know.
This idiot's
disabled the flippin' file.
Er, yeah, hello... Excuse me.
Thank you. Um...
some attention, please.
I know you don't think it's
important or cool but there is
a ruddy good reason why we put up
anti-viral software and firewalls.
It's because there are a lot
of dangerous things out there.
JESUS!
Oh, you know, all right, come down.
Just don't disable the files.
OK, 73, that's good, that's good.
And, um mum,
what age did Uncle Tony die?
32!
Oh, it was a car accident. Brilliant.
OK. No, I completely forgot.
OK. Oh, mum, I have to go.
Unbelievable, some brainiac disabled
his firewall which means that all of
the computers on floor seven are
teaming with viruses, plus I've just
had to walk all the way
down the mother-fudging stairs
because the lift is broken again.
Oh, my God. What?
Oh, my God.
What... What is it?
Denholm's dead.
Oh, yes, and Denholm's dead.
OK, everyone ready?
Wow, you look great.
We should go to more funerals.
Yeah, except is there any chance
that I could not go to this one?
No. why?
It's just, you know, funerals.
So morbid.
Oh, will you please forget
this website nonsense?
You are not going to die.
Come on, cheer up,
you're gonna ruin the funeral.
You're right. Pay no attention to me.
I'm being an idiot.
Dead man walking.
Very funny.
You crazy little bastard.
So when did you last exercise, Jen?
Oooh, no, you are
not gonna do it to me.
Scared?
No. I happen to think
I have a good few years left.
I take plenty of exercise and I
haven't smoked for three years.
I didn't know you smoked.
Oh, yeah,
I was on 40 a day by the end.
40 a day? That's 146,002 a decade,
presuming there's two leap years,
how the flip did you give up?
Basically pure self control, Moss.
No, no, I'd never smoke again.
I'd rather lick a tramp.
Derek, hello.
Hello, Jen.
Thank you for printing up
those funeral announcements.
Oh, no, no, I enjoyed doing it.
You know, in a...in a...
in a...in a sad way.
Can I have a word, please?
Sure.
Oh, hey, oh, my phone, oh, cool,
have you, um...souped it up?
Yeah, I've totally
pimped your phone, girlfriend.
BELLOWING BASS
Is that the highest setting?
That is the lowest setting.
It should come as no surprise
that I don't like this department.
Never have, never will.
I see no need for an IT department
and I would much rather use
this basement for something
important, like a big toilet.
Oooh, I have to say that
actually is a bit of a surprise.
Really? I did send out a memo.
I didn't get it. I...
I had no idea you felt like this.
Well, I do. However, I am
prepared to give you another chance.
Another chance? But I didn't
know we'd already had a chance.
This should be the first chance.
You should give us this chance
and then another chance.
LAUGHTER
OK, OK, now,
give me a go, give me a go.
I... I gotta put it up to five.
I'm gonna put it in my pocket.
Put it up to eight.
I'm not putting it up to eight,
Moss, it'll blow my cock off.
Go on, put it up.
OK, OK, I'll put it up.
You do know we are burying
a great man today?
Did someone else die?
I mean Mr Renham.
'Did someone else die?'
Well, I didn't know.
You have to be careful.
He's our new boss.
He hates us. He says doesn't need
to be an IT department.
Why did no-one tell me this?
There was a memo, it just said
"I hate the IT department".
Oh, no, no, no, no, you are not
coming to the funeral, Richmond.
What funeral?
CHURCH BELLS TOLL
Oh.
Has anyone got the right time?
It's twenty to three.
I make it a quarter to. Why?
Oh, yes, because that website
said you were going to die at three,
didn't it?
Did it? I... I can't remember.
But how could you forget? It clearly
stated that you were going to die,
today, at precisely three.
Unless it was tomorrow.
But no, it's today at three.
Will you put it out of your mind?
Right.
You're right, out of my mind.
CHORAL MUSIC
OK, there's Denholm's wife.
Never know what to say
to people at funerals.
No, neither do I. I'm terrible.
Oh, just say "I'm sorry
for your loss." Then move on.
He'll be in our prayers.
Thank you.
Sorry for your loss.
Move on.
Thank you.
It's not like you've
lost a pen, is it?
It's so much worse.
Would you like a pen?
I have a spare one.
No, thank you.
Please take it.
Why are you giving it to me?
I don't know.
Swings and roundabouts.
Death!
Death is coming.
Death is here.
Death is outside.
There is no escape.
I don't like the way
Derek's looking at us.
(SNARLS)
Who's that knocking at the door?
Yes, it's death. Let him in.
Is this normal?
Death came for Denholm just
as he will come for you.
Who will be next?
You?
Maybe you.
We are gathered here today...
What's wrong with you?
Nothing.
..for the passing
of a great man.
CLOCK TICK-TOCKS
I've never seen a grandfather
clock in a church before.
Yes, or one with a second hand.
Yes, he had more money than
most of us here today
but did that make him a better man?
(VOICE ECHOES)
We know Denholm was a man of money.
Yes, he had more money...
..than any of us here.
(SIGHS IN RELIEF)
Arghhh...Ooh!
Ohhhh!
Woooooahh!
Oh, Lord Jesus!
Aaaaah! Arr-r-rrghh!
Jesus Christ!
Ohhhh!
Call me an ambulance!
I'm not BLEEP joking! Oh.
I need an ambulance!
I'm not (BLEEP) joking!
Call me a (BLEEP) ambulance!
I'm not f... Oh.
Oh, no, wait.
It's my phone!
PHONE VIBRATES
(MUTTERS TO HIMSELF)
I'll turn it off. I'll just
put it on silent.
Oh, thank (BLEEP).
Go on.
Oh, it's gone to message.
Um oh, hello Roy, nothing important,
just wondering how the funeral went.
Call me back.
If we are all quite ready,
Denholm instructed that this short
film be played before the service.
You're all out of here. You
are out of here. You're history!
Hello.
If you're watching this
it means I'm dead now
and it's all thanks to these
little things.
Ha, wrong!
Shut up.
Cigarettes have finally killed me,
like they killed my father,
like father's father, my mother's
father, my mother and her father.
I just can't seem to give the
damn things up. I love them.
Sweet, smoky cigarettes.
(BREATHES OUT LOUDLY)
You delicious bastards.
Final thought, Stephanie,
could you categorise the personnel
files alphabetically?
That rhyming thing
just isn't working.
Also, call Who's Who
and get them to update my entry.
Well, thanks, everyone, for coming.
Enjoy the rest of the funeral.
Well said, sir.
I will now ask Mr Pippin
to read the eulogy.
I see a lot of faces out there.
Some of you I know,
some of you I hope to get to
know better over the coming months,
some of you I probably won't be
seeing very much of after today.
The reading of the eulogy is a duty
normally left to the eldest child
but, as you all know, Denholm's
son Douglas mysteriously disappeared
after a lengthy court case
seven years ago.
Let me start by
reading this poem that I saw in the
film Four Weddings and a Funeral.
"Stop all the clocks..."
Fathe-e-e-e-e-e-er!
(HUMS)
Arghh!
Tits!
Unhand me, priest.
Where is your God?
Where is your God now?
Here lies a great man, a great man.
Father!
(HE SOBS)
I miss anything?
Just the start of Derek's eulogy.
You stink.
I just smoked a cigarette
from the drain.
Well, who's this?
Hi, I'm Douglas.
Jen Barber.
That's a beautiful second name.
What are you
doing after the funeral, Jen?
Douglas.
Speak, priest.
No, I'm a bit...
Your father prepared a second tape
in the event of your sudden arrival.
A second tape?
I see.
Actually, I don't follow.
I'll just put it on.
Hello again.
If you're watching this
it's because my son from
my first marriage has arrived,
caused a scene
and is currently chatting up
some nearby trollop.
Hey!
Quiet, woman!
Douglas, I have something
important to tell you.
I'm here, Papa.
Reynholm Industries is now yours.
My Lord, thank you, Father.
But it's yours at a price.
Promise me now,
in front of all your new employees,
that you will never again become
embroiled in a sexual harassment
case that damages the company.
I promise, Father.
There's one more thing, Douglas,
but it's for your ears only so I want
you to stop the tape,
take it home
and watch it in private.
But these are my new family, father,
I hold no secrets from them.
OK, Douglas, now we're
alone I can speak frankly.
You may receive a visit
from the police concerning
irregularities in the pension fund.
Turn that off.
..I've been using a very
creative accountant,
recently released from jail,
to manage what I call...
Let me do it. Where's the remote?
..a suck fund.
I'll do it myself!
Goodbye, father. (SOBS)
Right, I'm off.
I'll see you all on Monday.
Oh, Douglas, Douglas. Sorry...
didn't mean to, um... Derek Pippin.
I worked very
closely with your father.
Oh, Derek, good to meet you. I'm
afraid I'll be bringing in my own
people so you're immediately fired.
OK, good luck everyone and, er
I'll see you later.
And you are ready to go.
Brilliant. Thank you, computer man.
I'm told my father was particularly
proud of the IT department,
run by a dynamic go-getter,
a genius and a man from Ireland.
One last thing, how do
I erase files like this one here
marked "pensions".
Um, just like this.
All gone. Wonderful. Thanks guys.
I'll be working very closely with
your department and I have a feeling
I'll be needing you
for a lot more than just deleting
incriminating files.
Ha-ha-ha! I just mean files.
OK, we'd better be off.
By the way, where's that
hootsie-tootsie, hum-dinging,
coochie mama boss of yours?
Um, she went home early. She said
she had some catching up to do.
EASTENDERS THEME TUNE PLAYS
Oh, one last thing,
I sorted out this for you.
Now I'm afraid the vibrate setting is
still a little weedy so you may wanna
put her all the way up to ten.
Ten?
Shall do.
Done.
And done.
(GIGGLING) OK, bye bye.
Sorry about this, old man.
Oh, yes.
LOUD VIBRATE
Oooh.
Ooh! Now, I like that.
LOUD VIBRATE
Oohh.
Ooh. Uoohhh.
Oooh!
VIBRATE CONTINUES
Nearly at the station!
Subtitles by
Red Bee Media Ltd