(THEME SONG PLAYING)
CLARKSON:  Tonight,
a BMW i8 at full chat
in the Yorkshire Moors,
the cream of Hollywood
on our track
and a pointless thing
about old Land Rovers.
(AUDIENCE CHEERING
AND APPLAUDING)
Thank you, everybody.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Thank you,
and welcome.
Welcome to what is
for the first time
in many years
an actual car show.
We've packed it
with mini facts and
a lot of informations.
And we're starting
the ball rolling with this,
the Mercedes SLS.
This was one of my
favourite cars,
and I was very sad
when they stopped making it.
But happily, there is now
a replacement
which I haven't been
driving on the track.
Because James has.
MAY:  This is what
they've come up with.
It's called the AMG GT,
and it costs between
£97,000 and 120,000.
Now, I have to be
entirely honest with you.
When I woke up this morning
and got out of bed
to come and drive this car,
it was with
a certain amount of disquiet.
I've always thought that
AMG Mercedes are a bit,
as my mother would say,
unnecessary.
I don't like the Stormtrooper
body kit look.
I don't really like those
pseudo Special Forces names
like "SLS" and "Black."
Jeremy likes them a lot.
With this car, however,
you sense that something
is different,
that everything's
a bit more grown up.
See, their last coupe,
the SLS, had a massive,
and again,
not entirely necessary,
6.2-litre V8.
This car also has a V8,
but it's a brand-new one.
And it's a
much more modest 4 litres.
Because of that,
you might expect it
to take a little longer
to get from A to B.
However...
(ENGINE REVVING)
The nought to 60 time
of that 6.2-litre SLS
was 3.8 seconds.
On this,
the 4-litre car, it is...
Exactly the same.
The top speeds are almost
exactly the same as well,
both up in the high 190s.
Brute.
And AMG has achieved this
by using brains to make
the brawn.
This car has
two turbochargers.
Normally, turbochargers
would be bolted onto
the outside of the engines,
but on this car, they live
inside the V of the engine.
What this means is
the engine is more compact
and the turbos
are more efficient.
So, this car costs
£50,000 less than the old SLS.
It uses a lot less fuel.
And it still goes
just as quickly.
That is what they call
on  The Apprentice "a win-win."
And then there's the styling,
which also has a new level
of sophistication,
with an interior that's
more James Bond
than Fast & Furious.
On the outside,
it's much the same story.
These doors are
perfectly conventional
in-and-out sort of doors.
They're not like those
idiotic gull-wing things
you get on the SLS
which makes it look as if
it's sniffing its own armpits.
This rear spoiler
is actually an option.
But even that,
by AMG standards,
is quite discreet.
In fact, the whole thing
is quite pretty.
Quite classic, even.
And now we must
move onto cornering,
an activity where
AMG normally scores
maximum points for mentalness.
This is,
when all's said and done,
a 503 horsepower
rear-wheel-drive muscle car,
and that sounds like a recipe
for extreme trickiness.
In fact, you can corner
quickly in this thing,
and without soiling
your trousers.
Which, one again, is thanks
to intelligent engineering.
In a normal car,
the engine and the gearbox,
they're just dead weight
hanging in there,
and they move around a bit,
and sort of spoil the balance
as you go around corners.
In this car, the mountings for
all that stuff are active.
So, as you go through a bend,
they stiffen up to keep
all that weight in check.
It's a bit like the way
a cat can walk along
the top of a fence
using its tail to keep
itself in balance.
However, if, like Jeremy,
you want to devour your
back tyres in one sitting,
you still can.
-(TYRES SCREECHING)
-Yes, thank you.
And then there's the noise.
Are you ready? Here we go.
(ENGINE REVVING)
(BARKING)
(BARKING MORE LOUDLY)
I hate it when
my prejudices are demolished,
but this car
is giving me the fizz.
What I like most of all
is that the GT is
cleverly designed
to be Jekyll and Hyde.
I'm just gonna
quieten it down.
Turn off the manual change,
the noisy exhaust.
We'll put it back
into comfort mode.
Comfort suspension.
There you go.
When you turn all that off,
it turns into this
incredibly civilised,
long-legged cruiser.
I like what they've done.
They've got rid of
the Andy McNab names
and all that nonsense
and they've given us
an AMG for grownups.
I'm glad I got out
of bed this morning.
(AUDIENCE CHEERING
AND APPLAUDING)
It's what I've been saying
for a long time.
So there you go, May.
Ha ha ha.
I've been saying for ages,
AMG Mercs are brilliant.
Yes, there a couple
of massive problems
-with this one, though.
-What?
Well, firstly,
it reminds me of you.
The second one is,
let's be honest,
for not much more than
half the price of this,
you could have
a Nissan GT-R,
which, as we have established,
is the finest car
in the world.
It's certainly up there,
I'll grant you that.
But I'll tell you
what we'll do.
We'll sort it out
on the track, okay?
We'll see how fast
this one can get round.
That, of course,
means handing it over
to our tame racing driver.
Some say that last week
he won a Bafta for
Best Original Smell.
(AUDIENCE LAUGHS)
And that when he dies,
he thinks he'll go to Devon.
All we know is
he's called The Stig.
(AUDIENCE CHEER)
And he's...not in the car.
Oh, yeah, Stig not happy
about Ricciardo's lap...
He's punched him.
That's bad.
He's really not happy
about that fast lap.
Oh, that...
He's in the car now,
and he's off.
-(TYRES SCREECH)
-A wheelspinning start,
obviously,
and a furious temper.
503 horsepower,
thundering through
the light but strong
carbon fibre prop shaft.
Oh, he's vandalised
the first corner.
and he's really
very annoyed.
But he is driving beautifully.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYS)
CLARKSON:
Another slice of the calming
Carpenters there.
and Chicago.
Looking very fast
and very controlled.
Now Hammerhead.
James says this car can suffer
from snap understeer,
so let's see what happens.
No, not a thing.
It's worth remembering,
of course, that James suffers
from being a moron.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYS)
Okay, into the Follow Through.
Banging up the
double clutch gearbox,
letting the perfect balance
of the transaxle layout
do its stuff.
And just a stabber brakes
past the tyres,
Stig returning the pedal
is in Australian's face.
Two corners to go.
Coming... Oh, he's hot
through there but very tidy.
Only Gambon left.
Laser-guided through there,
and across the line.
(AUDIENCE CHEERING
AND APPLAUDING)
I have the time here.
Ready?
It did a 1.17.5.
And that is, well, look.
That's quicker than
the old SLS Black.
And, ahem, quicker than
the Nissan GT-R,
which shows, James,
that you don't know
what you're talking about.
Interesting.
Didn't actually feel like it
would be that fast
when I was driving it,
to be honest.
No, that's because...
Yeah, you were driving it.
(AUDIENCE LAUGHS)
Right, and now we must
do the news.
And we start with big news.
This is the biggest news
we've had in a long time,
I would say,
because Ford
for the very first time
is making the Mustang
in right-hand drive
and will be bringing it
to the UK officially.
You can buy them over here.
There it is.
Two versions. You can have
four-cylinder EcoBoost
for £28,000,
or for £33,000,
a five-litre V8.
Mmm, the one I want,
though, is the Shelby.
The 350 GTR,
or something like that.
It's a 520-horsepower V8.
That's the one.
There it is. Look.
HAMMOND:
Yeah, it looks brilliant.
But you can't.
They're not bringing
that one here.
-They're not selling
that one to us.
-Why?
It is going to Canada
in a year.
Yeah, I know,
but so is the Internet,
but that's...
Yeah, but that's
not coming here.
No, we can't...
-Why won't they sell it to us?
-I don't know.
But you must be very looking
forward to a right-hand-drive
Mustang, Richard Hammond.
Yeah, you think.
No, not really.
Because I don't want
a right-hand-drive Mus...
Once it becomes
right-hand-drive,
it's like it's trying
too hard to be British
and sophisticated
and something it's not.
I know it. It's like when
Americans come over here
and start using words
like "bloody".
-Isn't it?
-Yes, it's exactly that.
It is, and they say,
"I'm going to the bloody pub."
Yeah, it doesn't sound right.
-And that's...
-Exactly, it is.
Or they say "mate".
They try and say "mate"
when it just doesn't work.
Yes, 'cause they think
that we're Crocodile Dundee.
-It's all the same 'cause
they haven't got atlases.
-Yeah.
So that, realistically,
should be called,
now it's coming here,
the Ford Bloody Quid, Mate.
-Yeah.
-That's its name.
Ooh, now. Can I just do...
Can I just do a survey?
How many people here
enjoyed the ambulance film
we did last week?
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
Okay, you see,
the problem we have
is that we've had an
electronic communication
from a man called
Mr E36Man4000, who says,
"Dear so-called  Top Gear,
"I hated your thing
on ambulances.
"Why don't you stick to cars?"
Shall we show Mr...
What's he called?
Mr Hashtag...
Shall we show him what
this show would be like
if we just talked about cars?
-Yeah, all right.
-Sure.
I'll tell you what
I drove this week,
Volkswagen Passat Diesel.
-Did you?
-Mmm.
(AUDIENCE LAUGHS)
-And?
-Surprisingly comfortable.
I also drove an Audi TT.
Which is much nicer
than you'd think.
Okay.
Actually, I've been driving
the new Porsche 911 Turbo,
which is very fast,
but surprisingly quiet.
-Is it?
-Yep.
Mmm-hmm.
(SMACKS LIPS) Ah.
Um, Aston Martin
have built a new one-off
for a Bond film.
It's called the DB10.
CLARKSON: Yep.
AUDIENCE: (SOFTLY) Ooh.
I don't think much
of that, actually.
-I don't like
the way it looks.
-No, I don't.
-No, I do.
-Okay.
Erm, Vauxhall has a new car,
-the Corsa.
-(AUDIENCE LAUGHS)
I've got nothing on that.
Shall we give up
on car news?
I'm going to take charge again
'cause I want to talk about
something else, right?
I want to talk about
some experts
who said last week
they wanted to rip up all
of Britain's railway lines,
replace them with motorways
that would then only
be used by coaches.
And I think
that'd be a shame.
Why would that be a shame?
-Because I like having
coaches on motorways.
-Why?
Because you can
drive alongside them
and use their Wi-Fi.
Can you? Can we just...
You can, obviously.
You all don't know?
It's fabulous.
My kids always say,
"Daddy, Daddy,
slow down to 70."
I mean, sorry,
"Speed up to 70.
"Catch the coach quickly
"so we can Snapchat
this picture of a poo
I've done."
So it's like a free
roaming Wi-Fi?
Exactly.
You do it on the way home.
It's incredibly cheap.
Now, a few years ago,
we improved police cars,
and last week,
we improved ambulances.
Yes, we did. We are now
the emergency service
for the emergency services.
Yeah, we are. Well, we are.
It's up to us.
Quite a lot of people have
written to us, and they said,
"Right, when are you gonna
improve fire engines?"
Hmm.
No, actually, ooh, yeah,
we've looked into this
and there's a problem.
Because if you have to build
a vehicle that's big enough
for all the water you need
and pumps and ladders
and buckets
and six burly men
and women in wellingtons,
what you end up with
is a fire engine.
-Yeah.
-But specifically,
a British fire engine.
-That's important.
-Yeah, not one of those
stupid American ones
-where all the firemen
stand on the outside.
-They do.
So you get there and
there's nobody onboard
to put the fire out.
You know what I like
about the British fire engine?
It says Dennis on the front.
(LAUGHS) That's the name.
Dennis is a reassuring name.
And Dennis would remember
to return your lawnmower.
It is interesting, actually,
because American fire engines
have really stupid...
I've got a picture of
an American fire engine here.
Guess what that's called.
CLARKSON: Fire engine.
No, it's called the Igniter.
-HAMMOND: What?
-It is.
I mean, how does...
"I've already got a fire."
Exactly. It should be called
the Extinguisher.
It's like they've probably
got an ambulance called
the Haemorrhage.
Yes.
Right, earlier on,
James had a go
at a proper road test
in our one-off car show,
and now it's my turn.
-Try not to muck it up.
-No, no, no, relax.
This is going to be
a blizzard of facts
because I'm gonna talk
about the new BMW M3.
It has a smaller engine
than the old model.
Three litres rather than four.
It has two fewer cylinders,
but it's turbocharged,
so you get a little bit
more horsepower
and 111 more torques.
That means it's four seconds
a lap faster round our track
than the old car.
And four seconds
is a huge goal,
because, remember,
that was already
five seconds a lap faster
round the Ascari track
in Spain
than the equivalent Mercedes
and Audi.
So this is properly quick,
and it's more economical,
but, and this is
the big one,
is it nicer to drive?
CLARKSON:  Well, here it is,
slithering about on our track.
Look at that.
I mean, that's just
the M3 signature dish.
(IMITATING CAR WHOOSHING)
But straightaway,
I must tell you
there's a bit of a niggle.
If you stick the tail
out in a corner,
which you can, easily,
because it's an M3,
you'll find it very hard
to hold the drift
because the power steering
is now electric
rather than hydraulic.
Going around
a corner like this
is like wrestling
with the tail of an
excitable crocodile.
It's not just hard
to hold the slide,
it's also hard to
straighten up again
afterwards.
See what I mean?
Now I admit, in the real world
this isn't going to be
much of a problem.
Ever, if I'm honest.
And anyway, you can solve it
by taking the steering
out of Sport Plus mode
and putting it
in Comfort mode.
Then everything is fine.
(TYRES SCREECHING)
Oh, yeah!
In fact, everything's
more than fine.
Everything is
absolutely sublime.
I'm not gonna
beat about the bush,
this car is utterly brilliant.
It's well-made,
it's got seating for four,
it's got a decent-sized boot.
It's comfortable, it's quiet,
it's got a lots of
standard equipment.
In many ways, this car
is like the perfect dog.
It's loyal, it's cute,
it doesn't chase sheep,
it doesn't go wrong
all the time.
And yet, if a burglar comes,
it has the power to
rip his throat out.
Look at me,
I'm an attack dog now!
I'm fierce and bitey.
And that really is that.
It is a fabulous,
wonderful car,
and if you have
£56,000 lying around,
you should
buy one immediately.
Or should you?
Because today
we live in strange times,
environmental times.
And BMW has another new car
which reflects that.
It's one of the most
talked about cars in years.
And this is it.
It's called the i8
and it's a hybrid,
which means it's powered
by an electric motor
and a tiny three-cylinder,
1.5-litre turbocharged
petrol engine.
That doesn't sound like
much of a recipe.
Sounds like a, sort of,
glorified Toyota Prius.
But let me give you
the headline figures.
This car does
155 miles an hour,
and 134 miles to the gallon.
And because
it's so economical,
you get a £5,000 grant
from the government
if you buy one,
it's exempt from
the London Congestion Charge,
and the road tax bill,
as you can see here, is nil.
It really does sound, then,
like this car answers
everyone's prayers.
But does it?
Are purebred
petrolheads like me
really going to say,
"Mmm, yes,
what I really want next
is a three-cylinder hybrid."
Well, that is what
I'm gonna try and find out.
I'm gonna set
the satellite navigation
for Whitby in North Yorkshire.
And obviously, in a car
as futuristic as this,
you don't push buttons
to do that,
you trace the letters you want
on this pad here.
So, "W."
"H."
"E." "T."
(CHUCKLING) Okay.
AUTOMATED SATNAV VOICE:
Whitby, North Yorkshire,
guidance started.
CLARKSON: Now, the reason
I've chosen Whitby is,
A, you get the best
fish and chips
in the world there,
and B, the M3
we saw earlier
is waiting for me there,
which means, when I arrive,
I will face a simple choice.
Will I want to drive home
in that or this?
With the satnav looking for
the most economical
route to Whitby,
I put my sensible head on
and settled down
for a 200-mile
fact-finding mission.
You have a choice of
three driving modes.
Number one,
electric drive, that's
the electric motor only.
It gives you
a range of 20 miles,
19 more than
you get from a Prius,
and probably enough
for you to do your
morning commute.
Then, if you move
the gear lever over here,
you engage sport mode.
That means the electric motor
and the petrol engine
are working together
to give 352 horsepower,
and it makes the car
sort of firm and bitey
and Nurburgringy.
But since we are on the A1,
I shall go for comfort mode.
Lovely.
And it really was lovely.
I know there's an
electric motor in the front,
driving the front wheels
through a two-speed
automatic gearbox.
I know there's
a petrol engine at the back,
driving the rear wheels
through a six-speed
automatic gearbox.
I also know there's another
small electric motor
at the back
filling in the gaps
and doing all sorts
of clever things.
And yet, sitting here,
this car feels
no weirder to drive
than that...
Whatever it is,
that hatchback thing, there.
I've got a steering wheel,
gear lever, accelerator,
brake,
and Ken Bruce on the radio.
(KEN BRUCE CHATTING
ON RADIO)
How normal is that?
(BBC RADIO 2 PROMO
PLAYING ON RADIO)
But there's a problem.
If you're driving
in comfort mode,
you're not really
charging up the batteries,
and eventually,
they are going to go flat.
One solution is to
turn off the motorway
and charge them up
at the mains.
But, as you're about to see,
this is not to be recommended.
"Connect your vehicle
and validate."
Look, I can operate a Hoover.
Oh, this is stupid!
Well, it must...
It must be charging,
it's plugged in, so...
I shall go and get
a cup of coffee.
While we wait
for the batteries to charge,
let me show you
this incredible app
that you can get
with your i8, okay?
If I push that, I can
set the air conditioning
so the car is cool
when I get back into it.
How amazing is that?
I can also
flash the headlights
so I could find it
if I'd lost it in a car park.
I can lock it.
I can unlock it.
I don't know why you'd want to
do that remotely, but you can.
I wouldn't be at all surprised
to find a feature on here
that enables the i8
to find another i8
for a good time.
After an hour,
I went back to the car
and found that
the charging point
hadn't worked.
If you have
a pure electric car,
you would be
completely stuffed.
But this not
a pure electric car.
So I am not.
I can either drive along
without the batteries,
or I can put
the gear lever over here
to engage sport mode,
and then they are being
charged up as I drive along.
What's more, in sport mode,
the i8 is properly fast.
I scoffed when BMW said
they were gonna make a hybrid
that was as fast as a 911
or a Chevrolet Corvette,
but it really is.
It's so fast that soon
I was in the North.
This is Doncaster.
This is where I grew up.
It was a mining town
back then, but now look.
It's a wind farm.
A bit less romantic,
the windmills.
And they employ fewer people,
but time moves on, I guess.
So far, then,
the i8 had done well.
But to find out
if it could truly win the
heart of the petrolhead,
I turned off the A1
and plunged into
the beautiful
North Yorkshire Moors.
So, let's find out.
Oh, God above, this is good!
This is a revelation!
It's the lightness
that staggers you most of all.
It's almost as though
I'm steering using
nothing but thought.
And because
the heavy battery pack
is located in the middle
of the car, here low down,
it has the same
centre of gravity as a worm.
Couple that to the
four-wheel-drive system,
and honestly,
you can go around any corner
at any speed
that takes your fancy.
The harder I go,
the faster I drive,
the sharper I brake,
the more electricity
I'm making for the battery.
If you get busted
for speeding in this car,
you get a thank-you letter
from Greenpeace.
And rightly so.
But before we get
carried away with this
environmental stuff,
there's one important point
we all need to remember.
I've always had a fundamental
problem with hybrids.
And it's this.
We all know the world
has limited resources
and we must do all we can
to eke them out.
And you're not gonna do that
if you drive around in a car
that has, effectively,
two engines.
You don't solve the problem
of conspicuous consumption
by using
conspicuous consumption.
The thing is, though,
while you have to
rape the world
to make a car like that,
the benefits of owning one
for you and I
in the here and now
are immense.
Because that car...
That car is staggering.
It's breathtaking.
It's nearly as breathtaking
as that view.
With the advert
for Yorkshire over,
I got back on the road.
It is incredible to think
that I am now cruising
into Whitby
in silent, electric mode,
using electricity that I made
by driving
quickly on the Moors.
The message really is
very clear from this car.
If you wanna save the planet,
drive fast.
After a short eco drive
through the pretty
fishing port of Whitby,
I arrived in the harbour,
where I faced a very
difficult choice.
Cod or haddock?
I think cod.
Then I faced
an even more difficult choice.
Which of these cars
would I drive back to London?
This is the hardest decision
I've ever had to make
between cars. Ever.
It's like the M3 is the best
of where we've come from
and the i8 is
where we're going.
There must have been
a moment in history
when everybody
had typewriters,
and typewriters had
been around hundreds of years
and they were brilliant,
and then somebody
came along with a laptop.
That is what's going on there.
No, I've made my mind up.
Bet you weren't
expecting that.
-(AUDIENCE CHEERING
AND APPLAUDING)
-CLARKSON: Thank you.
(CLARKSON SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY)
-What?
-Hold on, hold on, hold on.
Let me make sure
I've got this straight.
You, let's be honest,
are our resident dinosaur.
-I am.
-And you prefer
the i8 to the M3.
No.
But in the film...
Yes, I know.
I was wrong.
Thing is, I've had
some time to do some
thinking since then,
and there are one or two
bits and bobs on the i8
that would drive you mad.
I mean,
rear visibility is atrocious.
The boot's microscopic.
This window doesn't go
all the way down,
so you can't drive along
with your arm hanging out.
And I discovered last week
that an i8 has just been
bought by Wayne Rooney.
-Oh, no. No.
-Oh.
And it gets worse.
Well, how can it get
worse than that?
Because in a laboratory
in Munich,
it can do 134 miles
to the gallon.
But have a guess
how many miles to
the gallon I averaged.
-Em, 80.
-Nope.
79.
No.
-78.
-No, James.
-I averaged 31 miles
to the gallon.
-HAMMOND: Oh.
And other i8 owners
are reporting the same
sort of thing.
And it only has
a tiny little fuel tank.
Seven gallons.
Which means you're
gonna be stopping
for fuel all the time.
So when you said
it's a laptop,
-it's one of those really
early days laptop.
-It is.
They're on the right road,
make no mistake about that.
But they are not there
just yet.
So anyway, let's move on.
Let's put a star in our
reasonably-priced car.
Now my guest tonight
was Jordan Belfort's wife
in  The Wold of Wall Street,
one of my favourite films
of the modern age.
She's now in a new film
and she's brought along
her co-star.
So please welcome
Margot Robbie
and a man called Will Smith!
-Yeah!
-(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
CLARKSON: Oh, heavens above,
look what we got for you.
Yeah, we got you as well.
-SMITH: Good to see you.
-Good to see you too. Welcome.
Margot, I'll go round here
ROBBIE: Thanks for having us.
SMITH: What's up, everybody.
And relax.
Hey!
CLARKSON: Have a seat.
Have a seat.
This is fantastic.
-CLARKSON: Is it
really, really fantastic?
-Wow. This is great.
'Cause I was gonna begin
by apologising for the
trailers we have.
The trailers?
Oh, those trailers.
-Yeah.
-They're really nice.
You know, uh...
Will set his bar very high
with trailers, though, so...
-Really?
-Yeah, his trailer's pimped.
Yeah, I'm very serious
about the trailer.
The trailer, you know,
it has to be like...
You know,
you gotta hook it up.
-You gotta have
a stereo system.
-Mmm-hmm.
-You know, it has to...
-He also had mirrors
on the roof.
Very cool.
(MOUTHING)
I'm not insinuating anything.
I'm just saying. (LAUGHS)
That's gonna get in trouble.
That's gonna get into trouble.
Already in trouble there,
my mind's gone.
(LAUGHING)
No, 'cause really
not that long ago,
you were in  Neighbours.
-Yeah.
-What interests me
about  Neighbours,
-which is an Aussie TV...
-I know what  Neighbours is.
Don't pretend you know.
-Two days ago,
they asked him
what show I did in Australia.
Very popular show.
And you said
it started with C.
I couldn't remember the name.
There's no C in it.
I just can't see Will Smith
finishing it that way.
"Do you know what?
I think I'm watching
Neighbours."
-(LAUGHS)
-Oh, it's 6:30.
My show's on.
And Russell Crowe
started in that, didn't he?
-Mmm.
-And then Guy Pearce
was in another one.
-Kylie's in another one.
-Yeah. Yeah.
And I was wondering,
did you know
Coronation Street?
'Cause that's
produced literally...
Yeah, yeah, I know
all those shows, man.
You don't.
And you won't because...
I got the DVDs and everything.
It is just unbelievable.
I have all those...
The  Coronation Street
and  Neighbours and all those.
East Enders. Yeah.
Now you're over here
to promote a film.
-Yes.
-It's called  Focus,
but it isn't about
the small Ford hatchback.
-No. (LAUGHS)
-Disappointed,
some people in here.
Well, it's a love story
between you two,
which is rather sweet.
It's interesting. It's...
My character plays a conman,
a master thief.
And part of
being a master thief
is he's a liar.
And he meets
Margot's character, Jess,
and falls madly in love,
and realises quickly
that lying and loving
don't go together to well.
They go together often,
but they don't go
together well.
I believe we have a clip,
-which we will show now.
-Really? Okay.
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
JESS:  Are you
working an angle?
NICKY:  I wouldn't trust him
if I were you.
But I should trust you?
MAN:  You got a problem.
JESS:  I am going to kill you.
Kill me later.
You lost everyone's money,
my money.
Hey!
-Wow.
This is your mess!
JESS:  I think
you're losing it.
Whoa! Whoa!
Then why'd you come up here?
Professional curiosity.
And I like boobs. You know,
I figured it was a win-win.
Ohh!
NICKY:  At the end of the day,
this is a game of focus.
Yeah.
Did you notice?
When I had my shirt off,
you noticed, didn't you?
Did you see that shot?
Yes, that's what
everyone took away.
I just want to know
if you saw the shot?
Margot had her
trousers off.
Oh, yes. You saw that.
-Slightly more distracting.
-I get that. I get that.
And I've seen you in those
shirts on a million times
-but... Well, I have seen...
-Well.
(AUDIENCE LAUGHS)
CLARKSON:
I never seen you in those.
-(LAUGHS)
-This just got awkward.
-It did.
-(LAUGHS)
Now one of the things that
make it even more awkward
is you filmed quite
a lot of the movie
in Argentina.
Yes. Yeah. Mmm.
How did that go for you?
For me? It was good.
It was good, man.
Argentina's fantastic.
-Is it?
-(MUTTERS)
-Uh-oh.
-What's wrong with Argentina?
What's wrong with Argentina?
What happened?
Every fucking thing.
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
No, but it is.
Well, I enjoyed it,
and best of luck with it.
-Thank you, man.
-When does it open?
27th.
-27th...
-February 27th.
Is it 27th here?
-Yes, okay. Yes.
-ROBBIE: Yeah.
CLARKSON: Now,
we got to get on to cars
-'cause you grew up
on a farm in Australia.
-Mmm.
So you presumably
been driving since
you were nought
'cause it's such a vast area.
Yeah, it's huge.
But, yeah, in our family
the rule was we could drive
as soon as you could, like,
you know, physically
reach the pedals.
And you could have the car
on your own when you
reached double digits.
-So when you were 10,
you were allowed to...
-SMITH: Wow.
-And I remember being,
like, 9 years old...
-Little children at home.
...and arguing
with the parents,
being like,
"Guys, this is absurd.
I'm not, like..."
And they're like,
"No, you're 9. You have
to wait another year."
And I was like, "This is...
"I can't believe this.
This is ridiculous."
Have you been out
to the Outback?
The out... No, no, no.
I feel like
you'd fit right in.
You'd love it.
See, it's a racial thing.
You went racial.
-Yeah, it is. Yeah.
-(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
(LAUGHING)
And so, what was
your first car?
It was, ahem,
a candy apple red IROC Z.
A Camaro.
-Apparently, you don't
have those here.
-No, we don't. No.
We have, what's the word,
uh, taste.
(LAUGHTER)
I was thinking,
"Well, it may be
this would indicate
"you don't know
anything about cars."
And I started to look into
some of the lyrics, actually.
If you're familiar with the
lyrics of the early songs.
-SMITH: Oh, jeez. Oh, jeez.
-I wasn't born.
I a song called
Gettin' Jiggy Wit It...
-Yes.
-I remember that.
Yeah, I know that.
I don't recognise that one.
It's got "850 IS..."
850 IS if you need a lift.
"Who's the kid in the drop?"
Who else? Will Smith.
You were there?
Now "drop", I presume,
means drop-top.
Drop-top, yes.
They never did
a drop-top 850.
The... One second.
It's a small...
-(LAUGHING)
-No, it's...
Now hold on.
See now, he...
So he thinks
he knows everything.
He thinks he knows everything.
In the United States,
we do a thing where
we customise our car.
-Yeah.
-(LAUGHS)
-Can I just give you
another one?
-This is brilliant.
Just Cruisin'. The maestro.
-Do you know the next bit?
-Yes, yes, yes.
-"Nice flow..."
-Nice flow. Hot like nitro.
-"Cool as ice, though."
-Cool as ice, though.
That's a dichotomy.
Do you know
what a maestro is?
-Oh, you've got one?
-There you go.
(LAUGHING)
Okay.
Oh, my God.
(LAUGHS)
It is so awkward
for me to hear you say
my lyrics, Clarkson.
(LAUGHING)
-CLARKSON: Not bad.
-No, it's making
my eyes water.
We've done enough of this now.
We wanna get on to your laps.
-Ok, yeah.
-How did you
enjoy it out there?
It was really fun.
It was really nerve-wracking.
-CLARKSON: Was it?
-Yeah.
-Are you still...
-No, it's fantastic.
Like, I've never...
Well, you know,
in the United States,
the stick is
on the other side,
so having to drive
and do it with the other...
It was...
That's an advantage
for you, of course,
'cause you're used
to driving at the left.
Which is why he's obviously
mentioning it right now.
CLARKSON: Yeah,
he's already starting...
'Cause, like, "In case
she beats me on the laps,
"it's the whole
switching sides."
In case her time was better.
Okay. Margot you went first
and, well, there was
a bit of an off.
(WHISPERS) Crashed.
Who'd like to see Margot...
I said specifically
let's not let Will know that
that happened.
-Let's have a look.
Come on, let's play the tape.
-Oh, good.
CLARKSON:  Margot's off.
Oh, well, it's Chicago.
It's understeer
and she can't...
-(SHRIEKS)
-(SMITH LAUGHS)
CLARKSON:
It's Iain. It's Iain.
SMITH:  Ooh. Oh!
CLARKSON:  That is
Iain the cameraman.
SMITH:  Oh.
Sorry.
And he's dead.
He's dead.
-Margot, we have a little...
-I am sorry about that.
No, relax. We've got
a little present for you.
It's the landing light.
You can take that home
as a souvenir of your trip.
-To  Top Gear.
-I'm so sorry.
Right, now, we've got
both your laps still
to have a look at.
-So ladies first.
-SMITH: Ladies first.
Let's have a look at your lap.
This is gonna end
in a fistfight.
(ENGINE REVVING)
CLARKSON:  Right, here we go.
Good clean, aggressive start.
Up to third.
First corner, first corner.
(CLARKSON AND SMITH LAUGH)
CLARKSON:
Let's have a look at this.
CLARKSON:  The dam
of the brakes.
ROBBIE:  It feels
so much faster.
CLARKSON:  Everybody says it.
But the slower you look,
weirdly...
Oh, actually, I don't know.
There's a lot of
understeer there.
-That's ballsy.
-(ROBBIE CHUCKLES)
Oh, God.
(LAUGHS)
CLARKSON:  Here we go.
Are we gonna make it
without running over Iain?
Oh, waving to Iain.
It's a little wave there.
-That was nice.
-ROBBIE:  So sorry, Iain.
Don't brake. Don't brake.
Don't brake.
SMITH:  Don't brake.
(SMITH SNICKERS)
CLARKSON:  You do look like
you're concentrating in there.
SMITH:  Yeah.
CLARKSON:  Got to be.
ROBBIE:  Try not to
hit anyone, but...
CLARKSON:  This is good.
I'm liking a lot of this.
SMITH:  Mmm-hmm.
CLARKSON:  Yes.
Whew.
CLARKSON:  Right,
coming up to the fastest bit.
Foot down. Foot down.
(LAUGHTER)
ROBBIE:  Confidence, that was.
That was the look
of confidence.
CLARKSON:
Great face.
Through the tyres
Yes, take it easy.
SMITH:  Ooh.
CLARKSON:  That does look
quick, though.
That was the fun one.
I liked it.
CLARKSON:
Second to last corner.
This is what normally
catches people out.
SMITH:  Yeah, that's the one.
CLARKSON:
Through there easily.
To Gambon,
and more understeer.
Lot of understeer
and across the line.
There we are.
And now...
Now, that was pretty...
That was strong.
Yeah, it is strong,
Mr Will Smith.
Yeah. No, but every...
It was on the left for me.
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
-I'm used to driving...
Any more?
I had back surgery,
like, three days ago.
CLARKSON: Yeah.
Who'd like to see the lap
with the poor man with
the back surgery himself?
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
-Oh.
-Let's have a look.
Here we go.
-(TYRES SCREECH)
-Whoa! That was some revvs.
(ENGINE REVVING)
-Yep.
-Whoo!
(SMITH LAUGHS)
Ah.
All right,
this is the one.
CLARKSON:  Did you do
a few practices?
SMITH:  Yeah. Yeah, I did
a few practice laps.
CLARKSON:  That's a hard bit of
braking mid corner there.
I'll tell you what, though.
That car would bull
a GM's finest.
Yeah, powering through.
Feeling good.
CLARKSON:  Here we go.
This is the spiritual
successor of the IROC Z.
SMITH: (LAUGHING) Yeah.
I'm on the wall now.
They're putting me
on the wall.
My name
with all of the fastest times
on this track.
(SMITH LAUGHS)
CLARKSON: That is
a confident man right there.
It's actually
lovely conditions
for a fast time, this.
Keeping it
in the lines nicely.
Yes, just like watching Daniel
Ricciardo all over again.
This is the one
that makes my children proud.
CLARKSON:  Keep it in there.
No braking. Flat out. Yeah?
SMITH:  No braking. Flat out.
CLARKSON:  Good man.
Yeah, that's
looking very tidy.
Second-to-last corner.
You have any problems?
No, that is neat.
Very neat.
And through Gambon.
Still on all four wheels,
unlike some people,
-and there we are.
Across the line.
-Whoo!
-That was nice.
-That was so much fun.
-Yeah.
-Well done, you two.
Where do you think you've
come on the board?
(GRUNTS)
I'll be really psyched
if I get on the board,
to be honest.
You can't not be on the it,
because, trust me,
Jack Whitehall,
Ed Sheeran, they're...
So there's space
down there for me? Okay.
I want 1:52.
1:52, and Will?
Um... Well,
I want, like, 1:22.
(ALL LAUGHING)
CLARKSON: Yeah.
SMITH: That's what I want.
-You're asking
what I think I did?
-Yeah. Yeah.
Oh, man.
I think I might be
in the 1:50 zone.
Right in there.
-Somewhere with
the Hugh Bonneville...
-I felt like...
CLARKSON: These are wet times.
Well, let's have
a look, shall we?
-Let's have a look.
I've got the times here.
-Yeah. Oh, jeez. Okay.
-I'm going to did
you first, Will.
-Okay.
-Oh, jeez.
-This is really exciting.
-Will Smith...
-This is very exciting.
You did a one...
That's a good start.
(ALL LAUGHING)
-...40...
-Whoo!
-...seven...
-Whoa!
-...two.
-OK. Yeah. I'm not
mad at that.
That is not a very
bad time at all.
-That puts you...
-Wow.
-OK, yeah.
-ROBBIE: That's really great.
I'm not mad at that.
-That's not bad.
-I like that.
-That is not bad at all.
-Yeah.
-And, now, we must
get onto your co-star.
-Okay.
Oh, God.
If you beat me, this is
your last day on the tour.
(ALL LAUGHING)
I will never work
again after this.
It's Leo, Will Smith,
and then TV.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Margot...
-One...
-Oh, good!
-...40...
-Ooh!
-What?
-She'd better not.
(ALL LAUGHING)
-...seven...
-Oh!
-(SCREAMS)
-She'd better not.
-I can't believe this.
-...one!
-Whoa!
I'm not making it up.
(CHEERING AND APPLAUDING)
I'm sorry!
Holy shit!
(LAUGHS)
This was a bad idea.
This was a really bad idea.
It's like the Academy Awards
where you've got to clap
for the other person.
(ALL LAUGHING)
-I don't know what to say now.
-I actually can't
believe that.
-Both of you have
done amazing times.
-ROBBIE: Oh, my God.
-Yeah.
-There was a tenth in it.
Neither of you have got
anything to be ashamed about
-and it has...
-Oh, no! One of us has
something to be ashamed about!
-I was trying to end on
a really high note...
-No, no.
-...coming up with
some nice things...
-Yeah.
...but you're right.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I think you'll all agree,
this has been an absolute joy.
Will Smith and Margot Robbie.
(CHEERING)
Right, now we must move on
to some very sad news.
The Land Rover Defender
is going out of production
and our producers thought that
that meant it deserved
a fitting obituary
and all we needed for that was
a beach and a rural simpleton.
HAMMOND:
It's a little-known fact
that several of mankind's
greatest inventions
have started out
as drawings in the sand
on a beach.
Henry Royce,
of Rolls-Royce fame,
made his first sketch
of the Merlin engine,
the incredible motor that
powered the Spitfire
and the Lancaster,
in the sand
at his local beach.
Norman Woodland,
no, I'd never heard
of him either,
was in Miami when he
revolutionised shopping
by drawing the first bar code
in the sand.
And in 1947, here at
Red Wharf Bay in Anglesey,
it was the same story
for the Land Rover.
The sketch was done by
a chap called Maurice Wilks,
who was the technical director
for Rover cars.
At the time, he used
an old Bren Gun Carrier
to get around on his farm,
until one day he swapped it
for his neighbour's
old Willys jeep,
and soon thought,
"Hang on, we can make
something like this."
So, he sketched out
his creation in the sand,
and a first prototype
was quickly built
over the following few months.
Sadly, though,
there was a bit of an issue.
You see, Maurice thought
putting the steering wheel
in the middle
would mean they could sell it
to right and left hand
drive countries
without having
to re-engineer it.
But then they realised that,
amongst other things,
that was gonna make
hand signals rather tricky.
So it was back
to the drawing board.
And a mere 10 months
after that shaky start
the first Land Rover was born.
It came in this green
because the only paint
that Land Rover could
lay their hands on
was surplus army leftovers
they'd used for Spitfires.
The body was aluminium,
not for clever
engineering reasons
but because steel
was in short supply.
If ever there was an underdog,
it was this.
Nobody back then
could have predicted
what a phenomenon
the underdog would
turn out to be.
The military bought it
by the thousand,
and it was used by everyone
from the Medical Corp
to the SAS.
While in civilian life,
it was the very definition
of versatile.
You could have
a Land Rover tank,
a Land Rover train,
a Land Rover conveyor belt,
a snow plough, a fire engine,
and, rather annoyingly,
a Land Rover hovervan.
If explorers
wanted to explore,
adventurers wanted
to conquer terrain that
was unconquerable,
they'd turn to one of these.
It was the first
production vehicle
to travel 18,000 miles
from England to Singapore,
the first to cross
the Bering Strait,
and the machine of choice
for Ranulph Fiennes
on his epic
trans-global expedition.
In fact, at one time
the first car ever seen
by 60% of the developing world
was a Land Rover.
And on top of that,
it's been in production
for 67 years.
Sixty seven years!
The production run alone
makes this thing
one of the greats.
Look at the other icons.
The Beetle, I'd say 57 years.
2CV, well, that was a real
fly-by-night, 42 years.
So great is my love
for this machine
that when, 13 years ago,
we ran
a Top Gear  competition
asking viewers to vote for
the greatest car of all time,
I championed the Land Rover.
And the public clearly agreed,
because it won.
I drove a Series 1
in that film.
It was old
and tatty and worn.
But I fell so completely
in love with it
that I actually bought it
so I could restore it.
I'll never forget the day
I brought it home,
13 years ago.
It stood in this very yard
like a lost orphan.
So, I took it
into the workshop,
stripped it down
and laid it
all out on the floor
so I could begin
that long, loving process
of restoring it
to its former glory.
And here it is.
Yeah, I mean,
I have been really busy.
And the thing is,
it's good to have
a lot of spare parts
because Land Rovers
break down a lot,
so you never know.
Can't be too sentimental
about these things.
But because it is
the greatest car ever made,
I must now try to make amends
by giving it
a fitting send-off.
And this is the
perfect starting point.
There are many great
Land Rover TV adverts,
but what you're watching now
is the most famous
of them all.
This is the one
where it winches itself
up a vast, steep dam.
MAN: (ON TV)  Next time
you're late for work,
it's worth remembering
that nothing, but nothing,
gets in the way
of a Land Rover.
Now, the thing is,
that advert,
as exciting as it looked,
was, I'm afraid,
the result of,
shall we say,
the magic of television.
Because the Land Rover
didn't winch itself up.
The winch on the front bumper
pulled it the first few feet
out of the water,
but then it was
actually hauled
the rest of the way up
by a much bigger winch
hidden at the top of the dam.
So I think you can
probably see
what's coming next.
As our tribute to the
Land Rover Defender
we are going to
redo that stunt properly.
Oh, God.
The dam I'll be climbing
is Claerwen in Wales.
It's 1,200 feet wide,
and, more worryingly for me,
200 feet high.
To make things worse,
the Land Rover I'll be using
is 64 years old.
So, in order to do what
they never managed
in the TV advert,
we've added some bits.
When they made that advert,
there wasn't a winch around
big enough to take on board
all the cable you need
to go up a big dam.
So, we...
Well, not Jeremy and me,
somebody else has built
this ginormous one.
Then, there's the matter
of the engine.
You see, when this thing
starts to go up the dam
it will go vertical.
And at that point
the engine at the front
will cut out.
Problem, because we need
the engine to power the winch.
Solution, a second engine
just for the winch.
Best of all, this is built
so that it can pivot.
As the Land Rover
goes vertical,
this stays level.
None of this gave me
much comfort, however,
when I was standing
at the bottom.
Oh, bloody hell.
It's much steeper
than the other dam
in the advert.
For a brief moment
I thought I was off the hook,
because the start point
looked completely
inaccessible.
Sadly, the producers
had thought of that.
I hate problem-solvers.
And this just a little
amuse-bouche.
Eventually, I was in place.
The winch cable
was attached to the top.
And it was time to begin.
(CABLE STRAINING)
That's the engine in the back
that powers the winch,
remember,
because of the angle.
Um, I'd love to think of
something else to say or do.
I can't. So I'm gonna go.
So, um...
Right. Here I go.
(WINCH WHIRRING)
Oh, it's tensioning up.
This is okay so far.
Oh, there it is.
Oh, my God!
(GROANING)
Oh!
I know it's slow.
Any faster, and I risk
burning out all the
winch motors and things.
Plus, there was an issue with
the face of the dam itself.
The one on the advert
was smooth concrete,
this is rough stone.
I didn't take
that into account.
What I'm gonna do is steer
between these rocks
where they stick out
from the face.
(SHUDDERING)
It's jerking.
-I'm having to
read the surface.
-(THUDDING)
Ooh!
This vertical off-roading
gave me another problem.
Because the Land Rover
is winching itself up
on its own winch,
the cable has to feed
evenly onto the drum.
If it doesn't do that,
everything gets ruined.
I couldn't see the drum,
so up top, the producers
were spotting for me.
Straighten it up
please, Richard.
Ah.
Oh.
Ugh.
You know, because it's so slow
I've got time to think about
what would happen if...
Don't. I can't. I daren't.
I am now terrified.
I am now absolutely petrified.
Oh.
Past the halfway point,
it started to get even worse.
I can feel the
front wheels now
going very light,
because where it goes concave,
where it bellies in like that,
my winch cable is pulling
the front of the car
off the ground.
Oh!
And I can't tell you
how horrible that feels.
(HAMMOND GROANING)
Stop, stop, stop.
Okay, I'm stopping.
I'm stopping.
(ENGINE TURNING OFF)
(CABLE CREAKING)
Honestly, mate,
you've got about 20 seconds.
I'm fucking scared, okay?
And I mean it.
Okay, take your mind off it.
Take your mind off it.
-Um, this...
-(THUDDING)
(YELPING)
The water behind this dam
can supply Birmingham with
79 million gallons a day.
Who gives a fuck right now?
It's all right, we're good.
HAMMOND:
It's really vertical now.
Oh, God.
(CABLE STRAINING)
I can hear the lines...
I can actually hear
the tension in that wire.
As I get to the top,
the cable becomes less strong.
Partly because,
as well as the weight of
the Land Rover and me,
it has to be carrying
the weight of itself
and the winch.
(CABLE STRAINING)
Oh, God, I'm depending so much
on things made
by other people.
Every single part now,
the brake that stops
the winch feeding out,
the engine, everything.
In the face of
unutterable terror,
I was finally nearing the top.
We have nearly done this.
I've nearly cracked it.
Two hundred feet
of near-vertical rock.
(CABLE STRAINING)
Just a few more inches,
another few turns
on the winch.
What a fantastic way
to pay tribute to the car...
What?
It was at this point
the producers broke
the bad news.
Because of where
the winch cable was attached,
the Land Rover
wouldn't be able to climb over
onto the flat dam top.
And this meant only one thing.
I'm gonna have
to go back down.
I'm gonna have to winch it
down the dam.
I really need to piss.
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
Thank you. Thank you.
It was nothing.
Really, it was nothing.
So, you failed.
Well, I almost
got to the top.
Yeah, but then you just came
straight back down again.
I'm sorry, Hammond,
if I said, "I'm going
to drive to Bristol",
got nearly to Bristol
and came home again,
that's not going to Bristol.
Look, the main thing is I gave
the Land Rover Defender
a fitting send-off.
Yeah, but, Hammond,
they're working on
a new Defender now
and it looks exactly
the same as the old one.
So you said you'd drive
to the top of a dam,
which you didn't,
to pay tribute to a car
that you said was about
to die, but it's not.
Yeah.
Well, that means you're a liar
and you've completely
wasted our time.
Yeah.
And on that bombshell,
I'm afraid it's time to end.
Next week,
normal service is resumed.
James and I have a lot
of crashes on purpose.
Hopefully we
shall see you then.
Thank you for watching,
good night!
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)