Please!
Please listen to me!
It's my fault!
I'm sorry! I'm really sorry!
Kiss me.
Come on, kiss me.
I won't interfere in this again,
and I won't be a Curse User anymore!
Kiss me, please?
Come on, kiss me.
Of course, I'll quit Q too!
Right, I'll go home and be a farmer.
Did you hear me?!
I don't think curse users
know much about farming.
So you heard me.
How dare a student look down on me?
Mr. Bayer has already arrived anyway.
He is the strongest combatant of Q.
- All of you will—
- Let me ask you.
Is he the Bayer you are talking about?
Right, it's him.
Q'S STRONGEST COMBATANT BAYER LEFT
AND CAUSED DISINTEGRATION OF THE ORGANIZATION
Look, all boats are lining up in a row.
Starting from the inner circle,
one, two, three, four, five, six.
It starts now, with all boats rowing
in a beautiful straight line.
I was wondering where you ran off to.
What are you doing here?
I'm making money with money.
I have never seen you win though.
Don't you have work?
You're really annoying.
You make me sound like an idler.
You're an idler.
As an agent,
I have an obligation to report
your work performance to the client.
That guy is the eldest son
of the Gojo family.
I couldn't do anything to him
if I ran over there without a plan.
We need to send a few idiots
to weaken him first.
You are the one who's got work to do.
I am working, idiot.
What were you thinking?
You actually paid the full deposit.
I said I wanted to weaken him.
You don't have to worry.
I'll make all the money back.
Just like in this race.
Boat No. 6 Hatano
reaches the finish line.
The boat No. 1 Douguchi
is the second to do so.
And the third is boat No. 2 Matsuda.
It seems you're not good
at making easy money.
I'll leave it to you, Sorcerer Killer.
By the way,
is Megumi doing well?
Who are you talking about?
EPISODE 26: HIDDEN INVENTORY PART 2
JUJUTSU KAISEN SEASON 2
Should we bring her to a doctor?
If only we could use
Reverse Cursed Technique like Shoko.
No, we can't do that.
After all, we can't even
understand what she is saying.
Just like this and that.
This and that.
You don't understand?
You guys really have no talent.
She woke up.
Watch this!
You despicable villain!
You dare to hurt me.
I'll kill you first!
Riko, calm down.
We are not with those
people who attacked you.
Quit it! You clearly look like a liar.
Your bangs are weird too.
Stop!
CRACKLING
This is disrespectful!
Please... please stop!
Kuroi.
Miss, these two gentlemen
are our companions.
Kuroi, what is this thing you are riding?
This is the Cursed Technique
of the gentleman with bangs.
Can you please not call me that?
Cursed Spirits Manipulation.
Just as the name implies,
I can control
the cursed spirits I've absorbed.
This kid is more aggressive than I thought.
I thought the merging
would make you sentimental.
I was even wondering
how to take care of your feelings.
What a way of thinking
for a despicable man.
Listen carefully.
Master Tengen is me.
I am Master Tengen.
Some fools confuse merging
with death like you.
And it's a huge mistake.
Merging will make me become Master Tengen,
but Master Tengen will also become me.
My consciousness, mind, and soul
will continue to live on after merging.
Did you change your wallpaper?
It's Waka Inoue.
Listen to me!
Judging by the way she talks,
she probably has no friends.
Then we can send her off
without any worries.
I speak normally at school!
School... Kuroi, what time is it now?
It's not noon yet,
but you better not go to school.
Shut up, I'm going!
What?
It would be safer to have her
return to high school sooner.
I personally wish to do so,
but it's Master Tengen's order.
He wants us to fulfill
all of Riko Amanai's requests.
Isn't that spoiling her too much?
Don't say that, Satoru.
Although she said so,
she will become
the foundation of the barrier
at the bottom of the school
as Master Tengen after merging.
She will never see her
friends and family again.
Riko.
We need to go
for the next class.
Just let her do what she wants.
That's our mission.
Miss Riko has no family.
She lost her family in an accident...
I've been taking care of her since then.
So I hope that at least you'll let her
spend more time with her friends.
In that case, you are her family.
Yes.
Suguru, how are the cursed spirits
you sent to monitor her?
Unfortunately, I can't share
their vision like Miss Mei.
But if anything goes wrong,
I can immediately...
Satoru,
we need to hurry to Riko's school.
Two cursed spirits have been exorcised.
Who will be the best
of the new generation?
It will be decided in this important race.
The six boats finally
reached their destination.
The much-anticipated fifth round
is about to begin.
RIKO AMANAI, INTEGRITY GIRLS SCHOOL
REGARDLESS OF LIFE AND DEATH
JUJUTSU KAISEN SEASON 2
Where's Amanai?
It's music class now.
She should be in the music
room or the chapel.
Chapel?
They have the music class
wherever the teacher wants.
And it's a church school here.
Satoru, you go to the chapel.
Miss Kuroi goes to the music room.
I'll deal with the two unknowns.
Understood.
Don't follow me!
What if my friends see you?!
I'm terribly sorry.
I asked her to send me a message
before moving, but...
That's why we told her to let us protect her
within our sight, that little brat.
The race has started.
Players in lanes one and two
are on the inside.
- Player in lane three is a bit behind.
- What? They didn't return to high school?
Lucky.
Now the people who got lured by the bounty
will become acceptable fools.
Is that okay?
What's the matter?
The bounty was paid with the deposit of
30 million yen from Star Religious Group.
If Star Plasma Vessel is killed,
your deposit will be gone.
If there is a slight mistake,
you might not even get the reward.
They might even think
they should have put out the bounty
directly rather than commissioning you.
Don't forget that Satoru Gojo is there.
For the first time in a hundred years,
The Six Eyes paired
with limitless cursed technique.
As long as he's there,
no one can kill Star Plasma Vessel.
Including you?
Boat No. 3 Kono takes the lead!
Leaping ahead of everyone else.
It's hard to say.
He succeeded on the second try.
Anyway, within the 47 hours
before the bounty deadline,
let those fools wear down
Satoru and Jujutsu Sorcerers around him.
Stop there.
No, it's nothing.
Of course they can't kill her,
that's why they are working in vain.
Luckily we set a time limit.
Recruiting curse users
didn't take much effort.
But it's not just that.
It's about my perspective.
Oh my goodness!
Boat No. 3 Kono loses balance!
Boat No. 2 Yamazaki takes the lead!
I'll be there soon.
Things are progressing
faster than I thought.
I want the 30 million yen back in full.
Boat No. 2 Yamazaki reaches
the finish line first.
What's that nonsense?
It's not just a common
anonymous message board.
- Publication fee, handling fee and—
- I'm losing the signal.
That bastard.
The unknown person from Q?
Things could get a bit troublesome
if it's someone from the Star Religious Group.
That uniform is...
He assumed it's a multiple-on-one case
when he saw the high school uniform,
and placed Shikigami in front and behind.
It seems like he's experienced.
There is no medium, and his Cursed Energy
is different from the Jujutsu Sorcerer's.
Could this be...
Cursed Spirit Manipulation?
You got it right.
So you haven't lived so long for nothing.
No, there's no need to live too long.
The longer you live, the more you spend.
His Cursed Techniques are above mine.
But a Jujutsu Sorcerer thinks
the same as a Shikigami user.
Besides, he's so young.
I can see right through his thoughts.
I was right.
He usually doesn't rush to the front.
He must be not that good at close combat.
And he assumes that a Shikigami user
like me won't get close to him.
He hates close combat
and is not vigilant about it.
Killing him is a piece of cake.
You seem to have thought a lot.
But none of those matters.
What? Did he release those two
at the beginning to throw me off this attack?
Alright, one more to go.
You're dead!
Tasuke, is it you?
My parents only wanted to invest money
and time in my talented younger brother.
They despised me for being able
to see things that others couldn't.
Tasuke was the only one who accepted me.
Long time no see.
We haven't seen each other
for over 50 years.
Tasuke, ever since you die—
I see.
It's an illusion.
You tricked me...
Yes.
You've been trying
to get close to me, right?
For someone with their
own winning strategy,
I can just pave a path of victory for them
and they'll easily fall for it.
I want to ask you.
Are you from Q?
Or the Star Religious Group?
Amanai!
W-W-What?
Riko, who is he?!
Your boyfriend?
No, he's my cousin!
Not bad, Riko.
I told you he's not my boyfriend!
Is he a high school student?
He's so tall!
Big brother!
Take off your sunglasses!
AHHHH
What a handsome guy!
- Long eyelashes!
- Hi.
Why are his eyes blue?
Strike a pose, please!
Don't get carried away!
Everyone, quiet down.
We are having a class here.
You are interested in him too, Miss!
Don't educate us now.
This is troubling for me.
Even if you're a family member,
you can't just barge in.
I'm sorry. This is an emergency.
Here's my phone number.
ROAR
That's not fair, Miss!
Be quiet! I don't get many
chances to meet the man!
We don't have any chances either!
You like younger guys, Miss!
You can't do that!
Are you insulting the Genji family?!
This is a lively school.
Idiot, how many times have I told you
not to show up in front of them?
Curse Users are attacking.
I don't need to say anything more, right?
Why am I floating?
We'll go to the high school.
You don't want to involve
your friends, do you?
So that's for the bounty
of 30 million yen?
Is that person her classmate?
Could be her bodyguard.
This is some easy money.
Kill a non-sorcerer middle school kid
and we can get 30 million yen.
I'll have eel for tonight.
A meal after a murder
is especially delicious.
You must be from the Star Religious Group.
Because those from Q
dress more strangely.
Are you an amateur?
If you want to kill, do it secretly.
So slow.
I won't let you harm Miss!
Or I'll kill you.
What?
You're so strong.
Where's Riko?
She left the school with Mr. Gojo.
Let's leave too.
Things are getting a bit tricky.
So that was indeed for
the bounty of 30 million yen.
Shikigami?
No, it's a bit different from Shikigami.
Satoru.
Someone offered a bounty of
30 million yen for killing Amanai?
Yes, it's a limited-time bounty
on an underground website for Curse Users.
The deadline seems to be 11 a.m.
the day after tomorrow.
I see.
Two... three... four people.
They all look the same.
Are they Shikigami?
Geez. Jujutsu Sorcerers
are always short-handed.
You are welcome to
start a new career, guys.
No thanks. I guess job referrals
aren't easy for you either.
Just hand that kid over to us.
There are five of them now!
What's so good about this little brat?
What was that?
The Shikigami didn't disappear.
Which one is the original?
That's not a Shikigami, it's a clone.
And they're all original.
What's going on?
This is infinity.
Think about Achilles and the tortoise.
What?
What I mean is that studying is important.
It's a Cursed Technique that can summon
up to five clones including the original one.
He should be able to choose which one
to be the original at any time.
Once the original is in danger,
he'll switch to a safe clone.
Not a bad trick.
But why are you still so weak?
I don't get it.
Clones can't be summoned
temporarily after they are destroyed?
Why do you know my Cursed Technique?
Unfortunately,
I happen to have sharp eyes.
My Cursed Technique
is the convergence of an infinite series.
Things getting closer to me
will be slowed down gradually.
And they'll never touch me.
After being reinforced,
it becomes Limitless.
You could say it's
a negative natural number.
It creates a fictional situation
like negative one apple.
In that way, it can achieve
the vacuum reaction just now.
But it's surprisingly inconvenient to use.
One can't make too much
reaction around oneself.
And if you have to
worry about directionality,
controlling Cursed Energy
is a pain in the neck.
Simply put, it's exhausting.
But what I just explained is
about Cursed Technique Lapse.
Protect your head.
This is the divergence of infinity.
Cursed Technique Reversal.
Red.
I failed!
I thought it should work.
What's wrong with this guy?
Kuroi is calling.
What should I do?
Kuroi...
Kuroi is...
To express the voice of
the younger generation,
I vote in every election.
But I can't help but worry
if I can still be considered young.
NEXT EPISODE: HIDDEN INVENTORY PART 3
Next Episode: "Hidden Inventory Part 3."
Don't miss it!
NEXT EPISODE: HIDDEN INVENTORY PART 3
How old is Kuroi?
Three years old.
NEXT EPISODE: HIDDEN INVENTORY PART 3
Wow, super cute!